<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on game, game. repeat.</title><link>https://ggr.com/tags/security.html</link><description>Recent content in Security on game, game. repeat.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 17:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Security House Boat</title><link>https://ggr.com/my-security-house-boat.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 17:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/my-security-house-boat.html</guid><description>The more I learn about network security, the more trying to secure a Linux server feels like trying to make my house seaworthy&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;d be better off buying something that was built for seaworthiness from the start, like a boat. Security, like seaworthiness, is not a feature that&amp;rsquo;s well suited to being added onto a structure after the fact.
Its not just Linux of course&amp;hellip;with hundreds of thousands of lines of private code in multiple languages and hundreds more libraries bringing in millions of lines of open source code, plus thousands of lines of configuration for machines and services both real and virtual, some ours, some belonging to others (i.</description></item><item><title>The Big Unplug</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-big-unplug.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 09:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-big-unplug.html</guid><description>I posted this on my personal Facebook account yesterday morning:
I want to see what life is like without a (personal) Facebook account for a while. Seems the teenagers are doing fine (http://mashable.com/2013/08/11/teens-facebook/). I&amp;rsquo;m going to nuke my account (from orbit) this evening (it&amp;rsquo;s the only way to be sure). You can find me at https://ggr.com/ and scott@ggr.com. See you on the other side!
It was funny to see everyone&amp;rsquo;s responses.</description></item><item><title>Opting Out</title><link>https://ggr.com/opting-out.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/opting-out.html</guid><description>A government with easy access to all the public and private information of its people, that collects this information against their wishes, that makes them more vulnerable to harm in order to maintain their access, and then lies in order to cover up their actions is fundamentally incompatible with American democracy. The freedom to live, speak, and think in private, without worrying how a government agent might view our thoughts or try to use them against us, is liberty.</description></item></channel></rss>