<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on game, game. repeat.</title><link>https://ggr.com/tags/security.html</link><description>Recent content in Security on game, game. repeat.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 17:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Security House Boat</title><link>https://ggr.com/my-security-house-boat.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 17:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/my-security-house-boat.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The more I learn about network security, the more trying to secure a Linux
server feels like trying to make my house seaworthy&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;d be better off buying
something that was built for seaworthiness from the start, like a boat.
Security, like seaworthiness, is not a feature that&amp;rsquo;s well suited to being
added onto a structure after the fact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Its not just Linux of course&amp;hellip;with hundreds of thousands of lines of private
code in multiple languages and hundreds more libraries bringing in millions of
lines of open source code, plus thousands of lines of configuration for machines
and services both real and virtual, some ours, some belonging to others (i.e.
our ISP and various 3rd party SaaS providers), I need to be patching every day
just to keep up with the known vulnerabilities, to say nothing of the unknown
ones. Turns out I took my house boat out to sea, it sprang a thousand leaks, and
as soon as I patch the first thousand there will be another thousand to take
their place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Big Unplug</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-big-unplug.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 09:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-big-unplug.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ggr_com.s3.amazonaws.com/images/alien-self-destruct.jpg" alt="7">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I posted this on my personal Facebook account yesterday morning:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I want to see what life is like without a (personal) Facebook account for a while. Seems the teenagers are doing fine (&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/08/11/teens-facebook/)">http://mashable.com/2013/08/11/teens-facebook/)&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;m going to nuke my account (from orbit) this evening (it&amp;rsquo;s the only way to be sure). You can find me at &lt;a href="https://ggr.com/">https://ggr.com/&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="mailto:scott@ggr.com">scott@ggr.com&lt;/a>. See you on the other side!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was funny to see everyone&amp;rsquo;s responses. A couple people pointed out that most of my posts were &lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/">Runkeeper&lt;/a> jog updates, implying that &lt;em>they&lt;/em> won&amp;rsquo;t be missing out on much as I journey into the Facebook abyss. Fair enough. :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Opting Out</title><link>https://ggr.com/opting-out.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/opting-out.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ggr_com.s3.amazonaws.com/images/optout.jpg" alt="26">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A government with easy access to all the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PRISM_(surveillance_program)">public and private information&lt;/a> of its people, that collects this information &lt;a href="https://www.commondreams.org/view/2013/09/11-11">against their wishes&lt;/a>, that makes them more &lt;a href="http://www.technologyreview.com/news/519336/bruce-schneier-nsa-spying-is-making-us-less-safe/">vulnerable to harm&lt;/a> in order to maintain their access, and then &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/08/15/lies-damned-lies-and-the-nsa/">lies&lt;/a> in order to cover up their actions is fundamentally incompatible with American democracy. The freedom to live, speak, and think in private, without &lt;a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/technology/nsa-dragnet-wider-previously-suspected-says-nyt-6C10876005">worrying&lt;/a> how a government agent might view our thoughts or try to use them against us, &lt;em>is&lt;/em> liberty. I feel obligated to &lt;a href="http://www.draxe.com/i-opt-out-what-you-must-know-about-new-airport-backscatter-scanners/">opt out&lt;/a> and find other ways to protest and inhibit these &lt;a href="http://www.economonitor.com/dolanecon/2013/08/05/the-fourth-amendment-and-the-economic-spillover-from-nsa-surveillance-to-e-commerce/">destructive&lt;/a> programs.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>