<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership on game, game. repeat.</title>
    <link>https://ggr.com/tags/leadership.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leadership on game, game. repeat.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:00:09 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI is the 80 Percent</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/ai-is-the-80-percent.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:00:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/ai-is-the-80-percent.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI solves the first 80% of a lot of problems for almost free and then the last 20% takes 10x vs what it would have if you had hand coded the whole project. AI lovers and AI haters talk past each other, because the lovers either make more money by convincing people of AI&amp;rsquo;s awesomeness, or they are staying within the 80%, while the haters try using AI to solve a whole problem, see that it can&amp;rsquo;t, see that it makes the whole solution more expensive, and question AI lovers&amp;rsquo; motives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AI winners will be the AI makers that convert to other assets before the bubble bursts, and the AI users who figure out how to create significant value while staying within the 80% that AI&amp;rsquo;s easily good at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Leader Gets a Group of People From Point A To Point B</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/a-leader-gets-a-group-of-people-from-point-a-to-point-b.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 10:18:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/a-leader-gets-a-group-of-people-from-point-a-to-point-b.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bad leaders choose the wrong goal or fail to choose one at all. Their group ends up worse off. Divisive leaders optimize for a subgroup and the &amp;lsquo;in&amp;rsquo; group is more happy, the &amp;lsquo;out&amp;rsquo; group is less happy. They are playing a zero-sum game. Selfish leaders are an extreme of the divisive leader&amp;ndash;the selfish leader IS the &amp;lsquo;in&amp;rsquo; group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good leaders choose a goal where everyone wins, and they achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The better the leader, the bigger and better the outcomes and the bigger and broader &amp;rsquo;everyone&amp;rsquo; turns out to be. Alan Mulally famously &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/American-Icon-Mulally-Fight-Company/dp/0307886069&#34;&gt;turned Ford around&lt;/a&gt;, taking them from losing $17B/year to profitable and growing. He got Ford&amp;rsquo;s zero-sum-game-playing shareholders, executives, employees, car dealers, bankers, factory workers, union leaders, and parts suppliers to align, sacrifice, work, and win or lose together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://files.tablegroup.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/09201856/TTGBio-Jenson-050620.pdf&#34;&gt;Chris Jenson&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tablegroup.com/&#34;&gt;Table Group&lt;/a&gt; who was my coach and first told me &amp;ldquo;a leader gets a group of people from point A to point B&amp;rdquo; and I liked that statement so much I kept repeating it and thinking about it and blogging about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#43;1-1=0 Game vs the 1&#43;1=4 Game</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/the-1-10-game-vs-the-1-14-game.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 20:09:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/the-1-10-game-vs-the-1-14-game.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I suspect that if you take a somewhat random group of human beings
and ask them to organize themselves in order to
allocate work and limited resources, most of the time
they will find themselves playing a zero sum game with each other. I call
it the &lt;strong&gt;+1-1=0&lt;/strong&gt; game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other game to be played is the &lt;strong&gt;1+1=4&lt;/strong&gt; game. It&amp;rsquo;s the game
of abundance, of creating a bigger pie, of win-wins that benefit everyone.
It&amp;rsquo;s a lot harder to pull off.
It requires leadership and shared culture (which also requires leadership).
Our modern society is evidence it can be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which game are you playing? At work? With your spouse? Which game is
your boss playing? Your boss&amp;rsquo;s boss?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junior vs Senior Managers</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/junior-vs-senior-managers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 11:26:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/junior-vs-senior-managers.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Warning: preference-style opinions ahead, e.g. cherry pie is better than apple pie. That said, I’ve used these opinions &lt;a href=&#34;https://english.stackexchange.com/questions/30939/is-used-in-anger-a-britishism-for-something&#34;&gt;in anger&lt;/a&gt;, so they may be of interest to mangers trying to get ahead with a leader that thinks like I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: my first loyalty is to the team I lead, my downwards team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: my first loyalty is to the team my boss leads, my upwards team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: my span of control is how many people must do what I say&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: my span of control is how many people I know the name of their kids and what’s going on in their lives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: to make a good decision I must build a consensus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: to make a good decision I must mine for conflict and then use my judgement to make the best decision I can, even if it’s not popular&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: my management position is a reward for my talent and hard work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: my management position is a responsibility to help us achieve results to everyone’s benefit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: I avoid criticizing my staff, so they like me and I can use that to influence them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: I hold my staff accountable so they are clear on what’s expected and can perform their best&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: I’m not ready to make a decision—I need more information because I don’t want to make a mistake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: I will make a decision now so my team has clarity and can move forward in concert…if I’m wrong, that’s ok, we’ll course correct&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: conflict is bad and I do my best to cutoff or redirect discussions where my staff are getting riled up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: conflict is essential to making good decisions, I must mine for conflict to make sure we’ve gotten all the available ideas and concerns out on the table&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: I was right, but now I think we should go in a different direction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: I was wrong; I know my choice created a lot of work for you, now you have to throw it away, and I know how much that sucks…that’s on me and I’m sorry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: I take control of as much as I can so I can make sure everything is done correctly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: I delegate as much control as I can, so my staff feel empowered; I keep as much of the risk as I can, so my staff feel safe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: yes I’ll do it, but I’m already working 80 hours a week and I’m burning out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: yes I’ll do it, but I’m handing back item number 7 on my backlog to make room, ok?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: our boss’s boss said we have to do X, so let’s do it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: I believe we should do X for these reasons, what do you think, ok let’s do it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: hi boss, I have a problem, can you help me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: hi boss, I just solved a problem you had, you’re welcome, also I have a problem, can you help me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: sales keeps making impossible promises to our customers, engineering is left holding the bag, and it sucks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: sales and engineering are misaligned around what we’re telling customers, let’s fix that, I’ll bring it up at my team meeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: I told you that wouldn’t work and you’d regret making X decision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: WE decided X but we’re seeing Y evidence that it&amp;rsquo;s not working the way we hoped, I think we should revisit OUR decision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: individual performance is private and should only be discussed in the chain of command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: individual performance is not private, it impacts the entire company, and the most effective way to improve it is working together as a team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: I argued for X and that’s what I think is the best thing to do, but the boss decided Y, so we’re doing Y&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: I argued for X at first, but after hearing A, B, C arguments I became convinced that Y is what we should do, and that’s what we decided, let’s go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: X isn’t being done right, I’ll just do it myself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: X isn’t being done right, I need to hold the person responsibly accountable and support them improving so they can do it right next time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: Bob isn’t making the right decision, I need to tell him what to do and how to do it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: Bob isn’t making the right decision and any time I must exercise my authority to fix a one-off problem, something might be wrong on my end…could it be a context problem? If I gave Bob more info A, B, C would he make the right decision?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: my job is to lead my team so we can achieve our goals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: my job is to teach my team how to lead, so they don’t need me to achieve our goals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: meeting attendance is an important signal about which topics and which people are important&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: meetings should only be attended by those who add significant value to the debate and who could not add more value investing that time somewhere else&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: pressure is bad and should be minimized&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: pressure is good, ‘pressure is a privilege’, but it needs to be channelled productively or I risk unhealthy behavior and bad decisions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: risk should be minimized or eliminated, if possible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: risk should be thoughtfully managed, but it should not be eliminated because it isn’t worth the price&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: people who see therapists or work with coaches or otherwise seek help from mental health professionals are flawed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: the highest performing professionals invest in themselves by seeking help when it will give them an advantage, including from therapists, coaches, mental health professionals, trainers, lawyers, doctors, mentors, coworkers, and others&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: I start with making sure everyone on my team gets what they want individually and then work towards our collective goals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: I start with making sure we’ll achieve our collective goals and then I make sure each of my team individually (and all of our stakeholder groups) shares in our success&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ggr.com/junior-vs-senior-engineers.html&#34;&gt;Junior vs Senior Engineers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Five-Temptations-CEO-Anniversary-Leadership/dp/0470267585&#34;&gt;The Five Temptations of a CEO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Five-Dysfunctions-Team-Leadership-Lencioni-ebook/dp/B006960LQW/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=five+dysfunctions+of+a+team&amp;amp;qid=1651772739&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;The Five Dysfunctions of a Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Truth-About-Employee-Engagement-Addressing/dp/111923798X/ref=sr_1_1?crid=3O6FZDCAZ6BVQ&amp;amp;keywords=truth+about+employee+engagement&amp;amp;qid=1651772771&amp;amp;sprefix=truth+about+employee+engagemen%2Caps%2C247&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;The Truth About Employee Engagement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Death-Meeting-Leadership-Business-Lencioni-ebook/dp/B008L03W7O/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1C955LZQSC4MJ&amp;amp;keywords=death+by+meeting&amp;amp;qid=1651773201&amp;amp;sprefix=death+by+meeti%2Caps%2C293&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Death by Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you click on some of those you&amp;rsquo;ll notice I’m a Patrick Lencioni fan.
BTW I’m not paid for these links or for saying so&amp;hellip;this
is an old school, unsponsored, unpaid, shill-free, genuine opinion. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junior vs Senior Engineers</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/junior-vs-senior-engineers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 10:46:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/junior-vs-senior-engineers.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Warning: preference-style opinions ahead, e.g. pecan pie is better than apple pie. That
said, I’ve used these opinions &lt;a href=&#34;https://english.stackexchange.com/questions/30939/is-used-in-anger-a-britishism-for-something&#34;&gt;in anger&lt;/a&gt;, so they may be of interest to engineers
trying to get ahead with a leader that thinks like I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: right tool for the job&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: right ‘enough’ tool for the job, fewer tools better mastered&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: clever solution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: easy to understand solution, even if a bit ugly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: don’t like criticism, don’t want to look bad&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: want more criticism, don’t want to make a mistake that could be avoided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: job is to code, meetings are bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: job is to create value, well led meetings are where I do my highest value work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: this code sucks, the author was lazy and dumb, we should just throw it out and start over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: this code has created huge value and its survived because it did its job, there’s probably valuable context embedded in it that I can’t see yet, what’s the best way to learn that context and leverage the existing code given where I want to go next&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: do my best work alone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: do my best work in deep collaboration with a diverse, highly engaged team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: need to spend more time refactoring&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: if we spend 1 day refactoring this code it will save us 10 days over the next year according to this quick model I put together&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: bored when I’m not learning a new tool&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: bored when I’m doing low impact work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: never made any big mistakes, my track record is clean&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: made mistakes that cost over $10M, here’s what I learned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: yes I’ll do it, but I’m already working 80 hours a week and I’m burning out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: yes I’ll do it, but I’m handing back item number 8 on my backlog to make room, ok?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: want a raise because I found out Bob makes more than me and I’m insulted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: contributed $X incremental to the company’s bottom line last year according to this quick model. Does that look right to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: performance is a secret, just between me and my manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: want my team to know what I’m working on so I can get their support and improve faster&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: compensation is a secret, just between me and my manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: share my comp numbers with anyone who asks, so all of us have more context to negotiate with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: happy so I won’t interview anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: interview a few times a year to stay current on the market, maintain my network, and to be reminded how much I like my current job&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: QA is lower value work than coding, so we should hire cheaper people than me and let them do it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: QA is a worthwhile safety net, but quality is my job, I’m not going to let them find bugs in MY code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: if I just had more authority, I could fix all our problems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: the more vulnerable I am, the better my team will be at fixing all our problems together&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: I’m an imposter and I’ve gotta do my best to hide it or I’ll be fired&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: I’m good at what I do, but there is always someone that knows more, I want to keep improving, and great teamwork is the most reliable way to bring out the best in me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junior: need to upgrade to the newest computer, 4 of the best monitors money can buy, every year or two&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior: I’m highly productive on my 4y old laptop, please don’t make me spend 3 days switching to a new one&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Commitment</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/on-commitment.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 17:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/on-commitment.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine you have a team of 5, a leader plus 4 others. The leader chooses not to
contribute ideas, preferring to select from the ideas of his team. The team
members are equally persuasive and generate equally good and viable ideas, but
the ideas are as opposite/orthogonal/different as they can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team has decided to make decisions together and fully commit to those
decisions, so all their creative, persuasive, and intellectual energy operates
in concert. They recognize that to do otherwise, to decide individually what to
do and then work individually to accomplish their individual goals will lead to
everyone spending tremendous energy to&amp;hellip;cancel each other out and go
nowhere. It is better to be wrong together than to be right separately,
because being wrong together offers the prospect to progress and learn, and
eventually move in the right direction together, with great energy and
speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each time this team gets together, they have 4 opposing ideas. Each team member
argues passionately for their idea. And then the leader picks one. As previously
mentioned, the team members are equally persuasive and their ideas equally good,
so 25% their idea gets picked. And 75% of the time it does not get picked. So,
75% of the time, they must commit to decisions they initially argued against.
75%. Most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it turns out that being an effective team member means getting really good at
engaging your full passion around decisions you initially argued against. But
what if you &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; the decision was wrong? Then of course, you&amp;rsquo;ll work to
undermine the decision and move the team in the &amp;lsquo;right&amp;rsquo; direction. And of
course, so will the other 2 team members who feel the same way, with different
&amp;lsquo;right&amp;rsquo; directions in mind. And guess what, the team is back to moving forward
much, much slower or not at all. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man. Committing to 75% of decisions I fought against is hard. Can we make this
easier? How about fewer ideas? If we had a team with fewer members, or with
members that think alike, my ideas would win more often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, that would be easier, but I&amp;rsquo;d bet on the team with a greater diversity
of viable options to outperform one with fewer ideas to choose from. I would
expect ideas that have to run a difficult gauntlet of criticism and strong
alternatives to outperform ideas that were not so well challenged. The battle is
where the value comes from, not the &amp;lsquo;winning&amp;rsquo; of the battle. It&amp;rsquo;s the opposite,
in fact&amp;hellip;if everyone values winning and everyone loses most of the time,
everyone will be frustrated and unhappy most of the time and that won&amp;rsquo;t lead to
the team doing its best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my wife and I argue about what&amp;rsquo;s the best thing to do to guide our son
towards a happy, fulfilled life, there is no winner or loser in our arguments.
It&amp;rsquo;s not a zero sum game, except if we turn it into one by playing politics for
our individual gain at the expense of our son and our family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, commitment gets both more important and harder as you climb the
organizational ladder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s more important because any even slight difference between leaders projects
down into the company and manifests as bloody unwinnable battles. They are
frustrating and expensive, with hours wasted and hard earned trust lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It gets harder because as you climb, you encounter a more diverse set of roles,
personalities, perspectives, and ideas. You aren&amp;rsquo;t surrounded by people that
think like you anymore. It also gets harder because, you were probably expecting
the opposite&amp;ndash;your dreams of advancement always included having more control, of
finally being able to do the things you &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; are right, but you were never in
a position of sufficient authority to mandate them. Well, sorry to disappoint
you, the CEO isn&amp;rsquo;t either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, the CEO &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; mandate $10K laptops for everyone, or double the brand
budget, or say all languages and frameworks are permitted in our codebase. They
have the authority to do all sorts of things. But, it turns out they don&amp;rsquo;t
exercise that authority because they are constrained by a desire to help the
company succeed, and it turns out that giving everyone everything they ask for
won&amp;rsquo;t do that. Even giving herself everything &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt; wants won&amp;rsquo;t do that.
Instead, she has the unenviable job of making the final choice, rejecting 75% of
her team&amp;rsquo;s ideas, and rallying them behind the idea they must commit to. The
leader has a hard, hard job. The team members have a hard job. Commitment is
hard. &lt;em&gt;Real&lt;/em&gt; commitment is really hard. But what&amp;rsquo;s the alternative?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Companies Are Made of People</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/companies-are-made-of-people.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/companies-are-made-of-people.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tablegroup.com/books/&#34;&gt;Patrick Lencioni&lt;/a&gt; stack at Mixbook. We are starting with
The Advantage and working our way backwards in order of publication. Turns out
companies are made out of human beings. &lt;a href=&#34;https://27gen.com/2012/04/18/smart-vs-healthy/&#34;&gt;Who knew&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculate the Full Price of That New Tech</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/calculate-the-full-price-of-that-new-tech.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/calculate-the-full-price-of-that-new-tech.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next time you get the urge to try out some new tech in production please
remember this: 5 years from now, long after you got bored with it, some poor sap
is going to be stuck fixing bugs in that new tech code you committed, because no
one ever took the time to rip it out, and something in production depends on it.  You&amp;rsquo;ve just introduce tech debt that will most likely be wasting someone&amp;rsquo;s time
for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying never try new tech, I&amp;rsquo;m just saying, pay for it: write the new
feature in the old tech FIRST, to keep yourself honest, then in the new tech,
and deploy and maintain each of them on 50% of the servers. If the old tech
wins, you up the capacity on the old tech servers, turn off the new ones, rip
out the new code, and you&amp;rsquo;ve got no tech debt&amp;ndash;experiment paid for in full. If
you don&amp;rsquo;t do that you&amp;rsquo;re Trojan horsing it in&amp;ndash;it sounds innocent enough to just
upgrade one service to try out the new tech, but then what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the new tech &amp;lsquo;wins&amp;rsquo;, hold on a second and make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve thought through
the implications&amp;hellip;if the new tech wins does that mean you&amp;rsquo;re committed to
porting 10M lines of code in the old tech to the new tech? What will that cost?  What benefits will you get? Or are you instead committing to slowly port things
over taking 10 years while maintaining +1 stacks increasing the cost of new
feature development, maintenance, infrastructure, recruiting, training, bug
fixes, troubleshooting, etc. Is it worth it? Really? $10M invested across 10
years in porting and +1 stack costs to achieve a 10% productivity boost once
you&amp;rsquo;re done?  If the math doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, maybe its not a good idea. And maybe do
the math before starting the project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Pay Down Tech Debt With Tech Debt</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/dont-pay-down-tech-debt-with-tech-debt.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 19:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/dont-pay-down-tech-debt-with-tech-debt.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An anti-pattern I keep running across is trying to solve tech debt problems by
adding a new tool to the stack. It&amp;rsquo;s like planning to pay off some of your $10K
in credit card debt by getting a new card with a $5K limit with a lower interest
rate&amp;hellip;but then using $1K of it pay down the old card and spending the other $4K
on new stuff. Now you&amp;rsquo;ve got $14K of debt to service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you switch from from your old unsexy, fragile PHP or Cobol codebase to
Haskell, you need to fix your spaghetti code, in place, with the existing tech.  If you don&amp;rsquo;t understand it well enough to do that, or if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the time
to do it, you won&amp;rsquo;t be replacing the old system with your shiny new system
either, you&amp;rsquo;ll just be adding yet more technical debt to you existing pile
of&amp;hellip;tech debt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Delay Gratification For Others</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/dont-delay-gratification-for-others.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/dont-delay-gratification-for-others.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its generally thought that the ability to delay your own gratification &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Delayed_gratification&#34;&gt;is
correlated&lt;/a&gt; with greater success. I buy that. But I think it&amp;rsquo;s the opposite
when dealing with others&amp;ndash;giving others what they want right now and you&amp;rsquo;ll win
their &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_startup&#34;&gt;support&lt;/a&gt;, their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/apple-is-the-first-1-trillion-company-in-history/2018/08/02/ea3e7a02-9599-11e8-a679-b09212fb69c2_story.html?noredirect=on&#34;&gt;dollars&lt;/a&gt;, and their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/09/us/politics/hillary-clinton-donald-trump-president.html&#34;&gt;vote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Laying a Foundation</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/on-laying-a-foundation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 18:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/on-laying-a-foundation.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When someone says &amp;lsquo;we are laying a foundation for X&amp;rsquo; I take it as code for
wasting resources and the sort of lazy thinking that goes with it&amp;hellip;at least if
they are talking about going dark to make some software, whether its about the
code, infrastructure, tooling, UI, or UX. Real (successful) developers ship
value now; rinse, repeat. You don&amp;rsquo;t win a race by standing still.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Ideal Product Manager</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/my-ideal-product-manager.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/my-ideal-product-manager.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My ideal product manager is more interested in disproving their idea than
proving it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are a scientist with the humility to &lt;em&gt;expect&lt;/em&gt; they&amp;rsquo;ll be wrong, the
patience to try again, and the hunger to find the truth however unaesthetic it
may be. They are a business person, more interested in getting results than
questing after their ideal UI or zero bugs. They are a crafts person, not an
artist&amp;ndash;they value utility over beauty. They are a judge, not a legislator. They
are an anthropologist, not a therapist. They are editor, not an author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this also describe my ideal CEO? No.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Hiring DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/stop-hiring-devops.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 21:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/stop-hiring-devops.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Look. The reason its so hard to find (great) DevOps engineers is that is a shit
job at most companies. When last I was hunting for a DevOps lead, most of the
folks I talked to had war/horror stories about working at a company (or two or
three) where they were on duty 24x7, the codebase was fragile, they got paged a
lot (at 2a), and they weren&amp;rsquo;t given the time or help they needed to dig
themselves out of the hole they were hired into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a great backend engineer with DevOps skills, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to put up
with that crap&amp;ndash;you just take the &amp;lsquo;devops&amp;rsquo; keyword off your resume, get a job
writing code instead of maintaining servers, and let some other sucker get paged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realizing this might be why I was having such a hard time finding great DevOps
engineers to talk to, I stopped trying to hire DevOps engineers&amp;ndash;instead I asked
my senior engineers to do DevOps and made it their top priority to &lt;em&gt;prevent
getting paged&lt;/em&gt;. They still don&amp;rsquo;t like being on pager duty, because it makes it
harder to go mountain biking on the weekend, but besides that, they generally
like the DevOps day-to-day work (when it comes up), they don&amp;rsquo;t get paged very
often (almost never when they are sleeping), and most of the time its a false
alarm that&amp;rsquo;s easy and quick to resolve. Bonus points: having the DevOps skill
set and access rights spread out among all our teams means fewer pager duty
rotations per engineer, each team can wrangle infrastructure when needed without
blocking on another team, and on the rare occasion of a real emergency there are
a lot of people that can help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Haskell Programming Book Isn&#39;t Good Enough</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/the-haskell-programming-book-isnt-good-enough.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/the-haskell-programming-book-isnt-good-enough.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We (the human race) spend/waste an enormous amount of energy writing code that won&amp;rsquo;t last. We constantly cut ourselves on the sharp edges of C, PHP, Perl, Ruby, Java, and lots of other languages that were the best and brightest of their day, but they don&amp;rsquo;t go far enough protecting us from our own stupidity, laziness, distractedness, busyness&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point is, I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a way out of this mess. And as someone in management, I&amp;rsquo;m responsible for either doing nothing or making intentional choices about what tools galaxy my team lives in and how we go about our work of creating business value through software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I really like Haskell. I see the future in it or something like it. But man, I&amp;rsquo;m having a hard time getting my brain around it. I&amp;rsquo;ve read a bunch of books. I&amp;rsquo;ve written some code. But with 20 years of imperitive thinking pounded into my brain, its tough to load all these new abstractions into my brain at the same time and apply them effectively in real life. And that worries me. Because smart Haskell advocates like Gabriel Gonzalez &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Gabriel439/post-rfc/blob/master/sotu.md#education&#34;&gt;say Haskell has finally got some good docs&lt;/a&gt; as of &lt;a href=&#34;http://haskellbook.com/&#34;&gt;The Haskell Programming Book&lt;/a&gt; but having worked through 3/4 of it, I still struggle to do what I want with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Gabriel439/Haskell-Turtle-Library/&#34;&gt;Haskell-based shell scripts&lt;/a&gt; or a Haskell-based port of my (statically generated) blog. And while I like to think I hire and work with people smarter than me, as long as the learning curve is this high, Haskell is going to struggle to get beyond the handful of niches its into today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope the Haskell book is just the start. I have blind faith that there&amp;rsquo;s a way to teach its concepts in a way that&amp;rsquo;s even more accessible to more people. And I hope someone does it, because we&amp;rsquo;ve all put enough blood and sweat into software that won&amp;rsquo;t last as it is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby vs Haskell: Ruby is Lego, Haskell is Steel</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/ruby-vs-haskell-ruby-is-lego-haskell-is-steel.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 02:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/ruby-vs-haskell-ruby-is-lego-haskell-is-steel.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ruby feels like working with Legos: its easy to pickup, delightful from the start, and you can make amazing things with it quickly. But as your creations get bigger and bigger, they become increasing awkward and fragile. Using Haskell is like working with steel: its difficult to get started and takes a lot of energy to do anything, even after you&amp;rsquo;re good at it, but you can build very strong, resilient, large structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fell in love with Ruby in 2009 and have been &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mixbook.com/&#34;&gt;working&lt;/a&gt; with it ever since. I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://haskellbook.com/&#34;&gt;books&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bonds/winot&#34;&gt;spending time&lt;/a&gt; with Haskell a bit over the past year, and I still find it difficult to use. But I&amp;rsquo;m starting to get it, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t think it gets a whole lot easier anytime soon, at least from where I stand, I can see &lt;a href=&#34;https://ggr.com/minimize-maximum-stupidity.html&#34;&gt;why&lt;/a&gt; I might be using, or something like it more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mediocrity Isn&#39;t Worth It</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/mediocrity-isnt-worth-it.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/mediocrity-isnt-worth-it.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Companies and teams tend towards mediocrity over time. Call it entropy, call it regression to the mean&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering my own sins in this area lately, and I find myself wanting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mediocrity is infectious and it kills motivation, creativity, and productivity. But its sooo easy. It can start with a bad hire, whose not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad. They&amp;rsquo;ve been here for years, they are likeable, they are loyal, they&amp;rsquo;ve got outstanding raw potential&amp;hellip;but they struggle to get results. So after trying unsuccessfully to level them up, I (their manager) put them on the lower risk projects, the lower difficulty stuff, because, heck, there&amp;rsquo;s infinite work and nobody else wants to do it. And firing people is hard&amp;ndash;it hurts them, their friends in the company, me&amp;hellip;and my boss starts to wonder if I&amp;rsquo;m a bad manager, after all, I have bad reports. Its just so much easier to sweep the whole thing under the rug and focus my attention elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, they&amp;rsquo;re taking up a seat that could be filled by someone excellent. AND the excellent people on the team keep having to compensate for the mediocre guy and they are getting tired of it. Maybe they decide, heck, if that&amp;rsquo;s the bar, why am I trying so hard? Or more likely, if they try so hard and are going to get blocked by mediocre people anyway, why not try harder on their side projects instead? A few of those and&amp;hellip;voila! I&amp;rsquo;ve got a bonified mediocre team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I want a world class team, I need to fix people that don&amp;rsquo;t make the cut or fire them. Sometimes its my fault&amp;ndash;I hire someone whose awesome, but they aren&amp;rsquo;t the right fit for &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; team with &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; need. That sucks. Sometimes its their fault. Sometimes people change. Sometimes the company changes. There are lots of reasons and lots of paths to mediocrity, its the easy way to be. But its not worth it. I&amp;rsquo;m not interested in just making it through life, I want to contribute something meaningful, and I can&amp;rsquo;t do that alone, nor as part of a mediocre team, and as a manager and leader, no one else is going to make my team excellent, that&amp;rsquo;s my job.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture, Brand, (and Founders) FTW</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/culture-brand-and-founders-ftw.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/culture-brand-and-founders-ftw.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The quality of the people and the culture of a company define its trajectory. Brand is the bank where it stores the value it creates along the way. Everything else is implementation detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have great people operating in a great culture, you&amp;rsquo;re operating on borrowed time. Maybe you get lucky and can ride that luck for a while, but unless you build a sustainable, quality culture, you&amp;rsquo;re dying a slow (or fast) death. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t banking your wins in your brand, its like you&amp;rsquo;re living hand to mouth&amp;ndash;it works fine while things are good, but bumps in the road will be painful, leading to loss of talent and an eroding culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a strong team, culture, and brand, the world is your oyster. You start in books and pivot to hosting. You can start in luxury cars and extend to solar panels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies that no longer have their founders are at an inherent disadvantage&amp;ndash;the founders are the only people within the org that have the moral authority and political clout necessary to drive a strong, high quality culture and make dramatic changes to protect and grow the culture, when they are needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimize Maximum Stupidity</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/minimize-maximum-stupidity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/minimize-maximum-stupidity.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TL;DR scaling a dev team + code base has more to do with minimizing stupidity than with maximizing brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with some amount of C, C++, Java, Ruby, Python, Bourne Shell, PHP, HTML, Objective-C, Haskell, and Javascript, among others. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to imagine that the range of code quality, of an average line of code by an average engineer, using C as a sort of baseline, looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ggr_com.s3.amazonaws.com/images/language-scale.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;3&#34; title=&#34;ranges of brilliance and stupidity by language&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure you have your exceptions with folks that tend more the top or bottom of the range, but it seems that over time, most people and most projects encounter the full range for their language&amp;hellip;I think it was John Carmack that said: if the compiler will let you do it, it will end up in your codebase. That.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen plenty of code that was intended to be a throw away prototype but turned into production code. And plenty of projects under time pressure where corners were cut to meet a deadline, and the cleanup never seemed to be the highest ROI opportunity. And even when it all went right otherwise, requirement changes might still blow big holes in the technical design leading to tough choices between moving the product forward faster in the short-term or pausing product progress in order to refactor and avoid a bunch of tech debt. The point is, shit happens, its not primarily a lack of skill or some character defect that leads to the low end of the scale being used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put that another way&amp;ndash;the problem is not that there are a bunch of lazy, undisciplined idiots writing OpenSSL code (or insert your favorite punching bag project here). I&amp;rsquo;m amazed at how much time and love people put into code, be it freely given away for the good of all humanity like OpenSSL (thank you!!), or be it work for hire. No, the problem is that the low end of the range is too easy to use and its consequences are too costly&amp;hellip;much more costly than the high end of the range is cost-savings-y, in my experience. I mean, after a few million deaths in car accidents, you start to realize that blaming the drivers only gets you so far, and maybe adding &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unsafe_at_Any_Speed&#34;&gt;seatbelts&lt;/a&gt;, airbags, speed limits, and other safety features is a more promising approach to saving lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m less excited about dynamic languages than I used to be, because they expand both sides of the range, which is a net negative on large teams and/or codebases. We don&amp;rsquo;t need more brilliance, we need less stupidity. And we&amp;rsquo;re all stupid at times&amp;ndash;I don&amp;rsquo;t mean that in a character defect sort of way, I mean that we all make regrettable decisions, for whatever reason. That&amp;rsquo;s why tests, CI, linters, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamasutra.com/view/news/128836/InDepth_Static_Code_Analysis.php&#34;&gt;static code analysis,&lt;/a&gt; code coverage tools, etc. are important. They help add friction to the low end of the range. Languages like Haskell and Rust make it harder to screw up, which means less screwing up. If the path of least resistance (on a team/codebase) is also the path to greater code quality, code quality will go up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Employee Morale Scale</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/an-employee-morale-scale.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/an-employee-morale-scale.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The scale goes from low to high morale. My biggest realization of the past five
years, related to morale, is how weak a tool high comp is for driving morale.
It can make people very happy for a short time, but after that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t do
much on its own&amp;ndash;the steady state for high comp (alone) is no better than the
&amp;lsquo;passively looking&amp;rsquo; step of the scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rage quit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;actively looking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;passively looking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not looking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;like the work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;working efficiently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;like the boss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;like the coworkers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;appreciated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doing the best work of my career&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;respected internally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;world famous and loved by many&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Points</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/learning-points.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/learning-points.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I joined Mixbook 4 years ago, we were running very large, coarse
experiments, where we&amp;rsquo;d spend 3-6 months with 2-4 people building some new
feature until we thought it was done, then we&amp;rsquo;d ship. These days, we&amp;rsquo;re
a bit leaner, with the same sized teams typically shipping a new experiment
within 2-4 weeks. But we don&amp;rsquo;t want to stop there. Lately we&amp;rsquo;ve been talking
about how to get it down to 1-2 days per experiment, so we can ship 5 or
more per sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards that end I&amp;rsquo;ve dusted off a tool I created a couple years ago when
one my team&amp;rsquo;s was struggling to reach their growth targets. They were building
expensive new features, seeing what would stick, then trying something else,
but the features were so costly to make, that they weren&amp;rsquo;t learning very
quickly at all. With a unprofitable win to loss ratio, it didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense
to keep funding the project&amp;ndash;we needed to get the ratio up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we started tracking a new metric: learning points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-points&#34;&gt;Learning Points&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning Points represent progress towards understanding how to dramatically
grow the business. Projects earn learning points as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;0-learning-point&#34;&gt;+0 Learning Point&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;started without a hypothesis on file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR impact is not measured and/or is not measurable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-learning-point&#34;&gt;+1 Learning Point&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;started with a measurable hypothesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AND the results were measured, including both benefit and cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AND the hypothesis was proved or disproved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AND we gained a non-trivial insight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AND the hypothesis and results were recorded for easy reference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-learning-point-1&#34;&gt;+1 Learning Point&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;started with franchise KPIs clearly defined&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AND a KPI improved with 95% confidence and 10k+ observations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-learning-point-2&#34;&gt;+1 Learning Point&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;got the LP for a KPI improvement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AND there’s strong evidence to support the same pattern can be repeated 3 or
more times more, achieving similar gains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the size of the KPI improvement (or degradation) does not affect the
LP value. This is intentional&amp;ndash;bigger improvements in KPIs may be worth more in
the short run, but they don’t necessarily teach more, especially if they take a
long time to complete, i.e. they have a high LP/SP ratio. This scoring system
is designed to reward learning velocity and &amp;rsquo;lean&amp;rsquo;-er projects that get us the
most learning value at the lowest possible cost in effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to how non-backlog work is considered &amp;lsquo;waste&amp;rsquo;, as it does not increase
story point velocity on a Scrum team, work that does not produce learning point
velocity is considered waste on a Lean team and should be scrutinized and
targeted for elimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;back-to-our-story&#34;&gt;Back To Our Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we started using Learning Points, we shifted from a gut based, &amp;lsquo;we like
this idea more&amp;rsquo; approach to prioritizing the backlog, to one that asked the questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what are we trying to learn?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why are we trying to learn that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how much upside is there to learning that, i.e. does it scale?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do we avoid an inconclusive result?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how can we learn that same thing, but cheaper?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got better and better at answering those questions, our learning velocity
went up, and our ROI went up. We never achieved the growth we needed to to keep
going with that project, but we learned a lot about learning faster and we&amp;rsquo;ve
applied many of the ideas to other projects and other teams, which is how we&amp;rsquo;ve
managed to get leaner and learner. Perhaps the time has come again to measure
our learning velocity and see if it will help us push our learning efficiency
further.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Levels of Engineering Culture</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/the-levels-of-engineering-culture.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/the-levels-of-engineering-culture.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No process or rules to get in the way! All we do around here is code. It&amp;rsquo;s like
5 years old playing soccer&amp;ndash;everyone runs straight at the ball/latest shiny
object. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have rules/principles/policies/best-practices that we &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; (aka think) will
make us more productive, i.e. we use CI and CD! All PRs require a code review.
100% test coverage. 20% time (for innovating). We use Scrum/Kanban/Agile. We use
planning poker. We use burndown charts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have rules that we &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; make us more productive because we continually
measure their impact and can prove it. We alter or drop rules that no longer
work. We believe that a good rule set is good enough for a healthy engineering
culture, but its not enough for a great one. To get from good to great requires
&lt;em&gt;data driven&lt;/em&gt; feedback loops and continuous improvement informed by the data,
i.e. Agile + Data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Level 3, but we aren&amp;rsquo;t just measuring code productivity, we&amp;rsquo;re measuring
the profitability of our work, aka outcomes efficiency. We can use data to
demonstrate which productivity projects are worth more to the business than
which marketing/rain making projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Scrum Master Is a Personal Trainer</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/a-scrum-master-is-a-personal-trainer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 03:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/a-scrum-master-is-a-personal-trainer.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scrum Master is a greatly misunderstood and under appreciated role. On most
teams I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered its taken on by the PO or its ignored entirely. I&amp;rsquo;m
guilty of this sin myself and when &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; am not ignoring it, I&amp;rsquo;m playing scrum
master across way too many teams, in addition to way too many other duties, so
its not done terribly well&amp;hellip;better than nothing I suppose, but better is
possible, and, I think, a good investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that a Scrum Master is like a personal trainer for a group of
people. Some people are disciplined and are able to get a good workout on their
own, some people are less disciplined and struggle to get results at the gym.
But where ever you are on the spectrum, having a personal trainer who spends
time with you, helping you use the right technique and offering motivational
support to help you push a bit harder on the workout or when controlling your
eating habits, can have a huge impact on your rate of progress and your final
result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without a personal trainer the groups&amp;rsquo; results suffer not just a little, but a
lot. A personal trainer that&amp;rsquo;s spread out over 20 people is better than no
personal trainer at all, but much better results may be achieved by adding
another personal trainer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My guess is a good scrum master that&amp;rsquo;s not spread out can boost their team&amp;rsquo;s
productivity by 20-50% depending on their proficiency with scrum, their level of
interruption, and their seniority. Besides that, its more fun being more
productive, so there is a morale benefit. In short, a good scrum master per
scrum team readily pays for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On OKRs Requiring Miracles</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/on-okrs-requiring-miracles.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 19:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/on-okrs-requiring-miracles.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At least one person says you should be thinking you&amp;rsquo;ll need &lt;a href=&#34;http://eleganthack.com/the-art-of-the-okr/&#34;&gt;a miracle&lt;/a&gt; to
pull off your OKRs or they aren&amp;rsquo;t hard enough. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ggr.com/stables-and-volatiles-goals.html&#34;&gt;I worry&lt;/a&gt; that that sort of goal
feels too much like gambling to some of the folks I manage, but what&amp;rsquo;s a better
bar for OKR difficulty?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the goal should be to have objectives that &lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt; innovation to
succeed&amp;ndash;they need to be daunting enough that you must realize a new, hitherto
unused or not yet invented technique to pull them off. I like that better&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m
better at thinking of innovative solutions than I am at securing miracles. I&amp;rsquo;d
rather make my luck than be lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stables and Volatiles: Goals</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/stables-and-volatiles-goals.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/stables-and-volatiles-goals.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read &lt;a href=&#34;http://randsinrepose.com/archives/stables-and-volatiles/&#34;&gt;Stables and Volatiles&lt;/a&gt;, go read it and then come
back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working on &lt;a href=&#34;https://weekdone.com/resources/objectives-key-results&#34;&gt;OKRs&lt;/a&gt; this week and pondering whether objectives that require
&amp;lsquo;just&amp;rsquo; working hard are good enough, or whether our objectives should &lt;a href=&#34;http://eleganthack.com/the-art-of-the-okr/&#34;&gt;require a
miracle&lt;/a&gt; to pull off. Let&amp;rsquo;s say, for the sake of argument, one of our objectives
has a 10% chance of success if we work on it at a normal level and a 20% chance
of success if we bust our butts and pull off a couple brilliant moves. When my
team sees the goal, I imagine something like this going through their heads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;volatile&#34;&gt;Volatile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a tough goal. But if we work together, we can double our chance of
success. And if we succeed it will be awesome! Plus, even if we don&amp;rsquo;t succeed,
when we shoot for the stars, we&amp;rsquo;ll at least hit the moon and that will be great
too. Let&amp;rsquo;s do this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stable&#34;&gt;Stable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will most likely miss that goal. And even if we all work extra hard, we will
still most likely miss that goal&amp;ndash;chance plays the biggest role here. If I work
just hard enough to get full credit for participating and then invest some time
in an extra credit project, I can hedge: if we get lucky, we hit the goal and we
have my extra credit win too. If we miss the goal (as is likely) we&amp;rsquo;ll at least
have my extra credit project as a win. If we miss the goal and my extra credit
project doesn&amp;rsquo;t work out, at least I learned a new skill and had fun while
working on my extra credit project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volatiles seek glory and the chance at an interesting outcome. Give them Big,
Hairy, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Hairy_Audacious_Goal&#34;&gt;Audacious Goals&lt;/a&gt; and stand back. Stables seek high probability success.
Give them the chance to take an initiative from 90% to 99% probability of
success and stand back. Just don&amp;rsquo;t confuse or mix the two or you&amp;rsquo;ll end up
demotivating a lot of your team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Interviewing Policy</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/open-interviewing-policy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 05:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/open-interviewing-policy.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mixbook.com/careers&#34;&gt;interviewing a lot of people&lt;/a&gt; in the past few weeks and I&amp;rsquo;ve been
wondering how they, you know, get 4 hours off in the middle of the work day to
interview. Fake doctor&amp;rsquo;s appointment? Call in sick? No one is paying attention
to their office hours? WFH that becomes undocumented PTO? My guess is its not on
the record&amp;hellip;they aren&amp;rsquo;t telling their bosses that they are going on
interviews. There&amp;rsquo;s some level of sneaking around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems to me that the interviewing taboo is in no one&amp;rsquo;s best interest&amp;ndash;not the
employee, not the employer. If you are the kind of employer/manager that tries
to retain employees by keeping them ignorant of other opportunities, good luck
pulling that off in Silicon Valley&amp;hellip;you&amp;rsquo;re just going to annoy your top talent
and be left with, what&amp;rsquo;s left. Most of the talented people I know interview a
couple times a year even when they aren&amp;rsquo;t interested in making a move&amp;ndash;they
consider it basic career hygiene to stay in touch with what the market is like,
it also helps them figure out what they want (from their next career move).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to pitch my boss on an open interview policy for our company. I send
him a crazy idea like this once a quarter or so. :) Everyone is expected to
interview at least twice a year. You put it on your calendar and call it what
it is. And to prove we&amp;rsquo;re serious, you get, say, 1% of your annual salary as a
bonus for each set of interviews taken to 2nd round or later each year, 2 max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mixbook is a great place to work, the people are great, the work environment
is awesome, I believe that will be even more apparent to employees that look
around, and morale will benefit from folks seeing that for themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interviews become an opportunity to improve the employee+manager relationship.
Instead of sneaking around we can talk about the interviews. How did it go?
Oh, you like the idea of a role doing X? I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that, we need that too,
would you like a chance to do that here? They pay 20% more? I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that
was market, let&amp;rsquo;s make an adjustment!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are less likely to retain people that aren&amp;rsquo;t a good fit. Hey, it happens,
not every employee and every company stay in perfect alignment forever.
Parting ways on mutually agreeable terms seems far superior to the
alternatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Higher morale. I mean, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you rather work at a place where you can be
open about your career? Would you give that up lightly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our employees might interview more than they would otherwise (sort of the
point). And that may lead to higher churn. My bet is if churn goes up at all,
it would be &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; churn, where we were growing apart and the right thing to
do for both parties was to move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results &gt; Hours</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/results-hours.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 20:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/results-hours.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When one is trying to increase productivity, there are 3 areas of particular
interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hours worked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tasks completed per hour worked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unit of impact per task completed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hours-worked&#34;&gt;Hours Worked&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company culture where you work sets the tone for how many hours you work.
Startups tend to value long hours, but plenty of larger companies do too. Adding
more hours can be very effective in the short-run, but in the long-run the gains
can be elusive, as people shift more of their personal chores and relaxation
time into their work hours in order to satisfy the expectation that they are in
the office all the time, while still striking the balance that they prefer.
There are plenty of tools to counterbalance the distractions and keep focused,
from inspired goals to deadlines to pressure from a boss, but they don&amp;rsquo;t scale
well. My guess is that its unusual to find a (knowledge worker) organization
that can sustain gains from long hours when properly accounting for hours &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;
working (but in the office!), the cost of management time to maintain a long
hours culture, and the costs of employee churn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tasks-per-hour&#34;&gt;Tasks Per Hour&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting more done per unit of effort is the realm of Scrum, tools, process, and
organization design. Scrum Retrospectives can be an especially powerful tool for
uncovering inefficiency and fixing it. The improvements made to efficiency form
a virtual cycle, freeing up more time and accelerating further improvements, all
while making faster progress on the roadmap than before. Unlike increasing Hours
Worked there&amp;rsquo;s no real tradeoff, everyone wins, the gains are sustainable and
they often scale even further than Hours Worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;impact-per-task&#34;&gt;Impact Per Task&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing the right projects to work on is the hardest place to gain efficiency,
but in many organizations its also the biggest opportunity, offering 2-10x the
gains that the other two approaches do. Scrum teams measure backlog Velocity to
help them stay focused on roadmap progress instead of getting side tracked on
other tasks. Lean Startup teams release early and often, minimizing the cost of
learning so they can double down on the ideas that actually work in the
marketplace. 1 in 1000 startups succeed past their first year. Imagine if you
could increase that to 2 or 3 or more&amp;hellip;the possible gains of picking the
winners and NOT paying for the losers are big.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Scott Bonds Rules of Presentations</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/the-scott-bonds-rules-of-presentations.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 16:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/the-scott-bonds-rules-of-presentations.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got another deck to put together. Seems like a good time to write
down the Scott Bonds Rules of Presentations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;entertain your audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;do not forget to make your point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;do not put text on your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;entertain-your-audience&#34;&gt;Entertain Your Audience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first rule because its the most important. When you
entertain your audience, you make them into better listeners. They are
more engaged, more open minded, and more likely to absorb and retain
your message. They are also more likely to want to hear you speak again.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bing_Gordon&#34;&gt;Bing Gordon&lt;/a&gt; reveals 1 new, significant trade secret when he speaks,
making his talks buzzworthy in addition to entertaining his audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-not-forget-to-make-your-point&#34;&gt;Do Not Forget To Make Your Point&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever watch a brilliant ad on TV that made you LOL, but then were left
wondering what the ad was for? Yah, don&amp;rsquo;t do that. First entertain,
second get your point across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-not-put-text-on-your-slides&#34;&gt;Do Not Put Text On Your Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look. I&amp;rsquo;m lazy and pressed for time too, so I&amp;rsquo;ll forgive you if you
break this rule. But the best presentations do not have text on the
slides&amp;ndash;instead they use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.philnel.com/2010/08/08/powerpoint/&#34;&gt;visuals&lt;/a&gt; as emotional queues reinforcing
the words that are spoken&amp;ndash;they do what the soundtrack does for a movie.
And see rule #1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Screen Resumes For &#39;A&#39; Players</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/how-to-screen-resumes-for-a-players.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 21:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-screen-resumes-for-a-players.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I was asked how I figure out whether the resume I&amp;rsquo;m looking at belongs
to an &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; player or someone of a lesser grade. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A&amp;rsquo;s tend to list accomplishments, and they tend to have accomplishments that
really stand out, even in their hobbies. You see stuff like &lt;em&gt;1st place in the
Chicago Assembler Speed Competition&lt;/em&gt; on A engineers&amp;rsquo; resumes. Designers point
to a portfolio that you look at and go &amp;lsquo;wow&amp;rsquo;. Managers talk about team
transformations or compelling business outcomes. &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; product managers look
like CEOs&amp;ndash;they display strong evidence of vision, leadership, and meaningful
outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B&amp;rsquo;s and C&amp;rsquo;s focus on duties instead of accomplishments. They try to make what
they&amp;rsquo;ve done sound bigger by emphasizing the size of the team or company, but
when you read between the lines you realize they just organize meetings and
push documents around. Not that I have anything against documents and meetings
(well, I do despise unproductive meetings), but those are a means to an end,
not an end unto themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coming War for Design Talent</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/the-coming-war-for-design-talent.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 19:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/the-coming-war-for-design-talent.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ggr_com.s3.amazonaws.com/images/path1_vs_path2b.png&#34; alt=&#34;9&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2010/11/storm-clouds.html&#34;&gt;war&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.v3.co.uk/v3-uk/news/2167177/software-engineer-role-world-s-profession-demand-pay&#34;&gt;rages on&lt;/a&gt; for software engineers, I can&amp;rsquo;t help
wondering when UX, interaction designers, and product managers are going
to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastcodesign.com/1669445/how-facebook-finds-the-best-design-talent-and-keeps-them-happy&#34;&gt;have their turn&lt;/a&gt;. For a lot of software projects adding a
rockstar engineer can boost productivity by more than their substantial
individual contribution, but adding a rockstar designer can &lt;em&gt;double&lt;/em&gt; a
team&amp;rsquo;s output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say, for the sake of argument, that 1 in 5 of a good designer&amp;rsquo;s
decisions are adding value a year after they are released; let&amp;rsquo;s say a
rockstar achieves 2 in 5. The team building what the rockstar designer
chose are happier (more of their work has an impact), their customers
are happier (better &amp;lsquo;awesome&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;meh&amp;rsquo; ratio for new features), and
&lt;strong&gt;they are twice as productive&lt;/strong&gt; as measured by value to the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Velocity_(software_development)&#34;&gt;Velocity&lt;/a&gt; is important, but progress in the wrong direction is only
useful inasmuch as it &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Lean-Startup-Entrepreneurs-Continuous/dp/0307887898&#34;&gt;helps you figure out the right direction&lt;/a&gt;.
Some people &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_jobs&#34;&gt;guess&lt;/a&gt; better than others, some people &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shigeru_Miyamoto&#34;&gt;know&lt;/a&gt; more
than others, some people can &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_pincus&#34;&gt;read the tea leaves&lt;/a&gt; better than
others, and all of them are going to be in increasing demand as more
companies focus on the tremendous leverage of their design talent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Kinds of Engineering Leader</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/two-kinds-of-engineering-leader.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/two-kinds-of-engineering-leader.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ggr_com.s3.amazonaws.com/images/jordan_and_jackson.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a software company is searching for a new CTO or VP of Engineering,
they tend to look for either a Chief of Surgery or a Head Coach. Hiring
the right (or wrong) one can mean the difference between success and
failure as a company. Knowing which you are can help you choose the
right opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Chief of Surgery&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the best, if not the best, software
engineer at the company. Often they are career engineers with limited
management experience. But for a small startup where getting the code
right is critical and the CTO is 1/4 of the development team, the CoS
offers a huge boost in productivity by setting coding standards,
establishing the architecture, drawing the technology roadmap, and
coding like crazy. Basketball equivalent: Michael Jordan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Head Coach&lt;/strong&gt; is a former engineer who has spent years developing
their people, project, and communication skills in order to bring out
the best in their team. As a company grows and can count a number of
highly skilled engineers among its ranks, the engineering team will
usually include leaders who can help with coding standards and
architecture, but its up to the Head Coach to understand and grow
individual talent, to forge a team that&amp;rsquo;s worth more than the sum of its
parts, and to partner with the rest of the organization so the company
builds the right software and achieves the best possible
results. Basketball equivalent: Phil Jackson.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
