<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on game, game. repeat.</title>
    <link>https://ggr.com/tags/music.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on game, game. repeat.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 13:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Dropouts and Cutting Out When Using AirTunes on your Airport Express</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/how-to-fix-dropouts-and-cutting-out-when-using-airtunes-on-your-airport-express.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 13:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-fix-dropouts-and-cutting-out-when-using-airtunes-on-your-airport-express.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ggr_com.s3.amazonaws.com/images/setup-a-5Ghz-network.png&#34; alt=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For months I struggled with frequent audio dropouts while connecting to
stereo through my Airport Express from my Mac laptop. My connection was
strong (5/5 bars on wifi) but I still had dropouts. I tried every manner
of fix and none was satisfactory. Until now. I seem to have stumbled on
a solution and its one I had not read about before. No doubt it won&amp;rsquo;t
work for everyone because of the many different possible causes for bad
connectivity to your AirTunes device of choice. But here&amp;rsquo;s what worked
for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to dramatically reduce the frequency of dropouts playing
music through iTunes by enabling the separate 5ghz network option in my
Airport Extreme and then connecting my Mac to that new, 5ghz only,
network rather than the 2.4ghz network. After that smooth sailing!! I
have a central Airport Extreme to which both my Mac and my Airport
Express (which connects to my stereo) are connected. Using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geekosystem.com/crouching-lion-hidden-wifi/&#34;&gt;OSX Lion&amp;rsquo;s built in wifi troubleshooting app&lt;/a&gt;, I noticed that when I&amp;rsquo;m not right
next to my Airport Extreme, my Mac often switches to the 2.4ghz network.
I live in an apartment complex and I can see lots of wifi networks
nearby operating at 2.4ghz. So my theory is that by forcing my computer
to use the 5ghz signal (since its just as strong where I use my Mac) I&amp;rsquo;m
able to avoid the congestion on 2.4ghz. Let me know if that helps you
out and good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandora vs Last.fm</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/pandora-vs-last.fm.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2010 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/pandora-vs-last.fm.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ggr_com.s3.amazonaws.com/images/pandora-vs-last.fm_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re both good, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://last.fm/&#34;&gt;Last.fm&lt;/a&gt; wins. How can this be? Last.fm&amp;rsquo;s
amazing powers are put on display after the break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last.fm can perform these amazing tricks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Tag (and Multitag) radio**. If you want to listen to &amp;lsquo;piano&amp;rsquo;
music on Pandora, you have to select a song or artist that exemplifies
&amp;lsquo;piano&amp;rsquo;, then vote up/down songs until Pandora figures out what you
want. On Last.fm, you can simply tell it to play a radio station
made up of music that has the &amp;lsquo;piano&amp;rsquo; tag. Multitag stations are
particularly powerful because you can further refine your selection,
i.e. &amp;lsquo;piano&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;happy&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More variety&lt;/strong&gt;. After listening to similar radio stations on both
Pandora and Last.fm for 8+ hours, I noticed a lot of repeated songs on
Pandora, but no repeated songs on Last.fm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apps&lt;/strong&gt; (and API). Google&amp;rsquo;s vision of the future puts the browser
at the center of the universe, so call me a luddite, but I still prefer
desktop apps for a lot of things. Last.fm has a spiffy Flash-based
player, but there are also a lot of &lt;a href=&#34;http://osx.iusethis.com/app/everplay&#34;&gt;desktop apps&lt;/a&gt; that are more
pleasant to use (more stable, nicer looking, etc). Pandora, it
appears, is an entirely closed system without a publicly available
API. While developers have still found ways to &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/pandoraboy/&#34;&gt;wrap the Pandora
Flash widget&lt;/a&gt; in apps that add some features (like Growl
notification), they leave a lot to be desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly subscription&lt;/strong&gt;. Want to try Last.fm out for a month, no
commitment? Its easy to do. Pandora, on the other hand, only
offers their premium service in 1-year chunks. It&amp;rsquo;s only $36, but I
still prefer Last.fm&amp;rsquo;s bite-sized, 1 month for $3, offering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
