<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>openbsd on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/openbsd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in openbsd on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/openbsd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Install Coreboot Onto Your Lenovo Thinkpad X200 Laptop</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2017-02-27-how-to-install-coreboot-on-your-x200/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2017-02-27-how-to-install-coreboot-on-your-x200/</guid>
      <description>I flashed a Lenovo x200 with Coreboot with Intel microcode enabled, ME removed, and the gigabit ethernet firmware from Libreboot. Everything seems to work with OpenBSD (my daily driver OS). Unlike with Libreboot, which comes with a Grub2 payload, Coreboot uses the SeaBIOS payload by default and it can boot an encrypted OpenBSD volume. I&amp;rsquo;m encountering what seems to be a random lockup every few days, haven&amp;rsquo;t had a chance to troubleshoot it yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Run an Arch Linux (Qemu) Guest On an OpenBSD Host</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2014-09-30-how-to-run-an-arch-linux-qemu-guest-on-an-openbsd-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2014-09-30-how-to-run-an-arch-linux-qemu-guest-on-an-openbsd-host/</guid>
      <description>The main stumbling block I had to overcome to get various flavors of Linux to install as a guest OS on a Qemu instance, running on an OpenBSD source, was to disable APIC, not be confused with ACPI.
With Arch Linux you do this:
 boot the Arch Linux CD (in your Qemu guest) press tab to config the boot command add a space and then &amp;lsquo;noapic&amp;rsquo; to the boot command press Enter to boot install Arch Linux on your Qemu guest hard drive add the &amp;lsquo;noapic&amp;rsquo; parameter to boot command in your boot config, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Set the Default App For Opening a Directory Under OpenBSD &#43; Gnome 3</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2014-09-11-how-to-set-the-default-app-for-opening-a-directory-under-openbsd-gnome-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2014-09-11-how-to-set-the-default-app-for-opening-a-directory-under-openbsd-gnome-3/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you want &amp;lsquo;open .&amp;rsquo; to open a directory in your favorite GUI file manager, not EasyTag. Sometimes you wonder how EasyTag ever come to be the default app for opening a folder. Sometimes you do this:
$ xdg-mime query filetype . inode/directory $ xdg-mime query default inode/directory easytag.desktop $ xdg-mime default nautilus.desktop inode/directory $ xdg-mime query default inode/directory nautilus.desktop $ open .  You&amp;rsquo;re welcome.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
