<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on game, game. repeat.</title>
    <link>https://ggr.com/tags/politics.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on game, game. repeat.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 10:54:33 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Couple Of My Duties As a Citizen of a Democracy</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/a-couple-of-my-duties-as-a-citizen-of-a-democracy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 10:54:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/a-couple-of-my-duties-as-a-citizen-of-a-democracy.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;speak-up&#34;&gt;Speak Up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must speak up in public forums like LinkedIN, Twitter, and Christmas dinner. I’ve been taught that talking politics is impolite. But leaving good ideas unsaid and undefended, and letting bad ideas dominate the conversation and lead to bad decisions is even more impolite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;change-my-mind&#34;&gt;Change My Mind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must listen, learn, and change my mind, which is way harder than defending my beliefs and standing my ground. It requires humility to admit I was wrong and courage to let others see my mistakes. I have to love my community enough to do what’s right for us instead of what makes me look good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Americans like to think of themselves as uncompromising. But our true genius is for compromise. Our whole government’s founded on it.”&lt;/em&gt; —Shelby Foote&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open (Source) the NSA</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/open-source-the-nsa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 17:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/open-source-the-nsa.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Democracy and government secrets are at odds with each other. Keeping secrets
and accessing the secrets of others is a way to gain power. And while we want
our government to gain power over people that seek to harm us, we do not want
them to have power over the innocent citizen they answer to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution is transparency. The NSA must make a monthly copy of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the
data and software from their systems and make it available to the public 2
years later. 2 years gives the NSA and our government time to take advantage of
their secrets. And then it gives the people a chance to scrutinize the NSA&amp;rsquo;s
choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Won&amp;rsquo;t this reveal everyone&amp;rsquo;s deepest, darkest secrets? I don&amp;rsquo;t want &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt;
emails to be made public!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: I suggest a one-time purge be allowed when we implement this policy for the
first time. After that, if the information shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be made public in 2 years,
the NSA shouldn&amp;rsquo;t collect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Won&amp;rsquo;t this greatly reduce the NSA efficacy? The terrorists will know all of
our techniques and be able to protect themselves against them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Most people and organizations, even knowing everything the NSA can and does
do to monitor their communication, would still find it difficult and uneconomic
to protect themselves against NSA monitoring. These days, even after serious
software security bugs are found, fixed, and discussed publicly, many
computers remain unpatched and vulnerable to the bugs years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Ok, so maybe your average terrorist won&amp;rsquo;t be able to hide from the NSA, but
what about China, Russia, industrial spies, and other sophisticated
adversaries?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: This will make it harder to succeed against sophisticated adversaries. Let&amp;rsquo;s
say, for the sake of argument, that the NSA will be 75% less effective against
them. We&amp;rsquo;ll have the choice to increase the NSA&amp;rsquo;s budget to compensate or
accept a reduced capability. That said, I suspect that the NSA would eventually
get better at operating within the new constraints and the performance gap
would lessen over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: I have a better idea, why not make them 75% more effective by leaving them
alone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Our greatest innovation and asset is the liberty our founders and soldiers
fought and died to protect. The NSA&amp;rsquo;s mission is to help protect us through
signals intelligence, not only our physical persons but also our liberty&amp;ndash;some
would say liberty comes first. Just as we increase the cost of criminal justice
by treating the accused as innocent until proven guilty and enforcing rules of
evidence, our liberty will be better protected by limiting our government&amp;rsquo;s
ability to abuse secrecy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Won&amp;rsquo;t China, etc. use the NSA techniques against us, our government and our
companies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Yes. Authoritarian and criminal organizations operate with some advantages
because they are less constrained by laws, cultures, and institutions designed
to protect their citizens&amp;rsquo; freedom. Others will use the NSAs tools in
industrial and state espionage. But, operating under these new constraints, I
suspect the NSA will become a big source and advocate of fixes for security
bugs, and many security-minded software makers will take advantage of the NSA&amp;rsquo;s
knowledge to fix their bugs and improve security, limiting the utility of the
NSA&amp;rsquo;s 2-year-old exploits. Those software makers and users that aren&amp;rsquo;t
security-minded won&amp;rsquo;t patch their bugs, but they already don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Why not just reveal the techniques used and not the data? Why not allow
redactions to protect our spies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: The more complicated we make the maintenance and enforcement of the policy,
the less likely it is to work. Complexity can easily become an excuse to drag
our feet and it makes it too easy to hide information and avoid compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Won&amp;rsquo;t this put our sources in (mortal) danger?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: This will make it harder to use sources, human or technical, for any length
of time against a sophisticated adversary. When we do use human sources, we&amp;rsquo;ll
have to move them out of harm&amp;rsquo;s way before their identity becomes public, which
will be harder on them and us. I expect we&amp;rsquo;ll want to purge most of the
existing evidence when this policy is first rolled out, so as to start with
sources after we&amp;rsquo;re properly prepared to explain and manage the new risks we&amp;rsquo;re
taking on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Why 2 years of secrecy? Why not longer? Why not shorter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: 2 years is long enough to take some advantage of the secrets we gather while
being short enough for a motivated president to enforce the transparency policy
and for them to be held to account for it by the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Sounds expensive. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t the NSA have a massive amount of data?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Yes and yes. I imagine Google or another interested contractor would be able
to figure out how to host the public data if the NSA didn&amp;rsquo;t want to do so
itself, at a reasonable price given the volume of data to be published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: You are not qualified to talk about this, you don&amp;rsquo;t know what the NSA and
the President knows, if you did you might change your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: As a citizen its my right and duty to engage with the difficult topics that
impact our democracy. With the information available to me, its clear that we
are putting our democracy in great danger by concentrating more and more power,
with less and less meaningful oversight, with fewer and fewer people in our
government. Blind trust in our leaders is not how democracy works, its how
authoritarian regimes work. The main idea of this policy is to make meaningful
oversight possible while preserving as much of intelligence capability as
possible as the 2nd priority rather than the 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: What about objections X, Y, and Z that you didn&amp;rsquo;t talk about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about them. I have no doubt this idea can be improved upon. The
fundamental question I&amp;rsquo;m posing is this: if you treat liberty as the #1
priority and intelligence capability as #2, what kind of NSA do you get? I
suspect &amp;lsquo;a great one&amp;rsquo; that, instead of undermining our values, becomes a poster
child for them while also accomplishing their important intelligence gathering
mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Won&amp;rsquo;t the NSA say they are complying with this policy and then, give a wink
to the President, and then, you know, not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: They could. The President and Congress need to be onboard. Not just onboard
for optics while they secretly do something else, but onboard onboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: The President and Congress don&amp;rsquo;t agree with you. They like their secrets.
They believe they can be trusted with them and the power it gives them. They
won&amp;rsquo;t get onboard. Now what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: The People need to talk about this and decide its what they want. When we
are united, we get our way, we live in a democracy after all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Customer Support Has Gone Downhill</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/amazon-customer-support-has-gone-downhill.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/amazon-customer-support-has-gone-downhill.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon used to have outstanding customer support. But it seems their focus is elsewhere these days. In the past I&amp;rsquo;d contact them via phone or email and someone would try to understand my issue and resolve it in my favor. But yesterday I had a phone+email exchange about a very late order that they struggled to understand and chose not to fix&amp;ndash;it seemed it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fit for their playbook, so they couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out what to do except to tell me I&amp;rsquo;m out of luck. The fix would have been easy for an empowered, quality CS rep to handle, but that&amp;rsquo;s not what I got.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a customer since 1999 and I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of money (millions) with the for my family and my companies. But I guess folks like me aren&amp;rsquo;t worth the trouble anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh well, nothing lasts forever. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been super happy with their poor management of counterfeit merchandise, review quality, higher pricing&amp;hellip;this is a good excuse to get off my butt and take a good look at the alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outing Bigots</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/outing-bigots.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/outing-bigots.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems the bigots have come out of the woodwork recently, emboldened by Trump&amp;rsquo;s election. If someone behaves that way around me I&amp;rsquo;m recording a video and posting it online, for all to see. I&amp;rsquo;ll ask for their name and add it to the video&amp;rsquo;s description so its nice and easy for search engines to index.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a Consum-ee, Not a Consum-er</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/im-a-consum-ee-not-a-consum-er.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 20:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/im-a-consum-ee-not-a-consum-er.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a healthy relationship with consumer products. Or consumer content. I spent a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time on World of Warcraft back in the day. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time fiddling with apps on my iPhone. A lot. Candy Crush&amp;hellip;nuf said. TV shows keep getting better and better. There&amp;rsquo;s so much amazing content, I could just stare at these fonts of great entertainment all day long, wasting away, if I was so inclined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed all my stuff isn&amp;rsquo;t my stuff anymore&amp;ndash;Apple decides which software I can run on my phone, Amazon decides which books to delete from my collection, most computers I can buy from retailers come with malware preloaded. Intel and AMD put backdoors on all their chips, which means pretty much any computer I get has a backdoor. Almost all the email I sent to friends and family goes through Google whether I host my own email server or not. And they dip into my email to sell me stuff, sell my friends stuff, and comply with secret government requests to do whatever &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; like with my emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online ad networks use my IP and browser to fingerprint me and follow me around wherever I go, so they sell my data to whomever wants it and chase me to all corners of the web with their ads. Criminals are constantly scanning my computers for holes they can exploit in order to recruit my laptop into their zombie DDoS armies or so they can steal my credit card info and maybe charge $10 to me without my noticing before they get away with the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve turned off my phone&amp;rsquo;s ringer (whitelisting certain people) because over half the calls I get are someone trying to take up a few minutes of my time for their purpose. I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten pretty fast at deleting email spam. 95% of the snail mail I get goes directly into recycling, but it still takes a couple seconds each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not so much a consum-er as a consum-ee. &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; am what is being consumed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vote With Your Attention</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/vote-with-your-attention.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/vote-with-your-attention.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ggr_com.s3.amazonaws.com/images/unsupported.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until a few years ago, my software choices were largely accidents of circumstance and convenience. I started using CP/M, then an Atari 800, then DOS on a 386, then Windows, then OSX, then Debian, then Arch, then OpenBSD. Somewhere in the middle there was a mobile track, starting with dumb phones, then Palm, then Windows Mobile, then iOS, then Android, then Replicant. On the web it went NCSA Mosaic, Firefox, IE, Safari, Chrome, Firefox, vimb. Then there are editors, windows managers, email clients&amp;hellip;I used whatever was convenient and had the coolest features. I loved trying out new tech and being on the cutting edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But every time I used a piece of software I became accustomed to it and it started to define my new normal&amp;hellip;everything else became (relatively) harder to use and harder to try. I started to see the world through my software&amp;rsquo;s eyes. And the world started to see me through my software too&amp;ndash;for example, my choice of web browser logged a vote on every site I visited: IE matters! Windows matters! The websites I visited kept track of the software I used and their creators made decisions about what web browsers to test on based on the browsers they saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there. I file (detailed) tickets when the software I use breaks. And a lot of time the maintainers are happy to get the bug report and they fix the issue. Other times I&amp;rsquo;ll fix the bug myself and submit a patch. And thus, the software I use gets better and better. And as it gets better and better, more people use it and compound this effect. I spend money on software and donate to software too. Guesss what? I don&amp;rsquo;t donate to software I don&amp;rsquo;t use, so my choice of ecosystem really defines where my money goes and which developers get paid and what for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I post to forums asking for help when I&amp;rsquo;m lost. I answer others&amp;rsquo; questions. I blog about neat things I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to do with my software, or how to work around some obscure issue&amp;ndash;now when someone searches for an answer about the software I&amp;rsquo;m interested in, they might find it and stay interested or become more interested in that same software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the time and money in software flows into what we use and where we put our attention. Whether its proprietary or free (as in freedom), whether it has DRM or not, whether its keyboard based or touch based, whether its security focused or features focused&amp;hellip;every time we use some software we&amp;rsquo;re voting for the ecosystem and ideas it embodies. We&amp;rsquo;re causing more resources to flow to those ideas and making them more likely to attract more people and more resources until their ideas come to dominate our thinking&amp;ndash;they become the default, convenient (Chrome vs Firefox) and cheap (Intel vs Power8) choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m going to be more intentional about where I put my attention and my vote. Its not just about what&amp;rsquo;s convenient today, its also about what choices I want available to me down the road.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSS vs Proprietary Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/foss-vs-proprietary-cheatsheet.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/foss-vs-proprietary-cheatsheet.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOSS just gets better and better, feature-wise and ethics-wise&amp;hellip;and it seems
Proprietary keeps getting better feature-wise, but worse ethics-wise. Its got
me asking myself why I&amp;rsquo;m not fullstack FOSS, and&amp;hellip;its the money. I rather like
my Silicon Valley, electric car driving, Napa valley wine drinking, private
school for the kids, lifestyle. I don&amp;rsquo;t see a good way to keep my life and make
FOSS software fulltime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s where I think we stand today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;foss&#34;&gt;FOSS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;largest potential audience, i.e. audience for free beer &amp;gt; $1 beer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;high transparency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;high developer and end user control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;low value capture by the authors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;low average ease of use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lags many years behind proprietary on feature set, i.e. drivers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;proprietary&#34;&gt;Proprietary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;largest existing audience, i.e. Windows, iOS, Playstation &amp;gt; Linux,
Replicant, MAME&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;high value capture by the authors, i.e. its easier to make a living, its
easier to get rich&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;high rate of new, user facing features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;high average ease of use, i.e. most software that&amp;rsquo;s easy enough for grandpa
is proprietary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vendor lockin, i.e. DRM aka a movie bought on iTunes cannot be played on
Android, the video game publisher goes out of business and you cannot play
the game you bought anymore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;low transparency&amp;ndash;can and often is used to hide bad behaviour, i.e. invasive
tracking, selling your data to others, installing ad or malware on your
machine, hiding poor security practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;low developer and end user countrol&amp;ndash;you get what they give you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;high risk of unhealthy and/or &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@tristanharris/how-technology-hijacks-peoples-minds-from-a-magician-and-google-s-design-ethicist-56d62ef5edf3#.gnq5g61gg&#34;&gt;manipulative&lt;/a&gt; treatment of users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://drilix.com/en/blog/how-free-software-and-open-source-developers-earn-money-fo-economy&#34;&gt;How do Free Software and Open Source developers earn money? (the FO$$ economy)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/3qtc4l/ask_rlinux_how_do_a_company_make_profit_from_foss/&#34;&gt;Ask /r/Linux, How do a company make profit from FOSS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.honeytechblog.com/what-is-the-economics-behind-foss/&#34;&gt;What is the economics behind FOSS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoworld.com/article/2612393/open-source-software/greed-is-good--9-open-source-secrets-to-making-money.html&#34;&gt;Greed is good: 9 open source secrets to making money&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxinsider.com/story/74660.html&#34;&gt;Is It Wrong to Make a Profit From FOSS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why OpenBSD Is Important To Me</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/why-openbsd-is-important-to-me.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/why-openbsd-is-important-to-me.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;privacy-matters&#34;&gt;Privacy Matters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The freedom to speak in private is essential to democracy. The less private
your conversations, the more careful you are about what you say. And being
careful leads to less candor, less criticism, and less innovation. Thought and
private speech are the breeding ground for new, sometimes controversial ideas.
They are how we prototype, think new ideas through, refine them, and get them
ready for wider distribution and discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US government has chosen to attack everyone&amp;rsquo;s privacy, US citizen and world
citizen alike, in the name of attacking the privacy of terrorists. The
government view is that privacy is an impediment to keeping us safe from
physical harm. Tragically, they&amp;rsquo;ve thrown the baby out with the bathwater&amp;ndash;we
want to be safe from physical harm so that we can engage with society as free
citizens with the maximum possible liberty&amp;hellip;putting us in a digital prison,
where all of our communication is subject to the whim of government review is
the opposite of keeping us safe, its a devastating attack on our freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trust-matters&#34;&gt;Trust Matters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time after time when the people of the United States have openly debated
encryption and privacy, the people have made it clear that we do not want to
trade away our privacy in exchange for the possibility of making it easier
for the govenment to secure our physical safety. Instead of respecting our
wishes, or reopening the debate to see if we would change our minds in light of
9/11 or other physical attacks, the US govenment chose to spy on us in secret
and then lie about it. They took advantage of our trust in them, and that&amp;rsquo;s
the second tragedy of their actions&amp;ndash;this loss of trust will have negative, far
reaching consequences for decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-openbsd-i-trust&#34;&gt;In OpenBSD I Trust&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenBSD is an operating system that prioritizes security, encryption, and free
(as in free and open) software. Its built in the open&amp;ndash;anyone can see the code
and discussions around it. That&amp;rsquo;s no accident&amp;ndash;the earliest contributors
recognized that transparency and public discussion are essential to effective
security. If you follow the project and the email lists for any length of time,
it becomes clear that the core contributors are passionate about security and
quality. These are volunteers that spend their limited, precious spare time
on building a great operating system that they give away for free because they
want to see secure, high quality software thrive in the world. They&amp;rsquo;ve been
doing it for 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What they&amp;rsquo;ve made works really well. While its not as easy for a consumer to
use as Windows or OS X, to someone more technically inclined, its
straightforward to use as a server or as a desktop for many use cases. And the
big feature: it starts our very secure and if you&amp;rsquo;re careful you can keep it
that way as you customize it to suit your purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-fight-worth-fighting&#34;&gt;A Fight Worth Fighting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing is perfect, of course. I imagine the NSA has a bag full of OpenBSD
exploits, and truth be told, for most of us security newbs its easy to
misconfigure our software and expose our data on accident. But OpenBSD has
gifted to the world a fighting chance&amp;ndash;a foundation as solid as any available
for building a private digital life. Its for all these reasons that I use
OpenBSD for many of my servers at home, run OpenBSD on my main laptop, donate
to OpenBSD, buy CDs, patch 3rd party software so its compatible with OpenBSD,
and have looked for other ways to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have insecure, anti-secure, and anti-privacy software and hardware in
my life&amp;ndash;I have an iPhone, I use Linux and Windows at home, and Linux and OS X
at work. Plenty of hardware in my life has backdoors (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you
&lt;a href=&#34;https://libreboot.org/faq/#intel&#34;&gt;Intel&lt;/a&gt;). But I&amp;rsquo;m slowly replacing the bad stuff with the good stuff, as I&amp;rsquo;m
able to find OpenBSD (and open hardware) based solutions for my remaining use
cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its work, to be sure. It would be easier to just use OS X and Windows for a lot
of stuff I do. It would be easier to use iCloud and Google Drive and Dropbox
for everything. It would be easier to just trust everyone in all the
corporations of the world and all the governments of the world. Or short of
that, it would be easier to bury my head in the sand and optimize exclusively
for convenience. It would be easier not to contribute&amp;ndash;to just leech off others&#39;
works and let them leech off my me and my data. But that&amp;rsquo;s not the path to
better world or to a free one. Our freedom requires fighting, struggling,
working. OpenBSD is on our side, and its volunteers are fighting for us. We
should fight too. Our freedom is worth fighting for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=11659926&#34;&gt;Discussion&lt;/a&gt; on Hacker News.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Is Rich</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/who-is-rich.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/who-is-rich.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ggr_com.s3.amazonaws.com/images/scrooge-mcduck-swimming-in-money.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering Hilary Clinton&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://brokehillary.com/&#34;&gt;dead brokeness&lt;/a&gt;, what she meant, and
what it means to be rich. Or rather, what a (more) useful definition might
be&amp;ndash;one that could help predict (political) views and behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scotts-definition-of-rich&#34;&gt;Scott&amp;rsquo;s definition of &amp;lsquo;rich&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;top 1% of income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;owns job and/or almost no chance of being fired and/or the loss of income
from being fired would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have a material impact on their lifestyle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rich and/or powerful own the system, they are &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Root_user&#34;&gt;root&lt;/a&gt;, and for them the
system (the government, the law, the dominant corporations) is extremely
valuable and something to be preserved and exploited for their benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of us are &lt;a href=&#34;http://tron.wikia.com/wiki/User&#34;&gt;users and programs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;we are part of the system, but we
don&amp;rsquo;t own it. Its usually helpful to us, but it can also turn against us, and
our ability to mitigate an attack (by root) is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Gates is rich and powerful. Marc Andreessen is rich. Hilary is powerful,
but not rich&amp;ndash;she needs the income from her work to preserve her lifestyle.
Barack Obama is powerful, but not rich (before he became President he was
neither). Equipped with this definition I see some interesting patterns about
views on the NSA, Snowden, unlimited copyright, and a lot of other policies that
interest me and which I find myself on the other side from those that are allied
with or are themselves rich or powerful. Its a better predictor than political
party in a lot of cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opting Out</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/opting-out.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/opting-out.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ggr_com.s3.amazonaws.com/images/optout.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;26&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A government with easy access to all the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PRISM_(surveillance_program)&#34;&gt;public and private information&lt;/a&gt; of its people, that collects this information &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.commondreams.org/view/2013/09/11-11&#34;&gt;against their wishes&lt;/a&gt;, that makes them more &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technologyreview.com/news/519336/bruce-schneier-nsa-spying-is-making-us-less-safe/&#34;&gt;vulnerable to harm&lt;/a&gt; in order to maintain their access, and then &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2013/08/15/lies-damned-lies-and-the-nsa/&#34;&gt;lies&lt;/a&gt; in order to cover up their actions is fundamentally incompatible with American democracy. The freedom to live, speak, and think in private, without &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nbcnews.com/technology/nsa-dragnet-wider-previously-suspected-says-nyt-6C10876005&#34;&gt;worrying&lt;/a&gt; how a government agent might view our thoughts or try to use them against us, &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; liberty. I feel obligated to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.draxe.com/i-opt-out-what-you-must-know-about-new-airport-backscatter-scanners/&#34;&gt;opt out&lt;/a&gt; and find other ways to protest and inhibit these &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economonitor.com/dolanecon/2013/08/05/the-fourth-amendment-and-the-economic-spillover-from-nsa-surveillance-to-e-commerce/&#34;&gt;destructive&lt;/a&gt; programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started looking for alternatives to NSA compromised services and software and I&amp;rsquo;m going to slowly swap them out. I used to assume that big, brand name proprietary software was more secure, now I wonder what &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theforbiddenknowledge.com/hardtruth/nsa_backdoor_windows.htm&#34;&gt;backdoors&lt;/a&gt; and vulnerabilities, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/security/msrc/collaboration/mapp.aspx&#34;&gt;known to some&lt;/a&gt; who are trustworthy and some who are not, they contain. At least with open source software users have a fighting chance to find and address vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switched from Google to self hosted. I don&amp;rsquo;t want my personal email caught up in the NSA dragnet or any &lt;a href=&#34;http://yro.slashdot.org/story/11/04/07/232224/Obama-Administration-Wants-Your-Old-Email&#34;&gt;other dragnet&lt;/a&gt;. I realize that if the NSA wants to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pwn&#34;&gt;pwn&lt;/a&gt; me they will, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make it an any easier that I have to. I&amp;rsquo;m still using Google Apps at work because Google Apps is awesome and I&amp;rsquo;m less offended by the g-men snooping in that context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Search&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switched from Google to &lt;a href=&#34;http://duckduckgo.com/&#34;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;. They &lt;a href=&#34;http://donttrack.us/&#34;&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t store&lt;/a&gt; personal info. Their search isn&amp;rsquo;t as good as Google&amp;rsquo;s but I&amp;rsquo;ll live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lockitron.com/&#34;&gt;Lockitron&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cancelled my order. If you want to pick my lock you&amp;rsquo;re going to have to show up in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switched from Google Chrome to Chromium to Firefox. Installed Adblock Plus, BetterPrivacy, Flashblock, and NoScript addons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switched to &lt;a href=&#34;http://sonic.net/&#34;&gt;Sonic&lt;/a&gt; because they are the ISP available to me that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/who-has-your-back-2013&#34;&gt;fights the hardest&lt;/a&gt; for their users&amp;rsquo; rights. My old provider, Comcast, not so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switched from Apple Messages to Adium. Using OTR when I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Etc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donating monthly to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://supporters.eff.org/donate&#34;&gt;EFF&lt;/a&gt;. Wrote my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.house.gov/representatives/find/&#34;&gt;congresswoman&lt;/a&gt; asking her to vote for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jul/25/nsa-surveillance-amash-amendment-narrow-defeat&#34;&gt;bill restricting NSA phone-tracking&lt;/a&gt;. Signed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://petitions.whitehouse.gov/petition/pardon-edward-snowden/Dp03vGYD&#34;&gt;petition to pardon Snowden&lt;/a&gt;. Donated to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rally.org/lavabit&#34;&gt;Lavabit defense fund&lt;/a&gt;. Installed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.obdev.at/products/littlesnitch/index.html&#34;&gt;Little Snitch&lt;/a&gt; to reduce monitoring from my laptop, though I still need to take more time to lock thing down properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Todo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a Mac+OSX and iPhone user, look into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/os/&#34;&gt;open alternatives&lt;/a&gt;. I occasionally use Facebook, more and more these days for authentication across web and mobile apps, is there a way to share online without permitting a big company or a government agency the same access as my family? Try out more &lt;a href=&#34;https://prism-break.org/&#34;&gt;Prism-Break&lt;/a&gt; ideas. Ponder how to use encryption on top of cloud services so I can have my cake and eat it too. Need to buy a bumper sticker that says: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.osnews.com/story/25469/Richard_Stallman_Was_Right_All_Along&#34;&gt;Stallman Was Right&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright This</title>
      <link>https://ggr.com/copyright-this.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 1997 13:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ggr.com/copyright-this.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to copyright my DNA (TM). I mentioned this to my parents, and they
produced a copy of the End User License Agreement (EULA) that I signed for my
DNA when I was just a few seconds old, and complained of numerous violations
(they still claim to be the original authors, with all visible evidence to the
contrary). But, reading legal newsgroups has kept me abreast of the latest, and
I knew that a contract with a minor is non-binding. Besides, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even
look like my digital signature. Nevertheless, they sued me for the copyrights
my DNA and for the emotional trauma caused by my alleged abuse of their DNA
during my alleged childhood, in what appeared to be a clear alleged violation
of our alleged agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My legal expertise proved sound, and I was able to convince my parents to
settle out of court signing over the rights to my DNA (with a statement which
guarantees their right to make such an assignment) in return for the movie
rights to our story and a small royalty for the first 5 years on published and
derivative works based upon my DNA. All of our lawyers are living quite well on
an island they bought in the MS Ocean (if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard, Microsoft recently
acquired stock in the Pacific ocean in exchange for their pledge to continue to
write software which supports the shipping industry).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out all the details of what to do with my DNA in the
immediate future&amp;hellip;I may be willing to grant limited non-exclusive license for
purposes of cloning genetic research, but I have not been approached yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still working the details of porting my DNA to other media (maybe MP3 for
the Patrick Steward audio-book version) so that I can sue all the random
researchers out there who might upload and download my DNA all over the
internet for who knows what evil purposes, but I have high hopes that DNA
sequencers will become more affordable, reliable, and speedy within the next
few gigaseconds. My agent (a.k.a. WebSnake) has been hard at work locating
perspective publishers, and I think I have a few who are interested in a work
that consists entirely of billions of four letter words. A couple of the
publishers I&amp;rsquo;ve talked to want to make a &amp;lsquo;multi-player&amp;rsquo; version for play on the
internet, but I&amp;rsquo;m still skeptical about how my DNA will translate into a game.
However, they assure me that the technology is there (DVD may yet become a
standard, and they would be able to fit a lot of compressed text!), and that
the whole concept alone is so impressive that game play is not a significant
concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already sent PGP signed notices to my sibling that they are in violation
of my copyright because they are using a work which is almost identical.
Unfortunately, my younger brother proceeded to post my email address to all the
newsletters on the internet, so I can no longer correspond via e-mail. My
sister still maintains that I am from another planet, and therefore may not
claim protection under &amp;rsquo;local&amp;rsquo; copyright laws, but she has not produced any
evidence other than my weird articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve asked my lawyers about what to expect if I should decide to co-author a
sequel (have a kid), and they assure me that it would be less complicated if I
just wrote it myself (have a clone kid). They are still working out the
implications of revoking a descendant&amp;rsquo;s license to use my DNA, which is
currently legal only before they are published (they are born). I recall my
parents trying to revoke my license early in my childhood, but by then I was
already big enough to have My First Lawyer*. He succeeded in securing a
injunction on the grounds that the severe medical consequences of removing of
part or all of my DNA, especially considering the short period of time in which
I would have needed to find a suitable replacement. Bob (my lawyer), soon went
on to indisputably prove that publications have innate, inalienable rights and
proceeded to liberate all the CDs from the local Tower Records store. Before he
could do too much damage, congress passed a law making it illegal to liberate
CDs without FDA approval. Bob plead insanity to charges of contempt of most
people, and is now serving 17 years in the new Hawaiian &amp;lsquo;virtual prison&amp;rsquo;
complex for acting insane without a license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I had to find a new lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
