<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Politics on game, game. repeat.</title><link>https://ggr.com/tags/politics.html</link><description>Recent content in Politics on game, game. repeat.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 10:54:33 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Couple Of My Duties As a Citizen of a Democracy</title><link>https://ggr.com/a-couple-of-my-duties-as-a-citizen-of-a-democracy.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 10:54:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/a-couple-of-my-duties-as-a-citizen-of-a-democracy.html</guid><description>Speak Up I must speak up in public forums like LinkedIN, Twitter, and Christmas dinner. I’ve been taught that talking politics is impolite. But leaving good ideas unsaid and undefended, and letting bad ideas dominate the conversation and lead to bad decisions is even more impolite.
Change My Mind I must listen, learn, and change my mind, which is way harder than defending my beliefs and standing my ground. It requires humility to admit I was wrong and courage to let others see my mistakes.</description></item><item><title>Open (Source) the NSA</title><link>https://ggr.com/open-source-the-nsa.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 17:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/open-source-the-nsa.html</guid><description>Democracy and government secrets are at odds with each other. Keeping secrets and accessing the secrets of others is a way to gain power. And while we want our government to gain power over people that seek to harm us, we do not want them to have power over the innocent citizen they answer to.
The solution is transparency. The NSA must make a monthly copy of all the data and software from their systems and make it available to the public 2 years later.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Customer Support Has Gone Downhill</title><link>https://ggr.com/amazon-customer-support-has-gone-downhill.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/amazon-customer-support-has-gone-downhill.html</guid><description>Amazon used to have outstanding customer support. But it seems their focus is elsewhere these days. In the past I&amp;rsquo;d contact them via phone or email and someone would try to understand my issue and resolve it in my favor. But yesterday I had a phone+email exchange about a very late order that they struggled to understand and chose not to fix&amp;ndash;it seemed it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fit for their playbook, so they couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out what to do except to tell me I&amp;rsquo;m out of luck.</description></item><item><title>Outing Bigots</title><link>https://ggr.com/outing-bigots.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/outing-bigots.html</guid><description>It seems the bigots have come out of the woodwork recently, emboldened by Trump&amp;rsquo;s election. If someone behaves that way around me I&amp;rsquo;m recording a video and posting it online, for all to see. I&amp;rsquo;ll ask for their name and add it to the video&amp;rsquo;s description so its nice and easy for search engines to index.</description></item><item><title>I'm a Consum-ee, Not a Consum-er</title><link>https://ggr.com/im-a-consum-ee-not-a-consum-er.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 20:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/im-a-consum-ee-not-a-consum-er.html</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t have a healthy relationship with consumer products. Or consumer content. I spent a lot of time on World of Warcraft back in the day. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time fiddling with apps on my iPhone. A lot. Candy Crush&amp;hellip;nuf said. TV shows keep getting better and better. There&amp;rsquo;s so much amazing content, I could just stare at these fonts of great entertainment all day long, wasting away, if I was so inclined.</description></item><item><title>Vote With Your Attention</title><link>https://ggr.com/vote-with-your-attention.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/vote-with-your-attention.html</guid><description>Up until a few years ago, my software choices were largely accidents of circumstance and convenience. I started using CP/M, then an Atari 800, then DOS on a 386, then Windows, then OSX, then Debian, then Arch, then OpenBSD. Somewhere in the middle there was a mobile track, starting with dumb phones, then Palm, then Windows Mobile, then iOS, then Android, then Replicant. On the web it went NCSA Mosaic, Firefox, IE, Safari, Chrome, Firefox, vimb.</description></item><item><title>FOSS vs Proprietary Cheatsheet</title><link>https://ggr.com/foss-vs-proprietary-cheatsheet.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/foss-vs-proprietary-cheatsheet.html</guid><description>FOSS just gets better and better, feature-wise and ethics-wise&amp;hellip;and it seems Proprietary keeps getting better feature-wise, but worse ethics-wise. Its got me asking myself why I&amp;rsquo;m not fullstack FOSS, and&amp;hellip;its the money. I rather like my Silicon Valley, electric car driving, Napa valley wine drinking, private school for the kids, lifestyle. I don&amp;rsquo;t see a good way to keep my life and make FOSS software fulltime.
Here&amp;rsquo;s where I think we stand today:</description></item><item><title>Why OpenBSD Is Important To Me</title><link>https://ggr.com/why-openbsd-is-important-to-me.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/why-openbsd-is-important-to-me.html</guid><description>Privacy Matters The freedom to speak in private is essential to democracy. The less private your conversations, the more careful you are about what you say. And being careful leads to less candor, less criticism, and less innovation. Thought and private speech are the breeding ground for new, sometimes controversial ideas. They are how we prototype, think new ideas through, refine them, and get them ready for wider distribution and discussion.</description></item><item><title>Who Is Rich</title><link>https://ggr.com/who-is-rich.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/who-is-rich.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering Hilary Clinton&amp;rsquo;s dead brokeness, what she meant, and what it means to be rich. Or rather, what a (more) useful definition might be&amp;ndash;one that could help predict (political) views and behaviors.
Scott&amp;rsquo;s definition of &amp;lsquo;rich&amp;rsquo; top 1% of income owns job and/or almost no chance of being fired and/or the loss of income from being fired would not have a material impact on their lifestyle The rich and/or powerful own the system, they are root, and for them the system (the government, the law, the dominant corporations) is extremely valuable and something to be preserved and exploited for their benefit.</description></item><item><title>Opting Out</title><link>https://ggr.com/opting-out.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/opting-out.html</guid><description>A government with easy access to all the public and private information of its people, that collects this information against their wishes, that makes them more vulnerable to harm in order to maintain their access, and then lies in order to cover up their actions is fundamentally incompatible with American democracy. The freedom to live, speak, and think in private, without worrying how a government agent might view our thoughts or try to use them against us, is liberty.</description></item><item><title>Copyright This</title><link>https://ggr.com/copyright-this.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 1997 13:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/copyright-this.html</guid><description>I decided to copyright my DNA (TM). I mentioned this to my parents, and they produced a copy of the End User License Agreement (EULA) that I signed for my DNA when I was just a few seconds old, and complained of numerous violations (they still claim to be the original authors, with all visible evidence to the contrary). But, reading legal newsgroups has kept me abreast of the latest, and I knew that a contract with a minor is non-binding.</description></item></channel></rss>