<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>recipe on game, game. repeat.</title><link>https://ggr.com/tags/recipe.html</link><description>Recent content in recipe on game, game. repeat.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 09:51:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/tags/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Coconut Cream Pie</title><link>https://ggr.com/coconut-cream-pie.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 09:51:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/coconut-cream-pie.html</guid><description>Makes 8 servings.
Crust 10 whole graham crackers, broken into 1-inch pieces 6 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted and cooled 3 tablespoons sugar Adjust over rack to middle position and heat over to 325 F. Process graham cracker pieces in food processor to fine, even crumbs, about 30 seconds. Sprinkle melted butter and sugar over crumbs and pulse to incorporate, about 5 pulses. Sprinkle mixture into 9-inch pie plate. Using a large spoon, press crumbs into even layer on bottom and sides of pie plate.</description></item><item><title>Pecan Pie</title><link>https://ggr.com/pecan-pie.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 09:21:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/pecan-pie.html</guid><description>Makes 8 servings.
Butter Crust 1 tablespoon sour cream or 2 teaspoons apple cider vinegar 3 tablespoons ice water 1.25 cups pastry flour 1.5 teaspoons sugar 0.5 teaspoons salt 8 tablespoons unsalted butter, frozen, cut into 0.25 inch cubes Mix sour cream and ice water in a bowl until combined. Process flour, sugar, and salt in a food processor until combined, about 5 seconds. Add butter and pulse mixture until butter is the size of larges peas, about 10 pulses.</description></item><item><title>Arugula Salad</title><link>https://ggr.com/arugula-salad.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 22:22:21 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/arugula-salad.html</guid><description>Makes 2 servings.
5 ounces baby arugula 1 cup cherry tomotoes 1 ripe avocado 1 tablespoon oil free miso ginger dressing Add arugula to a large salad bowl. Remove pit from avocado and scoop a tablespoon at a time into bowl. Cut tomotoes in half and add to bowl. Drizzle dressing over salad. Toss the salad. Serve immediately.</description></item><item><title>Buckwheat Cereal</title><link>https://ggr.com/buckwheat-cereal.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 22:21:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/buckwheat-cereal.html</guid><description>Makes 1 serving.
0.25 cups roasted buckwheat aka kasha 1.5 cups water or milk 0.25 cups chia seed 0.25 cups flaxseed, ground 0.5 cups almonds, roasted and unsalted 1 Fuji apple, chopped Pour buckwheat into a large, microwave safe bowl. Add water. Microwave for 5 minutes. Remove from microwave and let buckwheat rest for 5 minutes. Stir in chia seed and flaxseed. Add apple and almonds on top. Serve.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Chip Ice Cream</title><link>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-ice-cream.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:46:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-ice-cream.html</guid><description>Makes about 2 quarts. Substitute 4 teaspoons vanilla extract for the vanilla beans by adding the vanilla extract after the mixture cools, before putting it in the refridgerator.
2 vanilla beans 3.5 cups heavy cream 2.5 cups whole milk 0.66 cups sugar 0.66 cups light corn syrup 0.5 teaspoons salt 12 large egg yolks 0.33 cups semisweet chocolate 1 teaspoon vegetable oil Cut vanilla beans in half lengthwise. Scrape out seeds.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title><link>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-cookies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-cookies.html</guid><description>Makes about 15 cookies.
3 cups pastry flour 0.5 teaspoon baking soda 0.5 teaspoon baking powder 1 teaspoon salt 2 sticks (8 ounces or 228 grams) unsalted butter, at room temperature 0.5 cups granulated sugar 1.5 cups packed brown sugar 1 teaspoon vanilla 2 large eggs or egg whites 1.5 cups semisweet chocolate chips In a medium bowl combine the flour, baking soda, baking powder and salt.
In the bowl of an electric mixer beat the butter, sugar, until creamy, about 2 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Broccoli Soup</title><link>https://ggr.com/broccoli-soup.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 08:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/broccoli-soup.html</guid><description>1 pound broccoli 0.5 cups avocado or grapeseed oil 0.5 cups water 1 teaspoon salt Boil broccoli in water for 10 minutes. Drain water. Transfer broccoli to blender. Add oil, water, and salt. Blend until smooth. Add more salt to taste. Add more water if you like it thinner and more soup-like. Serve hot or cold.
Don&amp;rsquo;t like broccoli? Me neither. But hold on to your soup bowls, this is a way to eat it that tastes pretty good.</description></item><item><title>Brussels Sprouts</title><link>https://ggr.com/brussels-sprouts.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/brussels-sprouts.html</guid><description>Makes any number of servings.
Brussels sprouts avocado or grapeseed oil salt Cut sprouts in half lengthwise, so that the stem is cut in half. Pour a generous layer of oil in a pan. Cover pan with sprout halves, flat side down. Cover pan with lid. Turn on heat to medium. Cook on medium for 5 minutes or until brown. Line a bowl with a paper towel. Turn off stove and use a slotted spoon to move the sprouts into bowl.</description></item><item><title>Mashed Potatoes</title><link>https://ggr.com/mashed-potatoes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/mashed-potatoes.html</guid><description>Makes about 12 servings.
5 pounds golden potatoes 1 package Philadelphia Cream Cheese 1 pint sour cream 0.5 cups milk 0.5 stick unsalted butter 3 medium size cloves of garlic 2 teaspoons salt 3 teaspoons white pepper optional: horseradish sauce Peel potatoes and add to a large pot. Fill pot with enough water to cover potatoes. Boil for 40 minutes then drain water. Mash potatoes with a potato ricer. Add cream cheese, milk, sour cream, butter, salt, and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Barley Soup</title><link>https://ggr.com/barley-soup.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 23:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/barley-soup.html</guid><description>Makes about 8 servings.
3 leg-and-thighs of chicken 1.5 cups pearl barley 2 carrots 2 stalks of celery 0.5 white onion salt pepper Wash chicken. Put chicken into a large pot. Add water to pot until chicken is covered. Wash barley and add to pot. Grate onion and add to pot. Add 2 teaspoons salt.
Simmer for 1 hour. Cut carrots and celery into 0.25 inch thick pieces and add to soup.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti Sauce</title><link>https://ggr.com/spaghetti-sauce.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/spaghetti-sauce.html</guid><description>Makes 10 servings.
0.5 cups avocado or grapeseed oil 4 cloves garlic 1 large yellow onion 1.5 pounds lean ground beef or Impossible Burger 15 ounces tomato sauce 12 ounces tomato paste 1 bottle of red wine or 4 cups of Burgandy 1 tablespoon oregano 1 tablespoon thyme 1 tablespoon sage 1 tablespoon basil 2 bay leaves 2 teaspoons salt 1 tablespoon brown sugar 56 ounces (2 cans) Italian-style tomatoes in basil Add oil to a large pot.</description></item><item><title>Spanish Sweet Bread</title><link>https://ggr.com/spanish-sweet-bread.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/spanish-sweet-bread.html</guid><description>Bread Machine Variant Makes 1 loaf. This method is way easier than the original, which you can find right after this one.
0.75 cup whole milk 2 eggs, beaten 0.5 teaspoon lemon extract 0.5 teaspoon vanilla extract 500 grams bread flour / 3.5 cups 0.5 cups sugar 0.25 teaspoon salt 1 stick butter 1 package of yeast 0.75 cups golden raisins Put all the ingredients, up to and including the butter, into the bread maker, in the order they are listed.</description></item></channel></rss>