<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>recipe on game, game. repeat.</title><link>https://ggr.com/tags/recipe.html</link><description>Recent content in recipe on game, game. repeat.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:46:17 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/tags/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chocolate Chip Ice Cream</title><link>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-ice-cream.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:46:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-ice-cream.html</guid><description>Makes about 2 quarts. Substitute 4 teaspoons vanilla extract for the vanilla beans by adding the vanilla extract after the mixture cools, before putting it in the refridgerator.
2 vanilla beans 3.5 cups heavy cream 2.5 cups whole milk 0.66 cups sugar 0.66 cups light corn syrup 0.5 teaspoons salt 12 large egg yolks 0.33 cups bittersweet chocolate 1 teaspoon vegetable oil Cut vanilla beans in half lengthwise. Scrape out seeds.</description></item><item><title>Abuelita Corral's Spanish Sweet Bread</title><link>https://ggr.com/abuelita-corrals-spanish-sweet-bread.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/abuelita-corrals-spanish-sweet-bread.html</guid><description>Makes 2 loaves.
2 packages of yeast soaked in 1/2 water 1/2 cup canned milk 1/2 cup whole milk 4 eggs beaten 1 cup butter 1 teaspoon salt 1 cups sugar 6 cups flour 1 teaspoon lemon extract 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 1.5 cups raisins
Close all windows and doors, don&amp;rsquo;t want cold air Scald 1/2 cup canned cream milk and 1/2 cup of whole regular milk (medium heat until crust on top, about a minute, don&amp;rsquo;t let it boil) Melt 2 cubes of butter on low heat Sift 7 cups of flour (throw through strainer if no sifter) into a separate bowl Take 2 packages active dry yeast and dissolve in 1/2 cup luke warm water for 5 minutes w/a pinch of sugar In a bowl, beat 4 eggs Throw in 1/4 teaspoon salt Add 1 cup to 1/2 cups sugar and mix Add butter and stir quickly so the egg is not cooked&amp;hellip;let butter cool first if necessary and mix Add milk after its cool and mix Add 1 teaspoon vanilla extract and 1 teaspoon lemon extract and mix Add yeast and mix Add half the flout and mix Add fists of flour Let bread rest on floured board covered with cloth and wait 3 minutes Put flour everywhere, flour hands Kneed dough&amp;hellip;turn and take outside and folding into middle for 8 minutes Add cup of raisons and kneed until it&amp;rsquo;s even.</description></item></channel></rss>