<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>recipe on game, game. repeat.</title><link>https://ggr.com/tags/recipe.html</link><description>Recent content in recipe on game, game. repeat.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 22:22:21 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/tags/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arugula Salad</title><link>https://ggr.com/arugula-salad.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 22:22:21 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/arugula-salad.html</guid><description>Makes 2 servings.
5 ounces baby arugula 1 cup cherry tomotoes 1 ripe avocado 1 tablespoon oil free miso ginger dressing Add arugula to a large salad bowl. Remove pit from avocado and scoop a tablespoon at a time into bowl. Cut tomotoes in half and add to bowl. Drizzle dressing over salad. Toss the salad. Serve immediately.</description></item><item><title>Buckwheat Cereal</title><link>https://ggr.com/buckwheat-cereal.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 22:21:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/buckwheat-cereal.html</guid><description>Makes 1 serving.
0.25 cups roasted buckwheat aka kasha 1.5 cups water or milk 0.25 cups chia seed 0.25 cups flaxseed, ground 0.5 cups almonds, roasted and unsalted 1 Fuji apple, chopped Pour buckwheat into a large, microwave safe bowl. Add water. Microwave for 5 minutes. Remove from microwave and let buckwheat rest for 5 minutes. Stir in chia seed and flaxseed. Add apple and almonds on top. Serve.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Chip Ice Cream</title><link>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-ice-cream.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:46:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-ice-cream.html</guid><description>Makes about 2 quarts. Substitute 4 teaspoons vanilla extract for the vanilla beans by adding the vanilla extract after the mixture cools, before putting it in the refridgerator.
2 vanilla beans 3.5 cups heavy cream 2.5 cups whole milk 0.66 cups sugar 0.66 cups light corn syrup 0.5 teaspoons salt 12 large egg yolks 0.33 cups semisweet chocolate 1 teaspoon vegetable oil Cut vanilla beans in half lengthwise. Scrape out seeds.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title><link>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-cookies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-cookies.html</guid><description>Makes about 15 cookies.
3 cups pastry flour 0.5 teaspoon baking soda 0.5 teaspoon baking powder 1 teaspoon salt 2 sticks (8 ounces or 228 grams) unsalted butter, at room temperature 0.5 cups granulated sugar 1.5 cups packed brown sugar 1 teaspoon vanilla 2 large eggs or egg whites 1.5 cups semisweet chocolate chips In a medium bowl combine the flour, baking soda, baking powder and salt.
In the bowl of an electric mixer beat the butter, sugar, until creamy, about 2 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Brussels Sprouts</title><link>https://ggr.com/brussels-sprouts.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/brussels-sprouts.html</guid><description>Brussels sprouts avocado or grapeseed oil salt Cut sprouts in half lengthwise, so that the stem is cut in half. Pour a generous layer of oil in a pan. Cover pan with sprout halves, flat side down. Cover pan with lid. Turn on heat to medium. Cook on medium for 5 minutes or until brown. Line a bowl with a paper towel. Turn off stove and use a slotted spoon to move the sprouts into bowl.</description></item><item><title>Mashed Potatoes</title><link>https://ggr.com/mashed-potatoes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/mashed-potatoes.html</guid><description>Makes about 12 servings.
5 pounds golden potatoes 1 package Philadelphia Cream Cheese 1 pint sour cream 0.5 cups milk 0.5 stick unsalted butter 3 medium size cloves of garlic 2 teaspoons salt 3 teaspoons white pepper optional: horseradish sauce Peel potatoes and add to a large pot. Fill pot with enough water to cover potatoes. Boil for 40 minutes then drain water. Mash potatoes with a potato ricer. Add cream cheese, milk, sour cream, butter, salt, and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Barley Soup</title><link>https://ggr.com/barley-soup.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 23:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/barley-soup.html</guid><description>Makes about 8 servings.
3 leg-and-thighs of chicken 1.5 cups pearl barley 2 carrots 2 stalks of celery 0.5 white onion salt pepper Wash chicken. Put chicken into a large pot. Add water to pot until chicken is covered. Wash barley and add to pot. Grate onion and add to pot. Add 2 teaspoons salt.
Simmer for 1 hour. Cut carrots and celery into 0.25 inch thick pieces and add to soup.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti Sauce</title><link>https://ggr.com/spaghetti-sauce.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/spaghetti-sauce.html</guid><description>Get a big pot. Chop a large yellow onion and fry it in grape seed oil in the pot until they are translucent, about 3 minutes. Add 1 lb of ground beef to the onions and cook until the meat is brown, about 2 minutes. Add 2x 1 quart cans of Italian tomatoes in basil (they look like tubes rather than spheres). Chop the tomatoes you just put in into 2 or 3 pieces each.</description></item><item><title>Spanish Sweet Bread</title><link>https://ggr.com/spanish-sweet-bread.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/spanish-sweet-bread.html</guid><description>Bread Machine Variant Makes 1 loaf. This method is way easier than the original, which you can find right after this one.
0.75 cup whole milk 2 eggs, beaten 0.5 teaspoon lemon extract 0.5 teaspoon vanilla extract 500 grams bread flour / 3.5 cups 0.5 cups sugar 0.25 teaspoon salt 1 stick butter 1 package of yeast 0.75 cups golden raisins Put all the ingredients, up to and including the butter, into the bread maker, in the order they are listed.</description></item></channel></rss>