<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>food on game, game. repeat.</title><link>https://ggr.com/tags/food.html</link><description>Recent content in food on game, game. repeat.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 10:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Best Milkshake</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-milkshake.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 10:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-milkshake.html</guid><description>Get the Swiss milk chocolate milk shake from Fentons. Get the jumbo, what&amp;rsquo;s another thousand calories? You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it. Ok, maybe you will. But still&amp;hellip;its so, so good.
Updated on October 21st, 2013
Added a picture. It required some field work.</description></item><item><title>Best Ribs</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-ribs.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 09:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-ribs.html</guid><description>The meat falls off the bone. They taste like ribs should taste. And I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who thinks so.</description></item><item><title>Best Chicken Maharaja</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-chicken-maharaja.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-chicken-maharaja.html</guid><description>Sneha rolls buffet style, all you can eat. All I can eat when I go is the Chicken Maharaja.</description></item><item><title>Best Grape Juice</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-grape-juice.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 12:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-grape-juice.html</guid><description>Why should wine get all the good grapes? I buy this stuff by the case when I&amp;rsquo;m in Sonoma and it still goes fast.</description></item><item><title>Best Deep Dish Pizza</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-deep-dish-pizza.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-deep-dish-pizza.html</guid><description>Try the Chicken Pizza and order a large so you can take some home.</description></item><item><title>Best Pastrami Sandwich</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-pastrami-sandwich.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-pastrami-sandwich.html</guid><description>The Refuge in San Carlos, CA makes their pastrami in-house and its amazing. You&amp;rsquo;ll wonder how you ever put up with the conventional, mass-produced pastrami you get pretty much everywhere else.</description></item><item><title>Best Burrito</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-burrito.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-burrito.html</guid><description>They won&amp;rsquo;t be serving these at the Ritz Carlton any time soon, but don&amp;rsquo;t let it&amp;rsquo;s commonplace appearance fool you. &amp;ndash;Chavez Supermarket makes a&amp;ndash;tasty&amp;ndash;Super Carnitas Burrito packed with lots of pork and other burrito essentials. &amp;ndash;But if that&amp;rsquo;s not fancy enough for you, you can always ask for it &amp;lsquo;Au Jus&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Best Spring Rolls Recipe</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-spring-rolls-recipe.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 13:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-spring-rolls-recipe.html</guid><description>Made&amp;ndash;spring rolls&amp;ndash;this weekend and they were good. &amp;ndash;BTW, you only need about 1/4 of the dipping sauce they suggest for the amount of spring roll generated.</description></item><item><title>Best Broccoli Soup Recipe</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-broccoli-soup-recipe.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 08:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-broccoli-soup-recipe.html</guid><description>Don&amp;rsquo;t like broccoli? &amp;ndash;Me neither. &amp;ndash;But hold on to your soup bowls, this is a way to eat it that tastes pretty good.
Take a pound or so of broccoli. &amp;ndash;Boil it until tender. &amp;ndash;Throw it in a blender, add a 1/2 cup water, 1/2 cup grape seed oil, and a 1/2 teaspoon of salt. &amp;ndash;Blend until smooth. &amp;ndash;Add more oil and water in the same proportions until it flows.</description></item><item><title>Best Brussels Sprouts Recipe</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-brussels-sprouts-recipe.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-brussels-sprouts-recipe.html</guid><description>I have never liked brussel sprouts, in fact I was generally vegetable averse growing up. It turns out it wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely the vegetables&amp;rsquo; fault.
This easy recipe can transform brussel sprouts from being in the dreaded &amp;rsquo;tastes like it&amp;rsquo;s good for you&amp;rsquo; category to the &amp;lsquo;wow, can I have some more&amp;rsquo; category while remaining very healthy.Michele Bonds&amp;rsquo; Brussel SproutsBuy as many brussel sprouts as you want to eatCut them in half lengthwise, so that the stem is cut in halfFry them, flat side down over medium heat in grapeseed or olive oilOnce they are a crispy brown, remove them from the heatAdd salt to taste.</description></item><item><title>Best Mashed Potatoes Recipe</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-mashed-potatoes-recipe.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-mashed-potatoes-recipe.html</guid><description>Sometimes you need mashed potatoes. Could be a holiday, could be you have this huge bag of potatoes you bought and they are starting to grow sprouts. Whatever your reason, when the time comes try these out. They are about the best mashed potatoes I&amp;rsquo;ve ever tasted and I&amp;rsquo;ve had quiet a few dolops of potatoes in my day.
Dad Bonds&amp;rsquo; Mashed Potatoes Take 5 lbs of golden potatoes peel, cook for 40 minutes or until done mash with a masher or use a potato ricer add 5/6 of a package of Philadelphia Cream Cheese add 2 cups of sour cream add 1/2 cup milk add 1/4 stick of butter add 3 medium cloves garlic, finely chopped or pressed salt and pepper to taste, white pepper preferred for presentation</description></item><item><title>Best Ice Cream</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-ice-cream.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2006 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-ice-cream.html</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s Hagen Daz, Dryers, and a whole lot of other companies making ice cream. Coldstone&amp;rsquo;s the latest craze and gelato has enjoyed a recent surge in the Berkeley, CA area. But they&amp;rsquo;re all pretenders to the Double Rainbow throne.
Double Rainbow makes the best ice cream I&amp;rsquo;ve had outside of homemade. Gelato&amp;rsquo;s great and all, but I&amp;rsquo;ll take a scoop of DR over any gelato I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had as well. Try the chocolate chip.</description></item><item><title>Best Barley Soup Recipe</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-barley-soup-recipe.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 23:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-barley-soup-recipe.html</guid><description>I had the good fortune of growing up during a bygone era when an average middle class kid like me had a stay home mom who heaped love and good food on me and my family. This recipe is one of my favorite from my mom&amp;rsquo;s repertoire. It tastes great, it&amp;rsquo;s simple, the ingredients are inexpensive, it&amp;rsquo;s good for you, it&amp;rsquo;s great for colds (I swear fresh chicken broth has special powers, it can be made in large quantities, and it stores frozen and refrigerated.</description></item><item><title>Best Hamburger</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-hamburger.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2006 23:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-hamburger.html</guid><description>This is old hat to California natives, but if you haven&amp;rsquo;t visited in say, the last 15 years, you may not have heard of In-N-Out. It&amp;rsquo;s a family owned chain that&amp;rsquo;s known for it&amp;rsquo;s simple menu, good service, and excellent hamburgers (the fries are really good too).
I&amp;rsquo;ve had burgers at joints across the country, from McDonald&amp;rsquo;s to mom-and-pop burger stands and I always come back to In-N-Out. What sets In-N-Out apart from most fast food restaurants are their quality, health conscious ingredients.</description></item><item><title>Best Seafood Pasta</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-seafood-pasta.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 16:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-seafood-pasta.html</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s not as good as homemade but Michelangelo&amp;rsquo;s has had the same special for 5 years: linguini with baby clams, shrimp, and mussels; and it&amp;rsquo;s really good.
The place has a fun atmosphere, there&amp;rsquo;s rarely a long wait, and they serve gummy bears for desert. Oh, and if there is a wait, ask them to break you off a chunk of parmesan from their 20 lb. block of cheese or grab some yourself, it&amp;rsquo;s usually near the entrance.</description></item><item><title>Best Spaghetti Sauce Recipe</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-spaghetti-sauce-recipe.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-spaghetti-sauce-recipe.html</guid><description>For me there is no better spaghetti sauce that the stuff I grew up with. Period. I grew up on this stuff and maybe that&amp;rsquo;s got something to do with it, but when I make my friends have no problem polishing off a plateful and coming back for more.
My dad learned his first version of this recipe while working in an Italian restaurant in college. He made it a bunch of times while studying at Berkeley because, besides tasting great, it can be made in big batches and it refrigerates well (up to about 2 weeks).</description></item><item><title>Best Fish and Chips</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-fish-and-chips.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 13:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-fish-and-chips.html</guid><description>My girlfriend introduced me to this joint last time we were in Malibu&amp;ndash;I ordered a 3 piece fish and chips and Malibu Seafood gave me the biggest chunks of fried fish I&amp;rsquo;d ever seen.
I&amp;rsquo;m accustom to the frozen variety and the bar food variety of fish and chips, and let me tell you this is different. They take good, fresh, gourmet quality fish and fry it up. Add some tartar sauce and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to go.</description></item><item><title>Best Corned Beef Hash</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-corned-beef-hash.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 13:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-corned-beef-hash.html</guid><description>Whenever I visit my family in the LA area I try to find my way to Billy&amp;rsquo;s in Glendale for an order of corned beef hashand an order of hash brown potatoes (with plenty of ketchup). Billy&amp;rsquo;s makes their own corned beef hash and it&amp;rsquo;s excellent. I have tried corned beef hash at many other restaurants trying to find something this good closer to my home in San Francisco; I&amp;rsquo;ve searched high and low, but I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to find a comparable hash.</description></item><item><title>Best Spanish Sweet Bread Recipe</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-spanish-sweet-bread-recipe.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-spanish-sweet-bread-recipe.html</guid><description>My great-grandmother was warm, fun, and loving. One of her favorite ways to show us she cared was to cook us food&amp;hellip;and to sneak us a cookie when mom wasn&amp;rsquo;t looking. My great-grandma (who we called Abuelita), grandma, mother, brother, and I have all made this bread and it&amp;rsquo;s really good.
Especially with a little warm butter spread on top. The recipe has been passed down through my family for generations and with each generation it&amp;rsquo;s become infused with a little more love.</description></item></channel></rss>