<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>food on game, game. repeat.</title><link>https://ggr.com/tags/food.html</link><description>Recent content in food on game, game. repeat.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 05:19:46 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Buttermilk Pancakes</title><link>https://ggr.com/buttermilk-pancakes.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 05:19:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/buttermilk-pancakes.html</guid><description>Makes 2 servings.
1 cup (5 ounces) all-purpose flour 1 tablespoon sugar 0.5 teaspoon baking powder 0.25 teaspoon baking soda 0.25 teaspoon salt 1 cup buttermilk 3 tablespoons sour cream 1 large egg 3 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted and cooled avocado oil spray Whisk flour, sugar, baking powder, baking soda, and salt together in medium bowl. In second medium bowl, whisk together buttermilk, sour cream, eggs, and melted butter. Make well in center of dry ingredients and pour in wet ingredients; gently stir until just combined (batter should remain lumpy, with few streaks of flour).</description></item><item><title>Chicken Salad</title><link>https://ggr.com/chicken-salad.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 18:17:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/chicken-salad.html</guid><description>Makes 8 servings.
Pastry Boats 0.66 cup water 5 tablespoons butter 0.5 teaspoon salt 0.66 cup all-purpose flour 3 eggs In a 2-quart pan, combine the water, butter, and salt. Quickly bring to a boil, stirring to melt butter. Add flour all at once, remove pan from heat, and beat ingredients with a wire whip until smooth. Beat in eggs, one at a time, until mixture is smooth and glossy.</description></item><item><title>Cheesecake</title><link>https://ggr.com/cheesecake.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 09:07:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/cheesecake.html</guid><description>Makes 12 servings.
16 ounces (2 boxes) Zwieback crackers or plain biscotti 1.5 cup sugar 1 cup unsalted butter 32 ounces (4 bars) Philedelphia cream cheese 4 tablespoons all-purpose flour 2 tablespoons vanilla extract 8 eggs 2 cup evaporated milk or light cream or half &amp;amp; half Take eggs, cheese, and butter out of the fridge 20 minutes before starting (makes eggs froth more for a fluffier cheesecake; makes butter and cheese easier to work with).</description></item><item><title>Egg Rolls</title><link>https://ggr.com/egg-rolls.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 08:23:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/egg-rolls.html</guid><description>Makes 12 servings.
Filling 0.5 pound shrimp 1 teaspoon dry sherry 0.5 teaspoon cornstarch 1 pound skinless, boneless chicken thighs 4 tablespoons avocado oil 2 tablespoons soy sauce 1 teaspoon salt 1 tablespoon sugar 1 pound (mung) bean sprouts 2 cups celery 5 stalks green onion Mix shrimp with sherry, cornstarch and 0.5 teaspoon salt. Stir fry for 1 minute then set aside.
If chicken is used, stir fry in 1 tablespoon oil, 1 tablespoon soy sauce, and 1 teaspoon sugar.</description></item><item><title>Cranberry Sauce</title><link>https://ggr.com/cranberry-sauce.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 02:01:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/cranberry-sauce.html</guid><description>Makes 12 servings.
12 ounces (1 package) fresh cranberries 1 orange 1 apple 1 cup sugar Add all ingredients to blender. Blend until smooth. Pour into a bowl and refrigerate until ready to eat. Serve.</description></item><item><title>Yellow Pepper Soup</title><link>https://ggr.com/yellow-pepper-soup.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:20:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/yellow-pepper-soup.html</guid><description>Makes 8 servings.
1 medium onion 1 celery stalk 1 carrot 2 garlic cloves 2 tablespoons avocado oil 1.5 pounds yellow peppers 0.75 pound potatoes 3 cups water or chicken stock 1 tablespoon sea salt 1 small hot red pepper or 1 pinch chili pepper flakes Chop onion, celery, carrot, and garlic. Add to 4-quart heavy-bottomed pot. Drizzle with oil, stir to coat over low heat for 10 minutes or until vegetables are soft.</description></item><item><title>Hamburger</title><link>https://ggr.com/hamburger.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 23:57:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/hamburger.html</guid><description>Makes 1 serving.
1 frozen Impossible Burger patty 1 brioche burger bun 1 thick slice of Tillamook medium cheddar 1 slice of sweet onion 1 slice of heirloom tomato 0.5 avocado Toast bun and set aside. Cut slices of cheese, onion, and tomato and set aside. Slice avocado into 0.125 inch thick pieces and set aside. Set oven to broil at &amp;lsquo;HI&amp;rsquo; temperature. Wait 5 minutes for it to warm up.</description></item><item><title>Butter Chicken</title><link>https://ggr.com/butter-chicken.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 18:01:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/butter-chicken.html</guid><description>Makes 8 servings.
14 ounces (1 can) diced tomatoes (do not drain) 1 cup water 5 garlic cloves 1 tablespoon minced ginger 1 teaspoon ground turmeric 1 teaspoon ground cayenne pepper 1 teaspoon paprika 2 teaspoons garam masala 1 teaspoon ground cumin 1 teaspoon salt 1 pound boneless, skinless chicken thighs 8 tablespoons (1 stick) unsalted butter 1 cup heavy cream or whole coconut milk 1 tablespoon sugar 0.5 cup chopped fresh cilantro 4 cups Basmati rice Wash rice, add water, and start cooking in a rice cooker.</description></item><item><title>Kale Salad</title><link>https://ggr.com/kale-salad.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 12:28:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/kale-salad.html</guid><description>Makes 4 servings.
Dressing 0.5 cup peanut oil 2 tablespoons toasted sesame oil 3 teaspoons soy sauce 2 tablespoons seasoned rice wine vinegar 2 tablespoons honey 1 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper 0.25 teaspoon cayenne pepper Add all ingredients to a mason jar and seal. Shake well. Refrigerate until ready to use.
Salad 10 ounces Trader Joes organic shredded kale 0.25 cup fresh cilantro 0.25 cup fresh mint 2 green onions 2 cups cabbage 0.</description></item><item><title>Cucumber Salad</title><link>https://ggr.com/cucumber-salad.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 10:11:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/cucumber-salad.html</guid><description>Makes 4 servings.
Less-Wet Cucumbers 5 Persian cucumbers 2 tablespoons salt Trim the cucumbers and cut into 0.5-inch thick pieces. Place in a small bowl. Sprinkle with salt and toss well to coat. Allow to sit at room temperature for 30 minutes. Rinse off salt mixture and pat dry.
Marinade 3 tablespoons rice vinegar 2 tablespoons mirin 1.5 tablespoons honey 2 teaspoons avocado oil 2 teaspoons sesame oil 1 teaspoon chili garlic sauce 0.</description></item><item><title>Baby Back Ribs</title><link>https://ggr.com/baby-back-ribs.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 05:01:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/baby-back-ribs.html</guid><description>Makes 4 servings.
1 rinsed, frozen, halved, rack of Swift Premium Pork Loin Backribs from Costco water BBQ sauce Place ribs in Instant Pot. Fill with water until ribs are covered. Set Instant Pot to &amp;lsquo;Meat&amp;rsquo; setting, 25 minutes, and press start. Release pressure, open pot, and transfer ribs to a baking sheet with a rack. Slather ribs with BBQ sauce. Set oven broiler to &amp;lsquo;hi&amp;rsquo;. Wait 5 minutes for broiler to warm up.</description></item><item><title>Coconut Cream Pie</title><link>https://ggr.com/coconut-cream-pie.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 09:51:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/coconut-cream-pie.html</guid><description>Makes 8 servings.
Graham Cracker Crust 10 whole graham crackers, broken into 1-inch pieces 6 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted and cooled 3 tablespoons sugar Adjust oven rack to middle position and heat oven to 325 F. Process graham cracker pieces in food processor to fine, even crumbs, about 30 seconds. Sprinkle melted butter and sugar over crumbs and pulse to incorporate, about 5 pulses. Sprinkle mixture into 9-inch pie plate. Using a large spoon, press crumbs into even layer on bottom and sides of pie plate.</description></item><item><title>Pecan Pie</title><link>https://ggr.com/pecan-pie.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 09:21:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/pecan-pie.html</guid><description>Makes 8 servings.
Butter Crust 1 tablespoon sour cream or 2 teaspoons apple cider vinegar 3 tablespoons ice water 1.25 cups pastry flour 1.5 teaspoons sugar 0.5 teaspoons salt 8 tablespoons unsalted butter, frozen, cut into 0.25 inch cubes Mix sour cream and ice water in a bowl until combined. Process flour, sugar, and salt in a food processor until combined, about 5 seconds. Add butter and pulse mixture until butter is the size of larges peas, about 10 pulses.</description></item><item><title>Arugula Salad</title><link>https://ggr.com/arugula-salad.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 22:22:21 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/arugula-salad.html</guid><description>Makes 2 servings.
5 ounces baby arugula 1 cup cherry tomotoes 1 ripe avocado 1 tablespoon Terrapin Ridge Farms ginger miso dressing Add arugula to a large salad bowl. Remove pit from avocado and scoop a tablespoon at a time into bowl. Cut tomotoes in half and add to bowl. Drizzle dressing over salad. Toss the salad. Serve immediately.</description></item><item><title>Buckwheat Cereal</title><link>https://ggr.com/buckwheat-cereal.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 22:21:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/buckwheat-cereal.html</guid><description>Makes 2 servings.
0.25 cups roasted buckwheat aka kasha 1.5 cups water or milk 0.25 cups chia seed 0.25 cups flaxseed 0.5 cups almonds, roasted and unsalted 1 Fuji apple, chopped Pour buckwheat into a large, microwave safe bowl. Add water. Microwave for 5 minutes. Remove from microwave and let buckwheat rest for 5 minutes. Grind flaxseed in a coffee grinder. Add chia seed and ground flaxseed to buckwheat and stir together.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Chip Ice Cream</title><link>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-ice-cream.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:46:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-ice-cream.html</guid><description>Makes about 2 quarts. Substitute 4 teaspoons vanilla extract for the vanilla beans by adding the vanilla extract after the mixture cools, before putting it in the refridgerator.
2 vanilla beans 3.5 cups heavy cream 2.5 cups whole milk 0.66 cups sugar 0.66 cups light corn syrup 0.5 teaspoons salt 12 large egg yolks 0.33 cups semisweet chocolate 1 teaspoon vegetable oil Cut vanilla beans in half lengthwise. Scrape out seeds.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title><link>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-cookies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-cookies.html</guid><description>Makes about 15 cookies.
3 cups pastry flour 0.5 teaspoon baking soda 0.5 teaspoon baking powder 1 teaspoon salt 2 sticks (8 ounces or 228 grams) unsalted butter, at room temperature 0.5 cups granulated sugar 1.5 cups packed brown sugar 1 teaspoon vanilla 2 large eggs or egg whites 1.5 cups semisweet chocolate chips In a medium bowl combine the flour, baking soda, baking powder and salt.
In the bowl of an electric mixer beat the butter, sugar, until creamy, about 2 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Best Milkshake</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-milkshake.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 10:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-milkshake.html</guid><description>Get the Swiss milk chocolate milk shake from Fentons. Get the jumbo, what&amp;rsquo;s another thousand calories? You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it. Ok, maybe you will. But still&amp;hellip;its so, so good.
Updated on October 21st, 2013
Added a picture. It required some field work.</description></item><item><title>Best Ribs</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-ribs.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 09:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-ribs.html</guid><description>The meat falls off the bone. They taste like ribs should taste. And I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who thinks so.</description></item><item><title>Best Chicken Maharaja</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-chicken-maharaja.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-chicken-maharaja.html</guid><description>Sneha rolls buffet style, all you can eat. All I can eat when I go is the Chicken Maharaja.</description></item><item><title>Best Grape Juice</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-grape-juice.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 12:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-grape-juice.html</guid><description>Why should wine get all the good grapes? I buy this stuff by the case when I&amp;rsquo;m in Sonoma and it still goes fast.</description></item><item><title>Best Deep Dish Pizza</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-deep-dish-pizza.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-deep-dish-pizza.html</guid><description>Try the Chicken Pizza and order a large so you can take some home.</description></item><item><title>Best Pastrami Sandwich</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-pastrami-sandwich.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-pastrami-sandwich.html</guid><description>The Refuge in San Carlos, CA makes their pastrami in-house and its amazing. You&amp;rsquo;ll wonder how you ever put up with the conventional, mass-produced pastrami you get pretty much everywhere else.</description></item><item><title>Best Burrito</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-burrito.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-burrito.html</guid><description>They won&amp;rsquo;t be serving these at the Ritz Carlton any time soon, but don&amp;rsquo;t let it&amp;rsquo;s commonplace appearance fool you. &amp;ndash;Chavez Supermarket makes a&amp;ndash;tasty&amp;ndash;Super Carnitas Burrito packed with lots of pork and other burrito essentials. &amp;ndash;But if that&amp;rsquo;s not fancy enough for you, you can always ask for it &amp;lsquo;Au Jus&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Best Spring Rolls Recipe</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-spring-rolls-recipe.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 13:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-spring-rolls-recipe.html</guid><description>Made&amp;ndash;spring rolls&amp;ndash;this weekend and they were good. &amp;ndash;BTW, you only need about 1/4 of the dipping sauce they suggest for the amount of spring roll generated.</description></item><item><title>Broccoli Soup</title><link>https://ggr.com/broccoli-soup.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 08:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/broccoli-soup.html</guid><description>1 pound broccoli 0.5 cups avocado or grapeseed oil 0.5 cups water 1 teaspoon salt Boil broccoli in water for 10 minutes. Drain water. Transfer broccoli to blender. Add oil, water, and salt. Blend until smooth. Add more salt to taste. Add more water if you like it thinner and more soup-like. Serve hot or cold.
Don&amp;rsquo;t like broccoli? Me neither. But hold on to your soup bowls, this is a way to eat it that tastes pretty good.</description></item><item><title>Brussels Sprouts</title><link>https://ggr.com/brussels-sprouts.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/brussels-sprouts.html</guid><description>Makes any number of servings.
Brussels sprouts avocado or grapeseed oil salt Cut sprouts in half lengthwise, so that the stem is cut in half. Pour a generous layer of oil in a pan. Cover pan with sprout halves, flat side down. Cover pan with lid. Turn on heat to medium. Cook on medium for 5 minutes or until brown. Line a bowl with a paper towel. Turn off stove and use a slotted spoon to move the sprouts into bowl.</description></item><item><title>Mashed Potatoes</title><link>https://ggr.com/mashed-potatoes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/mashed-potatoes.html</guid><description>Makes about 12 servings.
5 pounds golden potatoes 1 package Philadelphia Cream Cheese 1 pint sour cream 0.5 cups milk 0.5 stick unsalted butter 3 medium size cloves of garlic 2 teaspoons salt 3 teaspoons white pepper optional: horseradish sauce Peel potatoes and add to a large pot. Fill pot with enough water to cover potatoes. Boil for 40 minutes then drain water. Mash potatoes with a potato ricer. Add cream cheese, milk, sour cream, butter, salt, and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Best Ice Cream</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-ice-cream.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2006 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-ice-cream.html</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s Hagen Daz, Dryers, and a whole lot of other companies making ice cream. Coldstone&amp;rsquo;s the latest craze and gelato has enjoyed a recent surge in the Berkeley, CA area. But they&amp;rsquo;re all pretenders to the Double Rainbow throne.
Double Rainbow makes the best ice cream I&amp;rsquo;ve had outside of homemade. Gelato&amp;rsquo;s great and all, but I&amp;rsquo;ll take a scoop of DR over any gelato I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had as well. Try the chocolate chip.</description></item><item><title>Barley Soup</title><link>https://ggr.com/barley-soup.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 23:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/barley-soup.html</guid><description>Makes about 8 servings.
3 leg-and-thighs of chicken 1.5 cups pearl barley 2 carrots 2 stalks of celery 0.5 white onion salt pepper Wash chicken. Put chicken into a large pot. Add water to pot until chicken is covered. Wash barley and add to pot. Grate onion and add to pot. Add 2 teaspoons salt.
Simmer for 1 hour. Cut carrots and celery into 0.25 inch thick pieces and add to soup.</description></item><item><title>Best Hamburger</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-hamburger.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2006 23:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-hamburger.html</guid><description>This is old hat to California natives, but if you haven&amp;rsquo;t visited in say, the last 15 years, you may not have heard of In-N-Out. It&amp;rsquo;s a family owned chain that&amp;rsquo;s known for it&amp;rsquo;s simple menu, good service, and excellent hamburgers (the fries are really good too).
I&amp;rsquo;ve had burgers at joints across the country, from McDonald&amp;rsquo;s to mom-and-pop burger stands and I always come back to In-N-Out. What sets In-N-Out apart from most fast food restaurants are their quality, health conscious ingredients.</description></item><item><title>Best Seafood Pasta</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-seafood-pasta.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 16:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-seafood-pasta.html</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s not as good as homemade but Michelangelo&amp;rsquo;s has had the same special for 5 years: linguini with baby clams, shrimp, and mussels; and it&amp;rsquo;s really good.
The place has a fun atmosphere, there&amp;rsquo;s rarely a long wait, and they serve gummy bears for desert. Oh, and if there is a wait, ask them to break you off a chunk of parmesan from their 20 lb. block of cheese or grab some yourself, it&amp;rsquo;s usually near the entrance.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti Sauce</title><link>https://ggr.com/spaghetti-sauce.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/spaghetti-sauce.html</guid><description>Makes 10 servings.
0.5 cups avocado or grapeseed oil 4 cloves garlic 1 large yellow onion 1.5 pounds lean ground beef or Impossible Burger 15 ounces tomato sauce 12 ounces tomato paste 1 bottle of red wine or 4 cups of Burgandy 1 tablespoon oregano 1 tablespoon thyme 1 tablespoon sage 1 tablespoon basil 2 bay leaves 2 teaspoons salt 1 tablespoon brown sugar 56 ounces (2 cans) Italian-style tomatoes in basil Add oil to a large pot.</description></item><item><title>Best Fish and Chips</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-fish-and-chips.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 13:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-fish-and-chips.html</guid><description>My girlfriend introduced me to this joint last time we were in Malibu&amp;ndash;I ordered a 3 piece fish and chips and Malibu Seafood gave me the biggest chunks of fried fish I&amp;rsquo;d ever seen.
I&amp;rsquo;m accustom to the frozen variety and the bar food variety of fish and chips, and let me tell you this is different. They take good, fresh, gourmet quality fish and fry it up. Add some tartar sauce and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to go.</description></item><item><title>Best Corned Beef Hash</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-corned-beef-hash.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 13:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-corned-beef-hash.html</guid><description>Whenever I visit my family in the LA area I try to find my way to Billy&amp;rsquo;s in Glendale for an order of corned beef hashand an order of hash brown potatoes (with plenty of ketchup). Billy&amp;rsquo;s makes their own corned beef hash and it&amp;rsquo;s excellent. I have tried corned beef hash at many other restaurants trying to find something this good closer to my home in San Francisco; I&amp;rsquo;ve searched high and low, but I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to find a comparable hash.</description></item><item><title>Spanish Sweet Bread</title><link>https://ggr.com/spanish-sweet-bread.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/spanish-sweet-bread.html</guid><description>Bread Machine Variant Makes 1 loaf. This method is way easier than the original, which you can find right after this one.
0.75 cup whole milk 2 eggs, beaten 0.5 teaspoon lemon extract 0.5 teaspoon vanilla extract 500 grams bread flour / 3.5 cups 0.5 cups sugar 0.25 teaspoon salt 1 stick butter 1 package of yeast 0.75 cups golden raisins Put all the ingredients, up to and including the butter, into the bread maker, in the order they are listed.</description></item></channel></rss>