<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on game, game. repeat.</title><link>https://ggr.com/posts.html</link><description>Recent content in Posts on game, game. repeat.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:46:17 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chocolate Chip Ice Cream</title><link>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-ice-cream.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:46:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-ice-cream.html</guid><description>Makes about 2 quarts. Substitute 4 teaspoons vanilla extract for the vanilla beans by adding the vanilla extract after the mixture cools, before putting it in the refridgerator.
2 vanilla beans 3.5 cups heavy cream 2.5 cups whole milk 0.66 cups sugar 0.66 cups light corn syrup 0.5 teaspoons salt 12 large egg yolks 0.33 cups bittersweet chocolate 1 teaspoon vegetable oil Cut vanilla beans in half lengthwise. Scrape out seeds.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title><link>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-cookies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/chocolate-chip-cookies.html</guid><description>Makes about 15 cookies.
3 cups pastry flour 0.5 teaspoon baking soda 0.5 teaspoon baking powder 1 teaspoon salt 2 sticks (8 ounces or 228 grams) unsalted butter, at room temperature 0.5 cups granulated sugar 1.5 cups packed brown sugar 1 teaspoon vanilla 2 large eggs or egg whites 1.5 cups semisweet chocolate chips In a medium bowl combine the flour, baking soda, baking powder and salt.
In the bowl of an electric mixer beat the butter, sugar, until creamy, about 2 minutes.</description></item><item><title>The +1-1=0 Game vs the 1+1=4 Game</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-1-10-game-vs-the-1-14-game.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 20:09:25 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-1-10-game-vs-the-1-14-game.html</guid><description>I suspect that if you take a somewhat random group of human beings and ask them to organize themselves in order to allocate work and limited resources, most of the time they will find themselves playing a zero sum game with each other. I call it the +1-1=0 game.
The other game to be played is the 1+1=4 game. It&amp;rsquo;s the game of abundance, of creating a bigger pie, of win-wins that benefit everyone.</description></item><item><title>Junior vs Senior Managers</title><link>https://ggr.com/junior-vs-senior-managers.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 11:26:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/junior-vs-senior-managers.html</guid><description>Warning: preference-style opinions ahead, e.g. cherry pie is better than apple pie. That said, I’ve used these opinions in anger, so they may be of interest to mangers trying to get ahead with a leader that thinks like I do.
Junior: my first loyalty is to the team I lead, my downwards team
Senior: my first loyalty is to the team my boss leads, my upwards team
Junior: my span of control is how many people must do what I say</description></item><item><title>Junior vs Senior Engineers</title><link>https://ggr.com/junior-vs-senior-engineers.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 10:46:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/junior-vs-senior-engineers.html</guid><description>Warning: preference-style opinions ahead, e.g. pecan pie is better than apple pie. That said, I’ve used these opinions in anger, so they may be of interest to engineers trying to get ahead with a leader that thinks like I do.
Junior: right tool for the job
Senior: right ‘enough’ tool for the job, fewer tools better mastered
Junior: clever solution
Senior: easy to understand solution, even if a bit ugly</description></item><item><title>A Couple Of My Duties As a Citizen of a Democracy</title><link>https://ggr.com/a-couple-of-my-duties-as-a-citizen-of-a-democracy.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 10:54:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/a-couple-of-my-duties-as-a-citizen-of-a-democracy.html</guid><description>Speak Up I must speak up in public forums like LinkedIN, Twitter, and Christmas dinner. I’ve been taught that talking politics is impolite. But leaving good ideas unsaid and undefended, and letting bad ideas dominate the conversation and lead to bad decisions is even more impolite.
Change My Mind I must listen, learn, and change my mind, which is way harder than defending my beliefs and standing my ground. It requires humility to admit I was wrong and courage to let others see my mistakes.</description></item><item><title>On Commitment</title><link>https://ggr.com/on-commitment.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 17:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/on-commitment.html</guid><description>Imagine you have a team of 5, a leader plus 4 others. The leader chooses not to contribute ideas, preferring to select from the ideas of his team. The team members are equally persuasive and generate equally good and viable ideas, but the ideas are as opposite/orthogonal/different as they can be.
The team has decided to make decisions together and fully commit to those decisions, so all their creative, persuasive, and intellectual energy operates in concert.</description></item><item><title>Companies Are Made of People</title><link>https://ggr.com/companies-are-made-of-people.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/companies-are-made-of-people.html</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve adopted the Patrick Lencioni stack at Mixbook. We are starting with The Advantage and working our way backwards in order of publication. Turns out companies are made out of human beings. Who knew?</description></item><item><title>Calculate the Full Price of That New Tech</title><link>https://ggr.com/calculate-the-full-price-of-that-new-tech.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/calculate-the-full-price-of-that-new-tech.html</guid><description>Next time you get the urge to try out some new tech in production please remember this: 5 years from now, long after you got bored with it, some poor sap is going to be stuck fixing bugs in that new tech code you committed, because no one ever took the time to rip it out, and something in production depends on it. You&amp;rsquo;ve just introduce tech debt that will most likely be wasting someone&amp;rsquo;s time for many years to come.</description></item><item><title>Don't Pay Down Tech Debt With Tech Debt</title><link>https://ggr.com/dont-pay-down-tech-debt-with-tech-debt.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 19:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/dont-pay-down-tech-debt-with-tech-debt.html</guid><description>An anti-pattern I keep running across is trying to solve tech debt problems by adding a new tool to the stack. It&amp;rsquo;s like planning to pay off some of your $10K in credit card debt by getting a new card with a $5K limit with a lower interest rate&amp;hellip;but then using $1K of it pay down the old card and spending the other $4K on new stuff. Now you&amp;rsquo;ve got $14K of debt to service.</description></item><item><title>Don't Delay Gratification For Others</title><link>https://ggr.com/dont-delay-gratification-for-others.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/dont-delay-gratification-for-others.html</guid><description>Its generally thought that the ability to delay your own gratification is correlated with greater success. I buy that. But I think it&amp;rsquo;s the opposite when dealing with others&amp;ndash;giving others what they want right now and you&amp;rsquo;ll win their support, their dollars, and their vote.</description></item><item><title>How to Market Genode</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-market-genode.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-market-genode.html</guid><description>Following updates from Genode and Haiku highlighting their progress towards becoming broadly useful operating systems, I installed them on some real hardware, took them for a spin, and thought about what it would take for them to take over the world&amp;hellip;what market position is available and accessible to a potential, future, Genode based OS?
So. Would you be interesting in an OS that can say this (with a straight face)?:</description></item><item><title>On Laying a Foundation</title><link>https://ggr.com/on-laying-a-foundation.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 18:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/on-laying-a-foundation.html</guid><description>When someone says &amp;lsquo;we are laying a foundation for X&amp;rsquo; I take it as code for wasting resources and the sort of lazy thinking that goes with it&amp;hellip;at least if they are talking about going dark to make some software, whether its about the code, infrastructure, tooling, UI, or UX. Real (successful) developers ship value now; rinse, repeat. You don&amp;rsquo;t win a race by standing still.</description></item><item><title>My Ideal Product Manager</title><link>https://ggr.com/my-ideal-product-manager.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/my-ideal-product-manager.html</guid><description>My ideal product manager is more interested in disproving their idea than proving it.
They are a scientist with the humility to expect they&amp;rsquo;ll be wrong, the patience to try again, and the hunger to find the truth however unaesthetic it may be. They are a business person, more interested in getting results than questing after their ideal UI or zero bugs. They are a crafts person, not an artist&amp;ndash;they value utility over beauty.</description></item><item><title>Angband 2017 Review</title><link>https://ggr.com/angband-2017-review.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 16:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/angband-2017-review.html</guid><description>A couple months ago my wife got locked out of Steam while trying to remember her password and we had to give up on a rare chance to play some Don&amp;rsquo;t Starve Together, um, together. It got me thinking&amp;hellip;DRM is a pain in the butt sometimes. I wonder what FOSS games are out there.
Turns out there are some rather good ones available, unless your aim is showing off how much you can spend on a game system.</description></item><item><title>My First Idris Program</title><link>https://ggr.com/my-first-idris-program.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 19:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/my-first-idris-program.html</guid><description>Idris is sort of &amp;lsquo;Haskell 2.0&amp;rsquo;, where the authors got to apply the lessons learned from the creation and evolution of Haskell, but leave behind all the baggage embedded in existing, in use libraries, since, you know, they don&amp;rsquo;t have any of those yet. With the recent release of the book I was inspired to take Idris for a spin and see for myself just how lacking of &amp;lsquo;production readiness&amp;rsquo; it is.</description></item><item><title>How to GPS on OpenBSD</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-gps-on-openbsd.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 15:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-gps-on-openbsd.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard tell that the WWAN module lodged inside my laptop can give me my coordinates on planet Earth. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d see if it was true. Fortunately, a number of brave souls have blazed the path, I needed only to rediscover it.
Funny side note Did you know that your super modern WWAN module uses 1980s-era modem commands to control it? You know, AT&amp;hellip;OK, blah blah blah. Who knew, right?</description></item><item><title>Stop Hiring DevOps</title><link>https://ggr.com/stop-hiring-devops.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 21:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/stop-hiring-devops.html</guid><description>Look. The reason its so hard to find (great) DevOps engineers is that is a shit job at most companies. When last I was hunting for a DevOps lead, most of the folks I talked to had war/horror stories about working at a company (or two or three) where they were on duty 24x7, the codebase was fragile, they got paged a lot (at 2a), and they weren&amp;rsquo;t given the time or help they needed to dig themselves out of the hole they were hired into.</description></item><item><title>How To Install Coreboot Onto Your Lenovo Thinkpad X200 Laptop</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-install-coreboot-onto-your-lenovo-thinkpad-x200-laptop.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-install-coreboot-onto-your-lenovo-thinkpad-x200-laptop.html</guid><description>I flashed a Lenovo x200 with Coreboot with Intel microcode enabled, ME removed, and the gigabit ethernet firmware from Libreboot. Everything seems to work with OpenBSD (my daily driver OS). Unlike with Libreboot, which comes with a Grub2 payload, Coreboot uses the SeaBIOS payload by default and it can boot an encrypted OpenBSD volume. I&amp;rsquo;m encountering what seems to be a random lockup every few days, haven&amp;rsquo;t had a chance to troubleshoot it yet.</description></item><item><title>Open (Source) the NSA</title><link>https://ggr.com/open-source-the-nsa.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 17:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/open-source-the-nsa.html</guid><description>Democracy and government secrets are at odds with each other. Keeping secrets and accessing the secrets of others is a way to gain power. And while we want our government to gain power over people that seek to harm us, we do not want them to have power over the innocent citizen they answer to.
The solution is transparency. The NSA must make a monthly copy of all the data and software from their systems and make it available to the public 2 years later.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Customer Support Has Gone Downhill</title><link>https://ggr.com/amazon-customer-support-has-gone-downhill.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/amazon-customer-support-has-gone-downhill.html</guid><description>Amazon used to have outstanding customer support. But it seems their focus is elsewhere these days. In the past I&amp;rsquo;d contact them via phone or email and someone would try to understand my issue and resolve it in my favor. But yesterday I had a phone+email exchange about a very late order that they struggled to understand and chose not to fix&amp;ndash;it seemed it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fit for their playbook, so they couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out what to do except to tell me I&amp;rsquo;m out of luck.</description></item><item><title>Outing Bigots</title><link>https://ggr.com/outing-bigots.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/outing-bigots.html</guid><description>It seems the bigots have come out of the woodwork recently, emboldened by Trump&amp;rsquo;s election. If someone behaves that way around me I&amp;rsquo;m recording a video and posting it online, for all to see. I&amp;rsquo;ll ask for their name and add it to the video&amp;rsquo;s description so its nice and easy for search engines to index.</description></item><item><title>I'm a Consum-ee, Not a Consum-er</title><link>https://ggr.com/im-a-consum-ee-not-a-consum-er.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 20:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/im-a-consum-ee-not-a-consum-er.html</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t have a healthy relationship with consumer products. Or consumer content. I spent a lot of time on World of Warcraft back in the day. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time fiddling with apps on my iPhone. A lot. Candy Crush&amp;hellip;nuf said. TV shows keep getting better and better. There&amp;rsquo;s so much amazing content, I could just stare at these fonts of great entertainment all day long, wasting away, if I was so inclined.</description></item><item><title>Vote With Your Attention</title><link>https://ggr.com/vote-with-your-attention.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/vote-with-your-attention.html</guid><description>Up until a few years ago, my software choices were largely accidents of circumstance and convenience. I started using CP/M, then an Atari 800, then DOS on a 386, then Windows, then OSX, then Debian, then Arch, then OpenBSD. Somewhere in the middle there was a mobile track, starting with dumb phones, then Palm, then Windows Mobile, then iOS, then Android, then Replicant. On the web it went NCSA Mosaic, Firefox, IE, Safari, Chrome, Firefox, vimb.</description></item><item><title>The Haskell Programming Book Isn't Good Enough</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-haskell-programming-book-isnt-good-enough.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-haskell-programming-book-isnt-good-enough.html</guid><description>We (the human race) spend/waste an enormous amount of energy writing code that won&amp;rsquo;t last. We constantly cut ourselves on the sharp edges of C, PHP, Perl, Ruby, Java, and lots of other languages that were the best and brightest of their day, but they don&amp;rsquo;t go far enough protecting us from our own stupidity, laziness, distractedness, busyness&amp;hellip;
Point is, I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a way out of this mess. And as someone in management, I&amp;rsquo;m responsible for either doing nothing or making intentional choices about what tools galaxy my team lives in and how we go about our work of creating business value through software.</description></item><item><title>Ruby vs Haskell: Ruby is Lego, Haskell is Steel</title><link>https://ggr.com/ruby-vs-haskell-ruby-is-lego-haskell-is-steel.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 02:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/ruby-vs-haskell-ruby-is-lego-haskell-is-steel.html</guid><description>Ruby feels like working with Legos: its easy to pickup, delightful from the start, and you can make amazing things with it quickly. But as your creations get bigger and bigger, they become increasing awkward and fragile. Using Haskell is like working with steel: its difficult to get started and takes a lot of energy to do anything, even after you&amp;rsquo;re good at it, but you can build very strong, resilient, large structures.</description></item><item><title>Mediocrity Isn't Worth It</title><link>https://ggr.com/mediocrity-isnt-worth-it.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/mediocrity-isnt-worth-it.html</guid><description>Companies and teams tend towards mediocrity over time. Call it entropy, call it regression to the mean&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering my own sins in this area lately, and I find myself wanting.
Mediocrity is infectious and it kills motivation, creativity, and productivity. But its sooo easy. It can start with a bad hire, whose not that bad. They&amp;rsquo;ve been here for years, they are likeable, they are loyal, they&amp;rsquo;ve got outstanding raw potential&amp;hellip;but they struggle to get results.</description></item><item><title>Culture, Brand, (and Founders) FTW</title><link>https://ggr.com/culture-brand-and-founders-ftw.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/culture-brand-and-founders-ftw.html</guid><description>The quality of the people and the culture of a company define its trajectory. Brand is the bank where it stores the value it creates along the way. Everything else is implementation detail.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t have great people operating in a great culture, you&amp;rsquo;re operating on borrowed time. Maybe you get lucky and can ride that luck for a while, but unless you build a sustainable, quality culture, you&amp;rsquo;re dying a slow (or fast) death.</description></item><item><title>Minimize Maximum Stupidity</title><link>https://ggr.com/minimize-maximum-stupidity.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/minimize-maximum-stupidity.html</guid><description>TL;DR scaling a dev team + code base has more to do with minimizing stupidity than with maximizing brilliance.
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with some amount of C, C++, Java, Ruby, Python, Bourne Shell, PHP, HTML, Objective-C, Haskell, and Javascript, among others. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to imagine that the range of code quality, of an average line of code by an average engineer, using C as a sort of baseline, looks something like this:</description></item><item><title>FOSS vs Proprietary Cheatsheet</title><link>https://ggr.com/foss-vs-proprietary-cheatsheet.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/foss-vs-proprietary-cheatsheet.html</guid><description>FOSS just gets better and better, feature-wise and ethics-wise&amp;hellip;and it seems Proprietary keeps getting better feature-wise, but worse ethics-wise. Its got me asking myself why I&amp;rsquo;m not fullstack FOSS, and&amp;hellip;its the money. I rather like my Silicon Valley, electric car driving, Napa valley wine drinking, private school for the kids, lifestyle. I don&amp;rsquo;t see a good way to keep my life and make FOSS software fulltime.
Here&amp;rsquo;s where I think we stand today:</description></item><item><title>An Employee Morale Scale</title><link>https://ggr.com/an-employee-morale-scale.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/an-employee-morale-scale.html</guid><description>The scale goes from low to high morale. My biggest realization of the past five years, related to morale, is how weak a tool high comp is for driving morale. It can make people very happy for a short time, but after that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much on its own&amp;ndash;the steady state for high comp (alone) is no better than the &amp;lsquo;passively looking&amp;rsquo; step of the scale.
rage quit actively looking passively looking not looking like the work working efficiently like the boss like the coworkers appreciated learning doing the best work of my career respected internally world famous and loved by many</description></item><item><title>Why OpenBSD Is Important To Me</title><link>https://ggr.com/why-openbsd-is-important-to-me.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/why-openbsd-is-important-to-me.html</guid><description>Privacy Matters The freedom to speak in private is essential to democracy. The less private your conversations, the more careful you are about what you say. And being careful leads to less candor, less criticism, and less innovation. Thought and private speech are the breeding ground for new, sometimes controversial ideas. They are how we prototype, think new ideas through, refine them, and get them ready for wider distribution and discussion.</description></item><item><title>Learning Points</title><link>https://ggr.com/learning-points.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/learning-points.html</guid><description>When I joined Mixbook 4 years ago, we were running very large, coarse experiments, where we&amp;rsquo;d spend 3-6 months with 2-4 people building some new feature until we thought it was done, then we&amp;rsquo;d ship. These days, we&amp;rsquo;re a bit leaner, with the same sized teams typically shipping a new experiment within 2-4 weeks. But we don&amp;rsquo;t want to stop there. Lately we&amp;rsquo;ve been talking about how to get it down to 1-2 days per experiment, so we can ship 5 or more per sprint.</description></item><item><title>Winot and My OpenBSD Wifi Adventures</title><link>https://ggr.com/winot-and-my-openbsd-wifi-adventures.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/winot-and-my-openbsd-wifi-adventures.html</guid><description>I run OpenBSD on my main laptop. OpenBSD doesn&amp;rsquo;t come with a Gnome-like Network Manager&amp;hellip;you are on your own to keep your laptop connected to the wifi network, to manage your wifi passwords, etc. The OS makes it easy to connect to the wireless network to be sure&amp;hellip;it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t automate away connecting to a different network at work and home and such.
So I thought, I&amp;rsquo;ll see if anyone has written a tool, and lo and behold, wiconfig is a great start, written in Bourne Shell, so it has no requirements besides OpenBSD itself.</description></item><item><title>The Levels of Engineering Culture</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-levels-of-engineering-culture.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-levels-of-engineering-culture.html</guid><description>Level 1
No process or rules to get in the way! All we do around here is code. It&amp;rsquo;s like 5 years old playing soccer&amp;ndash;everyone runs straight at the ball/latest shiny object. Yay!
Level 2
We have rules/principles/policies/best-practices that we hope (aka think) will make us more productive, i.e. we use CI and CD! All PRs require a code review. 100% test coverage. 20% time (for innovating). We use Scrum/Kanban/Agile. We use planning poker.</description></item><item><title>Mbsync Is Way Faster Than Offlineimap</title><link>https://ggr.com/mbsync-is-way-faster-than-offlineimap.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/mbsync-is-way-faster-than-offlineimap.html</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in the market for a tool that syncs your email over IMAP, I recommend you check out mbsync. On my hefty machine, offlineimap takes many minutes to sync, all the while pegging a CPU at 100% and slowing my machine to a crawl. On the other hand, mbsync sips 5% CPU, finishes much faster, and has no noticeable impact on me while doing other tasks on the same machine.</description></item><item><title>How To Get Vim, Syntastic, Hdevtools, and Stack To Play Nice</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-get-vim-syntastic-hdevtools-and-stack-to-play-nice.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 16:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-get-vim-syntastic-hdevtools-and-stack-to-play-nice.html</guid><description>I was poking around some old Haskell code the other day, when I realized that, since switching to Vim (from Atom) I hadn&amp;rsquo;t setup the necessary plugins in Vim to get syntax checking and such for Haskell.
Seeing as Stack is the new Haskell installer hotness, I installed it and used it to install a bunch of &amp;lsquo;global&amp;rsquo; packages for use with my runghc based scripts. I installed ghc-mod and hlint, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t see any error messages when I messed up the syntax of my Haskell code.</description></item><item><title>A Scrum Master Is a Personal Trainer</title><link>https://ggr.com/a-scrum-master-is-a-personal-trainer.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 03:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/a-scrum-master-is-a-personal-trainer.html</guid><description>Scrum Master is a greatly misunderstood and under appreciated role. On most teams I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered its taken on by the PO or its ignored entirely. I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of this sin myself and when I am not ignoring it, I&amp;rsquo;m playing scrum master across way too many teams, in addition to way too many other duties, so its not done terribly well&amp;hellip;better than nothing I suppose, but better is possible, and, I think, a good investment.</description></item><item><title>On OKRs Requiring Miracles</title><link>https://ggr.com/on-okrs-requiring-miracles.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 19:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/on-okrs-requiring-miracles.html</guid><description>At least one person says you should be thinking you&amp;rsquo;ll need a miracle to pull off your OKRs or they aren&amp;rsquo;t hard enough. I worry that that sort of goal feels too much like gambling to some of the folks I manage, but what&amp;rsquo;s a better bar for OKR difficulty?
Perhaps the goal should be to have objectives that require innovation to succeed&amp;ndash;they need to be daunting enough that you must realize a new, hitherto unused or not yet invented technique to pull them off.</description></item><item><title>Stables and Volatiles: Goals</title><link>https://ggr.com/stables-and-volatiles-goals.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/stables-and-volatiles-goals.html</guid><description>First, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read Stables and Volatiles, go read it and then come back.
I&amp;rsquo;m working on OKRs this week and pondering whether objectives that require &amp;lsquo;just&amp;rsquo; working hard are good enough, or whether our objectives should require a miracle to pull off. Let&amp;rsquo;s say, for the sake of argument, one of our objectives has a 10% chance of success if we work on it at a normal level and a 20% chance of success if we bust our butts and pull off a couple brilliant moves.</description></item><item><title>Some Predictions</title><link>https://ggr.com/some-predictions.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/some-predictions.html</guid><description>By 2020 OpenBSD will be in the top 25 on Distrowatch, because of an increased interest in security. By 2025 US legislation will have shifted the cost of poor software security practices from the consumer to the website/software maker in the US. By 2030 all the mainstream (desktop and server) operating systems will be open source and sponsored/supported by at least one large (for profit) company.</description></item><item><title>Open Interviewing Policy</title><link>https://ggr.com/open-interviewing-policy.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 05:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/open-interviewing-policy.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been interviewing a lot of people in the past few weeks and I&amp;rsquo;ve been wondering how they, you know, get 4 hours off in the middle of the work day to interview. Fake doctor&amp;rsquo;s appointment? Call in sick? No one is paying attention to their office hours? WFH that becomes undocumented PTO? My guess is its not on the record&amp;hellip;they aren&amp;rsquo;t telling their bosses that they are going on interviews.</description></item><item><title>My Security House Boat</title><link>https://ggr.com/my-security-house-boat.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 17:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/my-security-house-boat.html</guid><description>The more I learn about network security, the more trying to secure a Linux server feels like trying to make my house seaworthy&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;d be better off buying something that was built for seaworthiness from the start, like a boat. Security, like seaworthiness, is not a feature that&amp;rsquo;s well suited to being added onto a structure after the fact.
Its not just Linux of course&amp;hellip;with hundreds of thousands of lines of private code in multiple languages and hundreds more libraries bringing in millions of lines of open source code, plus thousands of lines of configuration for machines and services both real and virtual, some ours, some belonging to others (i.</description></item><item><title>Results > Hours</title><link>https://ggr.com/results-hours.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 20:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/results-hours.html</guid><description>When one is trying to increase productivity, there are 3 areas of particular interest:
hours worked tasks completed per hour worked unit of impact per task completed Hours Worked The company culture where you work sets the tone for how many hours you work. Startups tend to value long hours, but plenty of larger companies do too. Adding more hours can be very effective in the short-run, but in the long-run the gains can be elusive, as people shift more of their personal chores and relaxation time into their work hours in order to satisfy the expectation that they are in the office all the time, while still striking the balance that they prefer.</description></item><item><title>Contact Sales</title><link>https://ggr.com/contact-sales.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/contact-sales.html</guid><description>These days it seems that a lot of SaaS tools are offering a free tier, one or more paid tiers, and an &amp;rsquo;enterprise&amp;rsquo; tier, which, unlike the other tiers, has amazing new capabilities but no price. Or rather, the price is &amp;lsquo;contact sales&amp;rsquo;.
That price is too high for me. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to contact sales. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to waste time listening to a pitch, hearing the retail price, hearing what a great deal they&amp;rsquo;re willing to offer me off the retail price because I&amp;rsquo;m special and there&amp;rsquo;s a blue moon tonight.</description></item><item><title>The Scott Bonds Rules of Presentations</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-scott-bonds-rules-of-presentations.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 16:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-scott-bonds-rules-of-presentations.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve got another deck to put together. Seems like a good time to write down the Scott Bonds Rules of Presentations:
entertain your audience do not forget to make your point do not put text on your slides Entertain Your Audience This is the first rule because its the most important. When you entertain your audience, you make them into better listeners. They are more engaged, more open minded, and more likely to absorb and retain your message.</description></item><item><title>Background Processes On the Brain</title><link>https://ggr.com/background-processes-on-the-brain.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/background-processes-on-the-brain.html</guid><description>When I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of a hard thought problem (i.e. coding) and I interrupt my work on the thought problem to do something else, I find it difficult to concentrate on the something else. I think my brain is still working on the hard thought problem in the background, sort of like a CPU that&amp;rsquo;s still processing a different job&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m not fully available to focus on the dinner party or new project at hand.</description></item><item><title>Burst > Drip For iTunes Review Reminders</title><link>https://ggr.com/burst-drip-for-itunes-review-reminders.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/burst-drip-for-itunes-review-reminders.html</guid><description>We email our customers after they receive their first Mosaic, asking them to submit a review to the iTunes (or Google Play) store. We used to send each email a few days after their package arrived, but we discovered that when we save up a whole bunch of the reminders, say a month&amp;rsquo;s worth, and send them all at once, it leads to more reviews, even though its the exact same number of people contacted, and for some people more time has lapsed between their order and the email.</description></item><item><title>How To Screen Resumes For 'A' Players</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-screen-resumes-for-a-players.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 21:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-screen-resumes-for-a-players.html</guid><description>Recently I was asked how I figure out whether the resume I&amp;rsquo;m looking at belongs to an &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; player or someone of a lesser grade. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I said:
A&amp;rsquo;s tend to list accomplishments, and they tend to have accomplishments that really stand out, even in their hobbies. You see stuff like 1st place in the Chicago Assembler Speed Competition on A engineers&amp;rsquo; resumes. Designers point to a portfolio that you look at and go &amp;lsquo;wow&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>How To Run an Arch Linux (Qemu) Guest On an OpenBSD Host</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-run-an-arch-linux-qemu-guest-on-an-openbsd-host.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 20:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-run-an-arch-linux-qemu-guest-on-an-openbsd-host.html</guid><description>The main stumbling block I had to overcome to get various flavors of Linux to install as a guest OS on a Qemu instance, running on an OpenBSD source, was to disable APIC, not be confused with ACPI.
With Arch Linux you do this:
boot the Arch Linux CD (in your Qemu guest) press tab to config the boot command add a space and then &amp;rsquo;noapic&amp;rsquo; to the boot command press Enter to boot install Arch Linux on your Qemu guest hard drive add the &amp;rsquo;noapic&amp;rsquo; parameter to boot command in your boot config, e.</description></item><item><title>Wishlist Upgraded</title><link>https://ggr.com/wishlist-upgraded.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 23:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/wishlist-upgraded.html</guid><description>I moved my wishlist from Amazon to CamelCamelCamel. I use my wishlist mostly as a check on my impulses&amp;ndash;when I want something I add it to the wishlist instead of buying it. It feels almost as satisfying and I haven&amp;rsquo;t spent any money. Every so often I go through my wishlist to see if I still want the stuff on there. About 3/4 of the stuff gets eliminated, the rest I eventually buy.</description></item><item><title>How To Set the Default App For Opening a Directory Under OpenBSD + Gnome 3</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-set-the-default-app-for-opening-a-directory-under-openbsd--gnome-3.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 01:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-set-the-default-app-for-opening-a-directory-under-openbsd--gnome-3.html</guid><description>Sometimes you want &amp;lsquo;open .&amp;rsquo; to open a directory in your favorite GUI file manager, not EasyTag. Sometimes you wonder how EasyTag ever come to be the default app for opening a folder. Sometimes you do this:
$ xdg-mime query filetype . inode/directory $ xdg-mime query default inode/directory easytag.desktop $ xdg-mime default nautilus.desktop inode/directory $ xdg-mime query default inode/directory nautilus.desktop $ open . You&amp;rsquo;re welcome.</description></item><item><title>Who Is Rich</title><link>https://ggr.com/who-is-rich.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/who-is-rich.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering Hilary Clinton&amp;rsquo;s dead brokeness, what she meant, and what it means to be rich. Or rather, what a (more) useful definition might be&amp;ndash;one that could help predict (political) views and behaviors.
Scott&amp;rsquo;s definition of &amp;lsquo;rich&amp;rsquo; top 1% of income owns job and/or almost no chance of being fired and/or the loss of income from being fired would not have a material impact on their lifestyle The rich and/or powerful own the system, they are root, and for them the system (the government, the law, the dominant corporations) is extremely valuable and something to be preserved and exploited for their benefit.</description></item><item><title>The AWSnow Story</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-awsnow-story.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 17:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-awsnow-story.html</guid><description>A few weeks ago we moved Mixbook.com ($25M/year) off our old, bare-metal ISP and onto AWS. After months of preparation we only needed a few hours of maintenance downtime for the final step of the move, and everything before, during, and after went smoothly. That&amp;rsquo;s due (especially) to the fine work of the Mixbook DevOps Team: Robert Butler, Denis Barushev&amp;ndash;they overcame a number of interesting and unexpected obstacles along the way, all of which they are chronicling, starting with their first blog post yesterday.</description></item><item><title>Montage Unleashed</title><link>https://ggr.com/montage-unleashed.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 14:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/montage-unleashed.html</guid><description>Montage is now live and its 10x easier1 to make a great photo book with Montage than any other way ever2. If you&amp;rsquo;ve made a photo book before, you&amp;rsquo;re uniquely qualified to notice the (stark) contrast between Montage and the other photo book making web apps out there. If you&amp;rsquo;ve never made a photo book before because it looked like it was going to be a chore, you should take Montage for a spin, its super easy&amp;hellip;fun even.</description></item><item><title>Hack Nights at Mixbook</title><link>https://ggr.com/hack-nights-at-mixbook.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 08:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/hack-nights-at-mixbook.html</guid><description>I organized my first hack night recently. It was a lot of fun, Dan Schultz talked about why Dart is awesome, I met some talented engineers, and Fast Company mentioned our hack night ways in their recent coverage of hackathons.</description></item><item><title>Mosaic for Android</title><link>https://ggr.com/mosaic-for-android.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 13:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/mosaic-for-android.html</guid><description>We just launched the Android version of Mosaic. Its pretty much the easiest way to make an awesome photo book. Besides the iOS version.</description></item><item><title>Montage Teaser</title><link>https://ggr.com/montage-teaser.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 12:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/montage-teaser.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m excited to pull the curtain back a bit on Montage. Montage is the second salvo (after Mosaic) in our war on mediocre photo books. We spent a year crafting a simple UI that makes it easy to create fantastic looking books. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun&amp;ndash;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to show it off. You can signup for the closed beta to get an early look.</description></item><item><title>The Big Unplug</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-big-unplug.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 09:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-big-unplug.html</guid><description>I posted this on my personal Facebook account yesterday morning:
I want to see what life is like without a (personal) Facebook account for a while. Seems the teenagers are doing fine (http://mashable.com/2013/08/11/teens-facebook/). I&amp;rsquo;m going to nuke my account (from orbit) this evening (it&amp;rsquo;s the only way to be sure). You can find me at https://ggr.com/ and scott@ggr.com. See you on the other side!
It was funny to see everyone&amp;rsquo;s responses.</description></item><item><title>IAmA</title><link>https://ggr.com/iama.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 16:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/iama.html</guid><description>I am a hipster. That is all.</description></item><item><title>Opting Out</title><link>https://ggr.com/opting-out.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/opting-out.html</guid><description>A government with easy access to all the public and private information of its people, that collects this information against their wishes, that makes them more vulnerable to harm in order to maintain their access, and then lies in order to cover up their actions is fundamentally incompatible with American democracy. The freedom to live, speak, and think in private, without worrying how a government agent might view our thoughts or try to use them against us, is liberty.</description></item><item><title>Best Milkshake</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-milkshake.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 10:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-milkshake.html</guid><description>Get the Swiss milk chocolate milk shake from Fentons. Get the jumbo, what&amp;rsquo;s another thousand calories? You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it. Ok, maybe you will. But still&amp;hellip;its so, so good.
Updated on October 21st, 2013
Added a picture. It required some field work.</description></item><item><title>The Coming War for Design Talent</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-coming-war-for-design-talent.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 19:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-coming-war-for-design-talent.html</guid><description>While the war rages on for software engineers, I can&amp;rsquo;t help wondering when UX, interaction designers, and product managers are going to have their turn. For a lot of software projects adding a rockstar engineer can boost productivity by more than their substantial individual contribution, but adding a rockstar designer can double a team&amp;rsquo;s output.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say, for the sake of argument, that 1 in 5 of a good designer&amp;rsquo;s decisions are adding value a year after they are released; let&amp;rsquo;s say a rockstar achieves 2 in 5.</description></item><item><title>Two Kinds of Engineering Leader</title><link>https://ggr.com/two-kinds-of-engineering-leader.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/two-kinds-of-engineering-leader.html</guid><description>When a software company is searching for a new CTO or VP of Engineering, they tend to look for either a Chief of Surgery or a Head Coach. Hiring the right (or wrong) one can mean the difference between success and failure as a company. Knowing which you are can help you choose the right opportunity.
The Chief of Surgery is one of the best, if not the best, software engineer at the company.</description></item><item><title>Natural: a ruby gem for natural language search</title><link>https://ggr.com/natural-a-ruby-gem-for-natural-language-search.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2012 10:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/natural-a-ruby-gem-for-natural-language-search.html</guid><description>When I started work on DishFu.com (one of my code playgrounds&amp;hellip;its something like Yelp) a couple years ago I wanted to support natural language search so that, instead of clicking lots of checkboxes to search for the best burrito in my zip code, I could just ask &amp;ldquo;what is the best burrito near me&amp;rdquo; and get the answer. At the time (and even now) I didn&amp;rsquo;t find a ruby library that made this easy to do, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take a stab at it.</description></item><item><title>How to Fix Dropouts and Cutting Out When Using AirTunes on your Airport Express</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-fix-dropouts-and-cutting-out-when-using-airtunes-on-your-airport-express.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 13:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-fix-dropouts-and-cutting-out-when-using-airtunes-on-your-airport-express.html</guid><description>For months I struggled with frequent audio dropouts while connecting to stereo through my Airport Express from my Mac laptop. My connection was strong (5/5 bars on wifi) but I still had dropouts. I tried every manner of fix and none was satisfactory. Until now. I seem to have stumbled on a solution and its one I had not read about before. No doubt it won&amp;rsquo;t work for everyone because of the many different possible causes for bad connectivity to your AirTunes device of choice.</description></item><item><title>How to Restart PostgreSQL While Developing a Rails App</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-restart-postgresql-while-developing-a-rails-app.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-restart-postgresql-while-developing-a-rails-app.html</guid><description>While developing a Rails apps using PostgreSQL (unlike MySQL) I often run out of db connections and see errors like
and when I do, my Rails app stops working. Restarting Postgres fixing the problem, but it was harder to restart postgres that I expected. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I do it.
To restart PostgreSQL I added a function to my ~/.bash_profile file:
After saving and restarting Terminal, running &amp;lsquo;pgr&amp;rsquo; will find all the postgres process and kill them.</description></item><item><title>How to Automatically Connect and Stay Connected to a Network Drive on OS X</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-automatically-connect-and-stay-connected-to-a-network-drive-on-os-x.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 18:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-automatically-connect-and-stay-connected-to-a-network-drive-on-os-x.html</guid><description>I keep my music and my photos on a server at home. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m home I want all of my shares to be accessible automatically so I can launch iTunes and iPhoto without needing to do anything first (i.e. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to click anything to mount the drives before I start listening to Adagio for Tron). Here&amp;rsquo;s how I pulled it off.
The short version: I run a script that checks whether any mounts are missing and if possible it restores them.</description></item><item><title>Pandora vs Last.fm</title><link>https://ggr.com/pandora-vs-last.fm.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2010 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/pandora-vs-last.fm.html</guid><description>They&amp;rsquo;re both good, but Last.fm wins. How can this be? Last.fm&amp;rsquo;s amazing powers are put on display after the break.
Last.fm can perform these amazing tricks:
** Tag (and Multitag) radio**. If you want to listen to &amp;lsquo;piano&amp;rsquo; music on Pandora, you have to select a song or artist that exemplifies &amp;lsquo;piano&amp;rsquo;, then vote up/down songs until Pandora figures out what you want. On Last.fm, you can simply tell it to play a radio station made up of music that has the &amp;lsquo;piano&amp;rsquo; tag.</description></item><item><title>How To Post Your Dynamic Internal IP To DynDNS From Your Windows Machine</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-post-your-dynamic-internal-ip-to-dyndns-from-your-windows-machine.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-post-your-dynamic-internal-ip-to-dyndns-from-your-windows-machine.html</guid><description>I looked around for an easier way to post an internal IP to DynDNS, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t find one. Scripting to the rescue.
If you have a paid account at DynDNS (may work for free ones too, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure), you can update a DNS entry by hitting a URL like this:
So, to update your DNS entry, you just need to get your IP alone in a variable that a batch file can use, then setup a task to request that URL every so often.</description></item><item><title>How To Get Your IP and ONLY Your IP in Windows</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-get-your-ip-and-only-your-ip-in-windows.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-get-your-ip-and-only-your-ip-in-windows.html</guid><description>Sometimes you need to know your Windows machine&amp;rsquo;s IP. For example, if you would like to update your dynamic DNS entry from a script file. Here&amp;rsquo;s a hack that gets the job done.
This is from someone good with windows scripts, updated with some extra &amp;lsquo;shifts&amp;rsquo; to get it to work under XP. Check out the link for an explanation. Save this in a batch file, I call mine &amp;lsquo;GetIP.</description></item><item><title>How To Scan For Viruses in Your Email When Using Apple Mail</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-scan-for-viruses-in-your-email-when-using-apple-mail.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-scan-for-viruses-in-your-email-when-using-apple-mail.html</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s more than way to go about it, but I prefer using the open source ClamAV and a script that runs to scan each email as it comes in.
Setup ClamAV
Install ClamAV. I used MacPorts to install it: sudo port install clamav Make sure all the ClamAV binaries are in your PATH. Chances are if you&amp;rsquo;re using MacPorts, you&amp;rsquo;ve already taken care of that. Configure freshclam and clamd. Since I used MacPorts to install ClamAV, this consisted of&amp;hellip; rename the example conf files in /opt/local/etc: mv example-freshclam.</description></item><item><title>How To Use Facebook Open Streams With Facebooker</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-use-facebook-open-streams-with-facebooker.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-use-facebook-open-streams-with-facebooker.html</guid><description>I would like my Facebook Connect app to publish stories to my users&amp;rsquo; Facebook news stream. I went looking for how do this with Facebooker and figured out an answer.
The old way of doing this, and the one built into Facebooker, is to publish a user action. There are two limitations of the old way: 1: you need a valid session_key (so, the user must be logged in); 2: you may only send up to 10 messages per day (without special permissions from the user).</description></item><item><title>How To Include a Gem's Rake Tasks in Your Rails App</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-include-a-gems-rake-tasks-in-your-rails-app.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2009 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-include-a-gems-rake-tasks-in-your-rails-app.html</guid><description>Rake tasks contained in a gem are not automatically available to a rails app that requires the gem. Whether that&amp;rsquo;s the right way to do things is under debate, but in the mean time there are a couple workarounds.
Option #1: Use the gem as a plugin instead. Files that match the following pattern are automatically pulled in, so you&amp;rsquo;re good to go:
Option #2: Create a ruby file that loads the gem&amp;rsquo;s tasks, then require the ruby file you made in your rail app&amp;rsquo;s Rakefile.</description></item><item><title>How To Permit A Blank Email Field With AuthLogic</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-permit-a-blank-email-field-with-authlogic.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 12:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-permit-a-blank-email-field-with-authlogic.html</guid><description>I too ran into some trouble before discovering that my beloved AuthLogic is validating my email field. The validation is a good thing overall, but I want to support blank email addresses as well as properly formatted ones.
It&amp;rsquo;s all in the AuthLogic docs of course, but if I can save you a few minutes of hunting around, that&amp;rsquo;s all good:</description></item><item><title>How To Predict The Future Using Excel</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-predict-the-future-using-excel.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 16:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-predict-the-future-using-excel.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to run out of hard drive space at some point. I&amp;rsquo;ve got 1.5TB drives in my Drobo right now, I wonder when the 3TB drives will come out so I can just upgrade them in place for double the capacity&amp;hellip;
First I looked up when each of the last several capacity jumps were announced. Google news did the trick: 500MB in 2005, 1TB in 2007, 1.5TB in 2008, 2TB in 2009.</description></item><item><title>How To Monitor Amazon For Price Drops</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-monitor-amazon-for-price-drops.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 13:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-monitor-amazon-for-price-drops.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to run out of hard drive space at some point. I&amp;rsquo;ve got 1.5TB drives in my Drobo right now, I wonder when the 3TB drives will come out so I can just upgrade them in place for double the capacity&amp;hellip;
First I looked up when each of the last several capacity jumps were announced. Google news did the trick: 500MB in 2005, 1TB in 2007, 1.5TB in 2008, 2TB in 2009.</description></item><item><title>How to Increase Traffic to Your Site By Optimizing For Search Engines</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-increase-traffic-to-your-site-by-optimizing-for-search-engines.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-increase-traffic-to-your-site-by-optimizing-for-search-engines.html</guid><description>Want more traffic from your friendly neighborhood search engine to your site? Here are some of the Search Engine Optimization (SEO) tricks I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up along the way.
Rule #1: make it easy for the search engines to see and understand your content
make as much content visible to users that are not logged in as you can&amp;ndash;search engines cannot login and they will not index any content that is behind a login barrier use descriptive names for everything, including your domains, paths, pages, and assets, i.</description></item><item><title>Best Ribs</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-ribs.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 09:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-ribs.html</guid><description>The meat falls off the bone. They taste like ribs should taste. And I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who thinks so.</description></item><item><title>Best Chicken Maharaja</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-chicken-maharaja.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-chicken-maharaja.html</guid><description>Sneha rolls buffet style, all you can eat. All I can eat when I go is the Chicken Maharaja.</description></item><item><title>Best Grape Juice</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-grape-juice.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 12:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-grape-juice.html</guid><description>Why should wine get all the good grapes? I buy this stuff by the case when I&amp;rsquo;m in Sonoma and it still goes fast.</description></item><item><title>Best Deep Dish Pizza</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-deep-dish-pizza.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-deep-dish-pizza.html</guid><description>Try the Chicken Pizza and order a large so you can take some home.</description></item><item><title>Best Pastrami Sandwich</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-pastrami-sandwich.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-pastrami-sandwich.html</guid><description>The Refuge in San Carlos, CA makes their pastrami in-house and its amazing. You&amp;rsquo;ll wonder how you ever put up with the conventional, mass-produced pastrami you get pretty much everywhere else.</description></item><item><title>How To Keep Your Cables Untangled While You Use Them</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-keep-your-cables-untangled-while-you-use-them.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 17:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-keep-your-cables-untangled-while-you-use-them.html</guid><description>The mess of cables behind your computer sure doesn&amp;rsquo;t look safe. And this probably won&amp;rsquo;t make it any safer, but it sure makes it easier to see what&amp;rsquo;s going on. It&amp;rsquo;s all about taking up the slack.</description></item><item><title>How To Keep Your Cables Untangled While You Store Them</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-keep-your-cables-untangled-while-you-store-them.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 17:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-keep-your-cables-untangled-while-you-store-them.html</guid><description>Ziploc freezer bags help keep your cables untangled and easy to sort through. There&amp;rsquo;s even space for you to write the date when your cable goes bad, in case you are good at predicting that sort of thing.</description></item><item><title>How To Create a Good Looking Graph (The Easy Way)</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-create-a-good-looking-graph-the-easy-way.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2009 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-create-a-good-looking-graph-the-easy-way.html</guid><description>There comes a time in every professional&amp;rsquo;s career when they need a graph. Maybe they need to illustrate a usability scale, maybe its something else. Fortunately, the developers at Omni are focused on making it stupid-easy to make graphs&amp;ndash;no need to bust open Excel, dust off any math skills, or crack open a book on Photoshop to make the graph you need.
watch the OmniGraphSketcher walkthrough video</description></item><item><title>A Usability Scale</title><link>https://ggr.com/a-usability-scale.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 11:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/a-usability-scale.html</guid><description>Many usability professionals focus on, well, usability. But there&amp;rsquo;s more to usability than an intuitive interface. The best stuff in our lives are pleasant, fun, even habit forming.
The Scott Bonds Usability Scale
Unusable. Not useful or usable in any sense. Functional. Very useful, but requires instruction (manual, training, demo, etc) before a desired feature is understood. Usable. Intuitive, requires little instruction before the user is proficient. Pleasant. Using it is satisfying and enjoyable.</description></item><item><title>How To Protect Your Pockets From Your Keys</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-protect-your-pockets-from-your-keys.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-protect-your-pockets-from-your-keys.html</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re tired of your keychain poking holes in your pockets you may want to consider investing in some protection.</description></item><item><title>How To Use Your iPhone To Record Notes</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-use-your-iphone-to-record-notes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-use-your-iphone-to-record-notes.html</guid><description>In the &amp;rsquo;80s all the cool executive-type people carried around small tape recorders for capturing ideas any time they had them. Today we can record notes in &amp;rsquo;00s style and have them sent straight to our email. Turns out its pretty handy to be able to quickly taking notes anytime, anywhere. You know&amp;hellip;until you can afford a personal assistant like the really cool &amp;rsquo;80s execs.
Directions leading to note recording bliss:</description></item><item><title>How To Subscribe To a Website</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-subscribe-to-a-website.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 21:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-subscribe-to-a-website.html</guid><description>WHAT IF you could subscribe to your favorite websites and automatically be sent any new articles they post instead of checking back a couple times a day or week to see if there is anything new? Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be great? The future is now! Head over to Google Reader, sign up for an account, then click the &amp;lsquo;add subscription&amp;rsquo; button. Type in the URL of the website you want to subscribe to and if it supports subscriptions (aka RSS) you&amp;rsquo;ll be reading their articles in seconds.</description></item><item><title>How To Create Flickr-Style Mouseover Notes On a Picture</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-create-flickr-style-mouseover-notes-on-a-picture.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 17:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-create-flickr-style-mouseover-notes-on-a-picture.html</guid><description>While you were reading the post about how to ship a used book, you may have found yourself strangely compelled to hover your mouse over the cool, image hotspot mouseover hover caption thingies on the picture of shipping supplies. Perhaps you wondered how you too could harness the power of such hotspots on your own blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll let you in on the secret.</description></item><item><title>How To Ship a Used Book</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-ship-a-used-book.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-ship-a-used-book.html</guid><description>So you sold your used book on Amazon, you&amp;rsquo;re basking in the glow of your success, and then it dawns on you that the buyer is expecting you to send them the book.
No worries, here&amp;rsquo;s how you do it: 1) print the packing slip from Amazon; 2) put the book in a padded envelope with the packing slip; 3) address the package to the buyer; 4) weigh the package; 5) look up the postage; 6) put the right postage on there; 7) write &amp;lsquo;media mail&amp;rsquo; beneath the stamps on the package;8) stop by your local post office and drop it off in person.</description></item><item><title>How To Sell a Used Book</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-sell-a-used-book.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-sell-a-used-book.html</guid><description>They do look good on your bookshelf, but are you really ever going to read them again? You can free up space in your home, save the environment, and spread knowledge throughout the world by getting that book off your shelf into the hands of an eager reader.
One of the easiest ways is through Amazon:&amp;ndash;do a search for your book, click on the &amp;lsquo;sell yours here&amp;rsquo; button, and you&amp;rsquo;re on your way.</description></item><item><title>Passage Moved Me</title><link>https://ggr.com/passage-moved-me.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2009 10:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/passage-moved-me.html</guid><description>Not knowing what to expect, I played Passage and found myself moved (not in the U-Haul sense, the other moved)&amp;hellip;something no other video game has accomplished before or since. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like much, but there&amp;rsquo;s real Art in there.</description></item><item><title>Braid Is a Beautiful Game</title><link>https://ggr.com/braid-is-a-beautiful-game.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 00:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/braid-is-a-beautiful-game.html</guid><description>You had me at hello. &amp;ndash;Wait&amp;hellip;I mean: you had me at the start up screen. &amp;ndash;Braid would make a great screensaver, it&amp;rsquo;s that neat to look at (and listen to). And for those who like side-scrollers, there&amp;rsquo;s a fun, innovative game in there too. The (free) demo is worth the price of admission and then some.</description></item><item><title>How To Get More Outlet Space</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-get-more-outlet-space.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 16:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-get-more-outlet-space.html</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s easy to run out of power outlets with all the must-have gadgets in our lives. Some self-important power adapters sprawl over 2 or more outlets, luxuriating without a thought for the other devices. Huge, Dubai inspired, power strips are one way to find more space, but these&amp;ndash;plug extenders leverage your existing power strip to offer each of your diva adapters their own luxury suite. &amp;ndash;Just don&amp;rsquo;t tell them that you only paid $9 for a pack of 3 (before tax+shipping), let them think you splurged.</description></item><item><title>Best Burrito</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-burrito.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-burrito.html</guid><description>They won&amp;rsquo;t be serving these at the Ritz Carlton any time soon, but don&amp;rsquo;t let it&amp;rsquo;s commonplace appearance fool you. &amp;ndash;Chavez Supermarket makes a&amp;ndash;tasty&amp;ndash;Super Carnitas Burrito packed with lots of pork and other burrito essentials. &amp;ndash;But if that&amp;rsquo;s not fancy enough for you, you can always ask for it &amp;lsquo;Au Jus&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Best Spring Rolls Recipe</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-spring-rolls-recipe.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 13:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-spring-rolls-recipe.html</guid><description>Made&amp;ndash;spring rolls&amp;ndash;this weekend and they were good. &amp;ndash;BTW, you only need about 1/4 of the dipping sauce they suggest for the amount of spring roll generated.</description></item><item><title>Best Broccoli Soup Recipe</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-broccoli-soup-recipe.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 08:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-broccoli-soup-recipe.html</guid><description>Don&amp;rsquo;t like broccoli? &amp;ndash;Me neither. &amp;ndash;But hold on to your soup bowls, this is a way to eat it that tastes pretty good.
Take a pound or so of broccoli. &amp;ndash;Boil it until tender. &amp;ndash;Throw it in a blender, add a 1/2 cup water, 1/2 cup grape seed oil, and a 1/2 teaspoon of salt. &amp;ndash;Blend until smooth. &amp;ndash;Add more oil and water in the same proportions until it flows.</description></item><item><title>Best Brussels Sprouts Recipe</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-brussels-sprouts-recipe.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-brussels-sprouts-recipe.html</guid><description>I have never liked brussel sprouts, in fact I was generally vegetable averse growing up. It turns out it wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely the vegetables&amp;rsquo; fault.
This easy recipe can transform brussel sprouts from being in the dreaded &amp;rsquo;tastes like it&amp;rsquo;s good for you&amp;rsquo; category to the &amp;lsquo;wow, can I have some more&amp;rsquo; category while remaining very healthy.Michele Bonds&amp;rsquo; Brussel SproutsBuy as many brussel sprouts as you want to eatCut them in half lengthwise, so that the stem is cut in halfFry them, flat side down over medium heat in grapeseed or olive oilOnce they are a crispy brown, remove them from the heatAdd salt to taste.</description></item><item><title>Mashed Potatoes</title><link>https://ggr.com/mashed-potatoes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/mashed-potatoes.html</guid><description>Makes about 12 servings.
5 pounds golden potatoes 1 package Philadelphia Cream Cheese 1 pint sour cream 0.5 cups milk 0.5 stick unsalted butter 3 medium size cloves of garlic 2 teaspoons salt 3 teaspoons white pepper optional: horseradish sauce Peel potatoes and add to a large pot. Fill pot with enough water to cover potatoes. Boil for 40 minutes then drain water. Mash potatoes with a potato ricer. Add cream cheese, milk, sour cream, butter, salt, and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Best Ice Cream</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-ice-cream.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2006 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-ice-cream.html</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s Hagen Daz, Dryers, and a whole lot of other companies making ice cream. Coldstone&amp;rsquo;s the latest craze and gelato has enjoyed a recent surge in the Berkeley, CA area. But they&amp;rsquo;re all pretenders to the Double Rainbow throne.
Double Rainbow makes the best ice cream I&amp;rsquo;ve had outside of homemade. Gelato&amp;rsquo;s great and all, but I&amp;rsquo;ll take a scoop of DR over any gelato I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had as well. Try the chocolate chip.</description></item><item><title>Barley Soup</title><link>https://ggr.com/barley-soup.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 23:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/barley-soup.html</guid><description>Makes about 8 servings of soup.
3 leg-and-thighs of chicken 1.5 cups pearl barley 2 carrots 2 stalks of celery 0.5 white onion salt pepper Wash chicken. Put chicken into a large pot. Add water to pot until chicken is covered. Wash barley and add to pot. Grate onion and add to pot. Add 2 teaspoons salt.
Simmer for 1 hour. Cut carrots and celery into 0.25 inch thick pieces and add to soup.</description></item><item><title>Best Hamburger</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-hamburger.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2006 23:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-hamburger.html</guid><description>This is old hat to California natives, but if you haven&amp;rsquo;t visited in say, the last 15 years, you may not have heard of In-N-Out. It&amp;rsquo;s a family owned chain that&amp;rsquo;s known for it&amp;rsquo;s simple menu, good service, and excellent hamburgers (the fries are really good too).
I&amp;rsquo;ve had burgers at joints across the country, from McDonald&amp;rsquo;s to mom-and-pop burger stands and I always come back to In-N-Out. What sets In-N-Out apart from most fast food restaurants are their quality, health conscious ingredients.</description></item><item><title>Best Seafood Pasta</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-seafood-pasta.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 16:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-seafood-pasta.html</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s not as good as homemade but Michelangelo&amp;rsquo;s has had the same special for 5 years: linguini with baby clams, shrimp, and mussels; and it&amp;rsquo;s really good.
The place has a fun atmosphere, there&amp;rsquo;s rarely a long wait, and they serve gummy bears for desert. Oh, and if there is a wait, ask them to break you off a chunk of parmesan from their 20 lb. block of cheese or grab some yourself, it&amp;rsquo;s usually near the entrance.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti Sauce</title><link>https://ggr.com/spaghetti-sauce.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/spaghetti-sauce.html</guid><description>Get a big pot. Chop a large yellow onion and fry it in grape seed oil in the pot until they are translucent, about 3 minutes. Add 1 lb of ground beef to the onions and cook until the meat is brown, about 2 minutes. Add 2x 1 quart cans of Italian tomatoes in basil (they look like tubes rather than spheres). Chop the tomatoes you just put in into 2 or 3 pieces each.</description></item><item><title>Best Fish and Chips</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-fish-and-chips.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 13:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-fish-and-chips.html</guid><description>My girlfriend introduced me to this joint last time we were in Malibu&amp;ndash;I ordered a 3 piece fish and chips and Malibu Seafood gave me the biggest chunks of fried fish I&amp;rsquo;d ever seen.
I&amp;rsquo;m accustom to the frozen variety and the bar food variety of fish and chips, and let me tell you this is different. They take good, fresh, gourmet quality fish and fry it up. Add some tartar sauce and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to go.</description></item><item><title>Best Corned Beef Hash</title><link>https://ggr.com/best-corned-beef-hash.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 13:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/best-corned-beef-hash.html</guid><description>Whenever I visit my family in the LA area I try to find my way to Billy&amp;rsquo;s in Glendale for an order of corned beef hashand an order of hash brown potatoes (with plenty of ketchup). Billy&amp;rsquo;s makes their own corned beef hash and it&amp;rsquo;s excellent. I have tried corned beef hash at many other restaurants trying to find something this good closer to my home in San Francisco; I&amp;rsquo;ve searched high and low, but I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to find a comparable hash.</description></item><item><title>Spanish Sweet Bread</title><link>https://ggr.com/spanish-sweet-bread.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/spanish-sweet-bread.html</guid><description>Bread Machine Variant Makes 1 loaf. This method is way easier than the original, which you can find right after this one.
0.75 cup whole milk 2 eggs, beaten 0.5 teaspoon lemon extract 0.5 teaspoon vanilla extract 500 grams bread flour / 3.5 cups 0.5 cups sugar 0.25 teaspoon salt 1 stick butter 1 package of yeast 0.75 cups golden raisins Put all the ingredients, up to and including the butter, into the bread maker, in the order they are listed.</description></item><item><title>Revamp On The Way</title><link>https://ggr.com/revamp-on-the-way.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2004 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/revamp-on-the-way.html</guid><description>Hey everyone&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of reworking the site. So theres not much to see at the moment, as you can see. ;) More to come&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Fantasy Stock Market For Blogs</title><link>https://ggr.com/fantasy-stock-market-for-blogs.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2004 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/fantasy-stock-market-for-blogs.html</guid><description>This is sort of random.</description></item><item><title>My Theory On Tetris</title><link>https://ggr.com/my-theory-on-tetris.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2004 23:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/my-theory-on-tetris.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done my share of dabbling in neurobiology literature and within said literature is information about our eyes. We dont perceive the world as a raw stream of color and brightness&amp;ndash;we see objects that retain their integrity even as we turn our heads or they move around. Anyone whos written AI visual navigation/targeting systems can attest to what an impressive ability this is.
Our eyes and brain dont do this in one step.</description></item><item><title>The Problem With Mr. Evil</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-problem-with-mr.-evil.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2004 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-problem-with-mr.-evil.html</guid><description>Maybe its just me, but I&amp;rsquo;m getting tired off all the comic book evil that we have in games these days. Whether youre playing KotOR or Fable youll notice that when you decide to veer to the dark side of the force its pretty obvious that what you are doing is evil . That is to say comic book evil&amp;ndash;no grays here, pretty much anyone on the planet would judge the evil action as such.</description></item><item><title>The Hollywood Eye</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-hollywood-eye.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2004 22:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-hollywood-eye.html</guid><description>While chowing down on workday lunches I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading The Hollywood Eye. It&amp;rsquo;s a book about what makes films enjoyable, moving, and generally impactful. Actually it&amp;rsquo;s the observations about what doesn&amp;rsquo;t work and why is the part most applicable to games&amp;ndash;there are a lot of ways to take the player out of the game just as there are ways to take the viewer out of a movie. Game designers have the added complication of satisfying the desires of the player without complete control over what happens.</description></item><item><title>The Key Programming Skill: Finishing</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-key-programming-skill-finishing.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2004 10:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-key-programming-skill-finishing.html</guid><description>Scott Writes:
I just graduated from Cal Poly with a Computer Engineering Bachelors degree. I took a computer graphics course using java3d which I really enjoyed. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to figure out what Id need to do to be attractive to Electronic Arts as a game programmer . I&amp;rsquo;ve been entertaining getting a masters degree in computer graphics at UC Davis, but am thinking maybe there is more straight forward approach. I commend you on the amount of networking you did to get into the company.</description></item><item><title>EA University Program</title><link>https://ggr.com/ea-university-program.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2004 10:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/ea-university-program.html</guid><description>Martijn Writes:
I&amp;rsquo;m sure you probably are already aware of this, but just in case you missed out on it. It&amp;rsquo;s the EA University Programme, i think a lot of your readers would be interested in this link.
Updated on October 11th, 2013
Removed the link to Martijn&amp;rsquo;s email. Remove the link to the EA University Programme, that page no longer exists.</description></item><item><title>From Psychology To Games</title><link>https://ggr.com/from-psychology-to-games.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2004 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/from-psychology-to-games.html</guid><description>Todd Writes:
Hi. I&amp;rsquo;m considering changing careers but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about the best way to do it. After graduating a few years ago with a doctorate in clinical psychology, I obtained a faculty position at a major university, where I now work as a clinician and researcher . While I have been successful thus far in my area of study, I have made a decision to pursue a career in game design and development.</description></item><item><title>Interships Breakdown</title><link>https://ggr.com/interships-breakdown.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2004 10:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/interships-breakdown.html</guid><description>James Writes:
[For internships at EA] I noticed that the applicant pool consists of about 720 students, and they only take in around 60. I had a question as to where most of these internship applications and opportunities fall . And also if 720 or so applicants consist of both high school students, current college students, and college grads.or just grads. Also, if you could tell me how many internships do they offer in the Marketing/PR department for the summer.</description></item><item><title>No More Comments</title><link>https://ggr.com/no-more-comments.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2004 08:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/no-more-comments.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to eliminate comments from this site &amp;lsquo;cause 99% of the stuff I was getting was SPAM and of the 1% of legitimate stuff about 90% of it was a question that is better suited to email than to commenting on a particular post.</description></item><item><title>Advice For an Interview</title><link>https://ggr.com/advice-for-an-interview.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2004 20:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/advice-for-an-interview.html</guid><description>Eric Writes:
I am interviewing for a Desktop Support position on Monday for EA Tiburon in Orlando. Is there any advice you can give me? I&amp;rsquo;ve also been told there will be a written technical assessment. I was looking at your game design questionaire and was wondering if it would reflect any of those kinds of questions.
My Reply:
I&amp;rsquo;ve never had a technical assessment since I haven&amp;rsquo;t applied for a position where it would be appropriate.</description></item><item><title>Programming vs Art Production</title><link>https://ggr.com/programming-vs-art-production.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2004 16:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/programming-vs-art-production.html</guid><description>Jeff Writes:
I hope you know someone in the Arts/Textures/Graphics department at EA that can answer a question for me. I currently attend Ohio State where I am studying Computer Science and Engineering. During the course of my major (which I begin in less than a month), I will have the opportunity to take a number of graphics courses, though all of these courses are centered in building graphics through the C language, at least from what I&amp;rsquo;ve been told.</description></item><item><title>Making Xbox Games At Home</title><link>https://ggr.com/making-xbox-games-at-home.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2004 15:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/making-xbox-games-at-home.html</guid><description>Stephan Writes:
hi my name is stephan i want to know if it is possible for me to make my own xbox videogames on my computer if so what software do i need and whatt are the steps to making the games like graphics and game modes and create player etc
My Reply:
Making games for the Xbox is an expensive endeavor requiring thousands of dollars of equipment and software from Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Interview Follow-ups</title><link>https://ggr.com/interview-follow-ups.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2004 21:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/interview-follow-ups.html</guid><description>Rudy Writes:
I was reading some stuff on your website and just want to say, it&amp;rsquo;s a really cool idea. Congrats on landing the job with EA! I was wondering if I could get your opinion on something, from someone who has been through the interview process before , I really value your opinion.
Last week at Siggraph I dropped off my reel /resume at the EA booth. The next day they brought me in for an interview at the convention.</description></item><item><title>Idea For a New Game Feature</title><link>https://ggr.com/idea-for-a-new-game-feature.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2004 22:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/idea-for-a-new-game-feature.html</guid><description>Stephan Writes:
my name is stephan i am 12 and i have an idea for a game mode on live 2005 it is called become an nba star .it is when you create a player then select his position, home town,school and,statistics, you can create his family members so they can be there on draft day.then what he will wear on draft day and a voice cause he will narate his career and how he feels.</description></item><item><title>Advice For an Intern</title><link>https://ggr.com/advice-for-an-intern.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2004 21:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/advice-for-an-intern.html</guid><description>Stefan Writes:
Hey Scott, My name is Stefan Stignei and I&amp;rsquo;m going to be a sophomore next year at OSU. I&amp;rsquo;m majoring in New Media Communications and minoring in Commnunications. I&amp;rsquo;m also going to be a Resident Assistant in my hall which I&amp;rsquo;m really pumped for because I love meeting new people and would like to help them out.
Anyway I would love to work for a video game company. I&amp;rsquo;m going to apply for an internship at EA Games this year and I am wondering if there is anything I need to know about the work.</description></item><item><title>Game Industry Pay and College Plans</title><link>https://ggr.com/game-industry-pay-and-college-plans.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2004 21:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/game-industry-pay-and-college-plans.html</guid><description>Justin Writes:
Hi, my name is Justin I. I live in southern part of California. I am only 14 years old but I am serious to pursue this kind of job. I&amp;rsquo;ve made maps for games like counter-strike , Medal Of Honor, Call Of Duty, and some more. I am currently working as a mapper for a Half-Life 2 mod called Insects Infestation. I dont know what its like to work at ea, or if its good pay.</description></item><item><title>UCF and Portfolios</title><link>https://ggr.com/ucf-and-portfolios.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2004 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/ucf-and-portfolios.html</guid><description>Albert Writes:
My name is Albert, and I first want to thank you on having a great website. It&amp;rsquo;s very helpful to those who are planning on joining EA and need some advice on what to expect and what is expect of you. I have several questions I need to ask. I would like to know if you have heard any information about EA expanding their office in Orlando, Fl. I am in the process of getting my BA in Computer Animation , and I hear that EA is building an academy at the University of Central Florida.</description></item><item><title>High School Prep For a Game Career</title><link>https://ggr.com/high-school-prep-for-a-game-career.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2004 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/high-school-prep-for-a-game-career.html</guid><description>Merenia Writes:
Hello, My name is Merenia, I am 13 years old. I go to high school in New Zealand. I know I am to young to get a job as big as this, but I thought I would email you to ask a few things.
I am an animal, art and computer lover. I love stragic games, like The Sims and Zoo tycoon. I own about 4 of The Sims and I hope to buy others.</description></item><item><title>Getting In With Pogo</title><link>https://ggr.com/getting-in-with-pogo.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2004 13:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/getting-in-with-pogo.html</guid><description>Chris Writes:
hello, i need to know how do i get a job in pogo to work for them i go to info.ea.com and it dont take me were i should take me so i can get a job in there can you help me please you can email me how i can getin please email me at [redacted]. | please get back to me please hank you very much</description></item><item><title>Some House Cleaning</title><link>https://ggr.com/some-house-cleaning.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2004 10:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/some-house-cleaning.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to take down the forums. It seemed that most people prefer to email me their questions directly, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to answer the choice ones in the blog. Besides, there are a ton of forums like those at the IGDA and elsewhere that are more trafficked and probably better suited to ongoing conversations on the topic of getting into the industry because they have a lot more participants. I&amp;rsquo;m taking a bunch of the posts and reformatting them as posts so we get the added benefit of having all the content searchable through a single click.</description></item><item><title>I Have a Job At EA</title><link>https://ggr.com/i-have-a-job-at-ea.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2004 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/i-have-a-job-at-ea.html</guid><description>Yeay!! Last week I accepted an offer for a permanent job with EA and my first day was this Monday. I couldnt be happierI&amp;rsquo;m working on possibly the biggest game EA&amp;rsquo;s ever done, my boss is one of the most experienced producers in the industry, my whole team is similarly badass, and I&amp;rsquo;m having a ton of fun. Besides the utter luck of landing a job with this team, it feels really good to have worked hard over the past 12 months towards a goal and to have reached it!</description></item><item><title>Salaries At EA</title><link>https://ggr.com/salaries-at-ea.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2004 15:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/salaries-at-ea.html</guid><description>Kat Writes:
Don&amp;rsquo;t ya just hate the whole salary negotiation thing!? Lets say there was a &amp;lsquo;manager&amp;rsquo; position being filled by someone with eight years experience in the industry. What kind of salary would be reasonable with which to begin negotiations? I know theres a lot of considerations and probably a huge range; I&amp;rsquo;m just looking for a baseline to get me headed in the right direction.
My Reply:
You should talk to recruiters working in the game industry.</description></item><item><title>Getting Into EA Music</title><link>https://ggr.com/getting-into-ea-music.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2004 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/getting-into-ea-music.html</guid><description>Ken #1 Writes:
Hi. My name is Ken. I&amp;rsquo;ve read about the mission of EA Trax and how it relates to the music business. I think the concept is very interesting and it has caught my attention. Can you tell me anything about the Music Dept. at EA? How would I go about applying for a job in the music dept.? I havent seen too many postings on the website.</description></item><item><title>I Have an Idea For a Great Game!</title><link>https://ggr.com/i-have-an-idea-for-a-great-game.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2004 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/i-have-an-idea-for-a-great-game.html</guid><description>A Reader Writes:
I have some game ideas for a new strategy game based on Tiberian Twilight. I would really like to have a little time to share them with someone . I really think i know the best way to make a really snazzy strategy system. To anyone who has connections! Hook me up for just a few mins!
My Reply:
You might want to check these out:
http://www.sloperama.com/advice/idea.htm][2] http://www.</description></item><item><title>Pasting Resumes Into a Text Box</title><link>https://ggr.com/pasting-resumes-into-a-text-box.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2004 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/pasting-resumes-into-a-text-box.html</guid><description>Ken Writes:
EA has updated the job board on their website. I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded my resume but when it shows up in the text box, a lot of my alignment is thrown off. Should I adjust it to fit the text box or leave it as it is in its MS-Word state? Which way will EA see it when I submit my resume?
Phil Replies:
Hi Kenbo, it might be easiest if you cut and paste your word document into Notepad and then format in that file.</description></item><item><title>QoL Paper Published</title><link>https://ggr.com/qol-paper-published.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2004 22:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/qol-paper-published.html</guid><description>The QoL whitepaper is out! I contributed interviews and my experiences getting into the industry and making my way as a newbie. It&amp;rsquo;s been a pleasure serving with all the veterans on the IGDA QoL committee. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be interesting to see what we decide to work on next. The paper has been getting some attention across the web: Slashdot, GameDev, and ChaosEngine has threads talking about it, to name a few.</description></item><item><title>AWOL, But Learning The Ropes</title><link>https://ggr.com/awol-but-learning-the-ropes.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2004 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/awol-but-learning-the-ropes.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working some solid hours these dayshavent had much chance to post I&amp;rsquo;m sorry to say. :p I commute from Berkeley to Redwood City, so that kills 2 hours a day on top of work. But enough of that crap. I&amp;rsquo;m going to the last day of E3 next weeklooking forward to seeing the show! The game I&amp;rsquo;m working on isnt making an appearance at this one, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to catch an Updated on HL2.</description></item><item><title>Music, Madden, and Steve Schnur</title><link>https://ggr.com/music-madden-and-steve-schnur.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2004 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/music-madden-and-steve-schnur.html</guid><description>Rus Writes:
I am currently working towards my science degree, my goal is to attain a position in audio engineering or related field- it looks like w/ Steve Schnur is where I would want to go Ofcourse being the biggest fan [and best player] of Madden is a good reason, but my dream career is to be part of the awesome music and/ or sound effects behind these great games that the world craves!</description></item><item><title>IT At EA Tiberon In Florida</title><link>https://ggr.com/it-at-ea-tiberon-in-florida.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2004 14:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/it-at-ea-tiberon-in-florida.html</guid><description>Joel Writes:
Does anyone have any information on IT jobs available in Orlando? I&amp;rsquo;m looking to work in the Orlando area. Is there certain certifications that I should get to be qualified or is the best way to start off, is to start at the bottom and work your way up?
Rob Replies:
Well, it varies depending on what department of IT you work for. Certifications and experience will definitely not hurt you.</description></item><item><title>Living In Redwood</title><link>https://ggr.com/living-in-redwood.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2004 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/living-in-redwood.html</guid><description>Rite Writes:
If you&amp;rsquo;re under 30 &amp;amp; probably not making a six-figure salary at EA, where do you live? Redwood City? I&amp;rsquo;m assuming most rent an apartment but what areas are safe and but have clubs, bars, shops, etc.?
My Reply:
I&amp;rsquo;m under the impression that the towns near Redwood City are not geared to single people under 30. The rent doesnt seem too bad$1200/mo for a 1 room apt or $700 for a room in a house.</description></item><item><title>EA's Music Process</title><link>https://ggr.com/eas-music-process.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2004 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/eas-music-process.html</guid><description>Biggs Writes:
I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some research on types of jobs at EA. I came to the conclusion that the type of job I wanted would be in the same Dept as Steve Schnur, He is the head of the music dept. for EA. The only thing is, I dont know what kind of schooling I would have to go to in order to work in his department . Can anybody help?</description></item><item><title>One Animators Career Path</title><link>https://ggr.com/one-animators-career-path.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2004 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/one-animators-career-path.html</guid><description>Lindsay Writes:
More questions for Chris! Just wondering which EA studio you work at&amp;ndash;Europe, Maxis, Redwood Shores, Burnaby, Downtown Vancouver, etc. Also, if you dont mind, Id be interested in hearing about how you got into the industry yourself and any advice on the best strategy for getting into EA (networking and connections? internships? sending in countless demos?).
Chris Writes:
In regards to Lindsay&amp;rsquo;s question, I work at the Redwood Shores office here in Redwood City CA.</description></item><item><title>Animator Roles</title><link>https://ggr.com/animator-roles.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2004 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/animator-roles.html</guid><description>Thomas Writes:
Chris: Can you describe different roles or capacities that an animator might perform in the game industry? Though my primary interest is in becoming a game designer; I am also interested in cinematic cut scene direction (I did my under grad. in film).
Can one move into game design from animation or is level design a more direct route? Would you mind describing some highlights of your career as an animator?</description></item><item><title>GDC Article: Landing Your Dream Job</title><link>https://ggr.com/gdc-article-landing-your-dream-job.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2004 10:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/gdc-article-landing-your-dream-job.html</guid><description>Chereya Writes:
I found this article from the Game Developer Magazine 2003 Game Career Guide. Someone has thoughfully scanned it into a PDF and uploaded it for the rest of us to read free of charge (saves you $6!).
Updated on October 11th, 2013
Removed the link to Chereya&amp;rsquo;s email, I figure she doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to keep hearing from people through this page nor be exposed to more spam.</description></item><item><title>GDC 2004</title><link>https://ggr.com/gdc-2004.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2004 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/gdc-2004.html</guid><description>I spent Wednesday at the GDC and I have to say it was excellent. I served on a panel discussing Quality of Life and a roundtable on the same subject. Unfortunately I did a crappy job of presenting on the panelword to the wise: public speaking is a real skill that needs to be maintained and practiced (and a good presentation requires good prep). The roundtable went well though and we talked about some really good stuff.</description></item><item><title>Another Foot In the Door</title><link>https://ggr.com/another-foot-in-the-door.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2004 13:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/another-foot-in-the-door.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that my gig has been extended another few months until the end of June. Its encouraging to note that my efforts are appreciated to that level! Now its on to showing that I&amp;rsquo;m worth keeping around past June. :)</description></item><item><title>More On Classes For Future Producers</title><link>https://ggr.com/more-on-classes-for-future-producers.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2004 15:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/more-on-classes-for-future-producers.html</guid><description>Koz Writes:
What would you say would be a better route if I want to get into a production role? I could take a computer game design/programming class that will mostly focus on the implementation process or take classes that revolve around operations management and business classes.
My Reply:
From what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen all of those skills are useful to a producer, though I think you would have easier time getting a job in todays industry with programming training than with business training.</description></item><item><title>Jobs Via the Web</title><link>https://ggr.com/jobs-via-the-web.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2004 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/jobs-via-the-web.html</guid><description>Alan Writes:
Hey Scott, You may have no way of gaining this info, but how effective has the web been for recruiting candidates at EA? Do you know of many people who have posted for positions via the web and have had success (success meaning interviews&amp;quot;)? Would it be better to go snail mail? Just curious as to your thoughts.
My Reply:
Most of the people I talk to got in through a friend, not through a web site.</description></item><item><title>Writers At EA</title><link>https://ggr.com/writers-at-ea.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2004 10:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/writers-at-ea.html</guid><description>Alan Writes:
First off, excellent site. I commend you on your creativity and tenacity in achieving your goal. Great job. | I&amp;rsquo;m a screenwriter thats had moderate Hollywood success. Moderate being defined in that I&amp;rsquo;ve sold two scripts to Hollywood production companies but nothing made (yet). I also have a background in I.T. (all areas of project life cycle). | My question is, do you know if EA employs a staff of writers?</description></item><item><title>Classes For a Future Tester</title><link>https://ggr.com/classes-for-a-future-tester.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2004 10:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/classes-for-a-future-tester.html</guid><description>Ian Writes:
What type of classes would you recomend me to take if I&amp;rsquo;m interested in being any type of producer or tester? if there is anyone out there that is currently in production at EA or elsewhere could you please share what classes really helped you or any other advice.
My Reply:
If you want to be a tester you should own every game system you can get your hands on and play games constantly.</description></item><item><title>Finding Internship Positions</title><link>https://ggr.com/finding-internship-positions.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2004 10:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/finding-internship-positions.html</guid><description>Kirk Writes:
I am wondering if anyone can offer any insight into more about the production internships they offer over at EA. I really only see the Tiger Woods Golf one, which is about as good as it gets, but do they offer anymore? Is this a one intern deal? Any help would be greatly appreciated.
My Reply:
The internship position I have now did not even exist before I landed itI had the good fortune of meeting the right people who offered to get me in.</description></item><item><title>QA Interview Post-mortem</title><link>https://ggr.com/qa-interview-post-mortem.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2004 10:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/qa-interview-post-mortem.html</guid><description>A Reader Writes:
Here&amp;rsquo;s another rejection QA story to read. I was reading over what Jonathan said about his experience before my interview. I had the same test he did ( I know this because the questions he posted were on my test as well). Heres my idea of what there hiring strategy is for new QA testers.
They have about 3 or so hiring periods 1 day a week (1:00, 3:00, 5:00 etc.</description></item><item><title>Full Sail and Classes For Animators</title><link>https://ggr.com/full-sail-and-classes-for-animators.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2004 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/full-sail-and-classes-for-animators.html</guid><description>Kim Writes:
I am interested in the computer animation, game design field. My question is what is the best classes to take and what will I need to become a great future EA Games associate? What classes should I look for to make sure I am getting my monies worth?I am looking at the computer animation program and Full Sail in Orlando. But the tuition is $58,000. Is a full program like that recommended or could classes be taken at a community college or university individually?</description></item><item><title>Studying For a Career in Production</title><link>https://ggr.com/studying-for-a-career-in-production.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2004 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/studying-for-a-career-in-production.html</guid><description>Koz Writes:
Should a college student who wants to get in to the production side of video games look to take a major in say buisiness management or related buisness majors or somthing closer to computers.
My Reply:
Theres no major that maps well to production. Producers vary widely in their areas of expertise from: former artists to programmers to testers to business people. My boss is a senior producer who used to be in marketing.</description></item><item><title>Programming vs Marketing</title><link>https://ggr.com/programming-vs-marketing.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2004 10:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/programming-vs-marketing.html</guid><description>Ian Writes:
Hi my name is Ian and I am a computer science major at Dakota State University. Where I am at right now is that I&amp;rsquo;m finding out that I am less interested in heavy programming and all the technical aspects of making games and more in to the production/testing/and possibly marketing part of it although the last one is a little iffy. I&amp;rsquo;ve started applying for multiple internships for this summer.</description></item><item><title>Internship Application Process</title><link>https://ggr.com/internship-application-process.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2004 10:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/internship-application-process.html</guid><description>Thomas Writes:
Dear Scott and IWTWAEA posters,
Thank you for this resource. It is inspiring to read about your efforts. I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting my portfolio together for various EA Academy internships at the Redwood City campus. I was wondering if I could get some advice on my application process.
I would like to direct my mail and cover letter to a person and not To whom it may concern&amp;quot;. Would I be able to get the proper contact name by calling EA&amp;rsquo;s HR dept, or will I not even make it past the receptionist?</description></item><item><title>Business Skills In the Game Industry</title><link>https://ggr.com/business-skills-in-the-game-industry.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2004 10:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/business-skills-in-the-game-industry.html</guid><description>Will Writes:
Good evening. I currently work as a Senior Process Manager for a top 10 financial institution. In my current role, I am responsible for ensuring that our institution (over 80 million accounts) complies with multiple forms of USA Patriot Act legislation, including Office of Foreign Assets requirements and Bank Secrecy Act requirements. I manage a direct team of four Process Managers and an indirect team of over 20 Operations/Process Managers across our company, including across 6 different geographic locations and multiple business types.</description></item><item><title>Internship Pay</title><link>https://ggr.com/internship-pay.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2004 10:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/internship-pay.html</guid><description>Chereya Writes:
Hey Scott, This may be too personal but I thought Id try asking you anyhow since you&amp;rsquo;re the only person I know who might share the answer. Please feel free to disregard&amp;hellip; What is the basic pay rate for EA interns? What other benefits are interns offered that are comparable to benefits accorded to a permanent position? ie. housing, insurance, holidays off or sick days&amp;hellip; If my hubby-to-be gets an internship position -crosses fingers- what would the intern-role be like for married father of an infant?</description></item><item><title>L33t Programmer Wants In</title><link>https://ggr.com/l33t-programmer-wants-in.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2004 11:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/l33t-programmer-wants-in.html</guid><description>Marquin Writes:
Alright, so, I&amp;rsquo;ll start off with a simple question&amp;ndash;how does one go about getting a job as a software engineer at EA? I hate to come off as arrogant, however, I have learned that this may be the only chance I have&amp;ndash;every person trying to get a job &amp;ldquo;fluffs up&amp;rdquo; their resume, advertising skills they dont really have. Thus, on a resume, I am the same as anyone else, because even though I may be honest about my skills, I look no different on a resume than someone whos fluffed theirs up.</description></item><item><title>Transfering To Executive Producer</title><link>https://ggr.com/transfering-to-executive-producer.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2004 11:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/transfering-to-executive-producer.html</guid><description>Chris Writes:
I have about three years experience in creating stochastic simulations and visualization systems for the US Army at WSMR. In addition I am currently the Executive Producer of a CG kids show for APTN. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in flying the coop here sometime in the next couple of years. What kind of chance do I have to get into an Executive Producer slot at EA. A great deal of my experience is in getting a team of modelers/animators/programmers to create specific simulation systems for the military.</description></item><item><title>Animator Networking</title><link>https://ggr.com/animator-networking.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2004 11:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/animator-networking.html</guid><description>Lindsay Writes:
Hi Scott, I came across your site while looking at the EA Academy site (actually I was examining the guidelines for loopholes to get in as an intern). I gotta say that it was pretty smart of you to start this site&amp;ndash;talk about a great way to get noticed by the company! Anyways, I recently graduated from Vancouver Film School as an animator. I would love to get a job at EA in animation (whether it be as a mocap operator or clean up artist, etc) but am finding it incredibly difficult.</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Penny Arcades</title><link>https://ggr.com/my-favorite-penny-arcades.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2004 11:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/my-favorite-penny-arcades.html</guid><description>Its the best comic in the industry&amp;hellip;and some say on the web. And really, all of them are good, but heres a list of my favorites.
Gamers and the Girls That Put Up With Us
Girlfriends, Tribes, and You Soul (Calibur) Mate Get Down Tonite x2 The Difference While You&amp;rsquo;re Ahead Sure, Its Cotton - But What Is It? This Comic Got Me In Trouble Pretty Please I Must Not Recall I Mean, Who Doesnt The Comic That Heals Gamer Friends</description></item><item><title>What I Do These Days</title><link>https://ggr.com/what-i-do-these-days.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2004 23:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/what-i-do-these-days.html</guid><description>I made it past my 1 month anniversary at EA and I thought it would be good to reflect a bit on what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned and what I&amp;rsquo;m up to. I continue to be wowed by the people I work with. I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by the best of the best and it&amp;rsquo;s at once exhilarating and humbling.
I&amp;rsquo;m a Production Intern on an unannounced title which is in the middle of pre-production (the design/early prototyping phase for those of us coming from biz software).</description></item><item><title>Being A Main Character In An MMORPG</title><link>https://ggr.com/being-a-main-character-in-an-mmorpg.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2004 23:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/being-a-main-character-in-an-mmorpg.html</guid><description>I realize that Lucas does not need my advice, not the least because I have no idea what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. But that said, I was walking home from the theatre the other evening and I got to thinking about MMORPG and what can be done, taking Star Wars Galaxies as an example. You see, it had come up in an EA interview&amp;ndash;a question about why I think some game works or doesnt and then what could have been done differently, so its not purely a random fun exercise.</description></item><item><title>EA Is Hiring Marketing Interns</title><link>https://ggr.com/ea-is-hiring-marketing-interns.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2004 20:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/ea-is-hiring-marketing-interns.html</guid><description>Just got an email from EA Jobs&amp;hellip;they are looking for applicants by 3-12-04. Looks like they want a Product Marketing Intern or two.</description></item><item><title>Interview With EA Tiberon</title><link>https://ggr.com/interview-with-ea-tiberon.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2004 10:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/interview-with-ea-tiberon.html</guid><description>Jonathon writes:
I got to Tiburon around 3:40pm. My interview wasnt until 4pm, so that was good. I would have been there even earlier, but we had a little trouble finding the place. Good thing we left early!
So I walked into Tiburon, very cool building. I saw some arcade machines and stuff in this one room, it must have been the game room. I then found where I needed to go, told them I was there for the interview, and they gave me an application to fill out.</description></item><item><title>Online Game Classes</title><link>https://ggr.com/online-game-classes.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2004 21:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/online-game-classes.html</guid><description>Brian Donoho tells me that Gameversity is offering online courses for aspiring game programmers, including a few free 2-week seminars to try and get you hooked. :) Kinda cool
Updated on October 10th, 2013
Archive.org-ed the Gameversity link.</description></item><item><title>What EA Wants In A Tester</title><link>https://ggr.com/what-ea-wants-in-a-tester.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2004 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/what-ea-wants-in-a-tester.html</guid><description>Jeremy Writes:
I have a couple of questions. First I am attending a community college in pennsylvania for a generalized computer degree and I am also planning on getting my mcse certification. What I am wondering is how can I get into the industry now to gain experience, I heard that testing is an excellent way to get started but what kind of experience are they looking for in testers. I love video games and EA is always been a favorite of mine, if you could tell me anything I would appreciate it.</description></item><item><title>How To Start Networking</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-start-networking.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2004 11:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-start-networking.html</guid><description>Jon Writes:
Howdy, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading everything you have on your site about building contacts and networking but I&amp;rsquo;ve found a snag that I was wondering if you could help me with. Currently I&amp;rsquo;m a student and the University of Texas A&amp;amp;M. I&amp;rsquo;m majoring in Architecture with plans on joining a graduate level program designed to teach 3d modeling, 3d programming, animation, and basically anything related to the special effects field of movies.</description></item><item><title>Tips If You're In High School</title><link>https://ggr.com/tips-if-youre-in-high-school.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2004 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/tips-if-youre-in-high-school.html</guid><description>An Anonymous Reader Writes:
Ok i have always been interested in games and making them was always my dream job and i was woundering if there are any tips you guys could give me for making it come true i am still in high school and i am trying to figure out what i am going to do with my life and i just bought a new game (need for speed: underground) and in the back it said something about ea academy and it made me want to check it out and i did which is how i got here and figured i would ask some pros about it so here it is above well hope you guys can help.</description></item><item><title>Some Networking Ideas</title><link>https://ggr.com/some-networking-ideas.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2004 11:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/some-networking-ideas.html</guid><description>Dave Writes:
Nice forum, Scott. I have actually set up phpBB a few times for friends I host websites for. I am presently in the process of creating a forum interface in Flash. The initial backend is CODE:NEO with MySQL, but I will probably port it to PHP, as well. Have you ever seen a message board done in Flash? I think I might have something original with that. So I want to work at EA!</description></item><item><title>Forums Are Live</title><link>https://ggr.com/forums-are-live.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2004 03:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/forums-are-live.html</guid><description>The link is over there on the right. Ah heck, here it is too.
Updated on October 10th, 2013
I stopped hosting the IWantToWorkAtEA.com forums a while ago, so it seemed only logical to remove the link to them from this post.</description></item><item><title>New Blog Engine</title><link>https://ggr.com/new-blog-engine.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2004 21:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/new-blog-engine.html</guid><description>While working to add forums I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to move the site and change Blog engines. This is the new one. I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of restoring the content and finding my way around, so please pardon the sawdust.
Updated on October 10th, 2013
I think I was using Movable Type and changed to Wordpress. Of course these days its Octopress.</description></item><item><title>Budgetting For a Game Career</title><link>https://ggr.com/budgetting-for-a-game-career.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2004 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/budgetting-for-a-game-career.html</guid><description>Being a production intern, it occurs to me that I make less money than I used to. ;) Starting a new career involves making some sacrifices and in my case I knew to expect some belt tightening. Planning for this has been key&amp;ndash;at least for myself, I find that I dont need much money to live on comfortably as long as I pay attention to what I&amp;rsquo;m spending money on.</description></item><item><title>Working On Forums</title><link>https://ggr.com/working-on-forums.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2004 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/working-on-forums.html</guid><description>EA Academy recently linked to this site and the email has been coming in a bit faster&amp;hellip;and its started me thinking about what direction to take the site next. I&amp;rsquo;m working on putting up some forums so more people can check out the questions and discussions that have been happening in email and blog comments up to this point. I bet there are some people who visit this site on occasion who know a lot more than I do about breaking into the industry and might be happy to help out as well!</description></item><item><title>Aspiring Marketing Dude</title><link>https://ggr.com/aspiring-marketing-dude.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2004 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/aspiring-marketing-dude.html</guid><description>Jason Anderson emailed a couple days ago with aspirations to land an internship in marketing at EA. Hes a marketing major with a spring internship under his belt and a strong interest in EA. I put him in touch with Tara S. (she works in marketing at EA) who graciously agreed to chat with him and see if she could help. Id be happy to send more help his way if I can, so if any of yall reading this might have some words of wisdom be sure and send me an email!</description></item><item><title>First Week At EA</title><link>https://ggr.com/first-week-at-ea.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2004 10:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/first-week-at-ea.html</guid><description>I started work Tuesday and man, I&amp;rsquo;m having a great time! I really lucked out&amp;ndash;Hunter and Lisa have tons of experience are a real pleasure to work with. Everyone I&amp;rsquo;ve met so far has been helpful and enthusiastic in fact&amp;ndash;like Victor and Robert in IT who have been going out of their way to help me get what I need. I dont know if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever worked with more helpful IT guys.</description></item><item><title>Game List</title><link>https://ggr.com/game-list.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/game-list.html</guid><description>Here it is, all the games I can remember having ever played:
3D Tic-Tac-Toe, Atari 800 688 Attack Sub, PC Advanced Civilization, board Advanced Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons, pen-and-paper Age of Empires, PC Age of Emipres 2, PC Air Hockey, table Alice, PC Aliens vs. Predator, PC Alpha Centauri, PC The Ancient Art of War at Sea, Apple II The Ancient Art of War, Apple II The Ancient Art of War, PC Archon, Commodore 64 Archon, PC Archon 2, Apple II Archon 2, PC Arkanoid, PC Ashernons Call, PC Asteroids, Atari 2600 Asteroids, Atari 800 Autoduel, PC Backgammon, board Balderdash, board Baseball, sport Battle Realms, PC Battlezone, Atari 2600 Badminton, sport Bards Tale, Apple II Bards Tale 2, Apple II Bards Tale 3, PC Battle Chess, PC Battlefield 1942, PC Battletech, board Black and White, PC Blackjack, card Bridge, card California Games, Atari 2600 Car Wars, pen-and-paper Castle Risk, board Castle Wolfenstein, PC Centipede, Atari 2600 Centipede, Atari 800 Champions of Krynn, PC Checkers, board Chess, board Chessmaster, Commodore 64 Chessmaster 2000, PC Chessmaster 4000, PC Chessmaster 8000, PC Chessmaster 9000, PC Chopper Command, Atari 2600 Chutes and Ladders, board City of Heroes, PC Civilization, board Civilization, PC Civilization II, PC Civilization: Call to Power, PC Command &amp;amp; Conquer, PC Command &amp;amp; Conquer: Red Alert, PC Crimson Skies, PC Curse of the Azure Bonds, PC Dark Reign, PC Decent, PC Decent II, PC Defender, Apple II Defender, Atari 2600 Deus Ex, PC Diablo, PC Diablo 2, PC Donkey Kong, acrade Donkey Kong, Apple II Doom, PC Doom II, PC DigDug, Atari 800 Dragons Lair, arcade Dragons Lair, PC Dragons of Flame, PC DragonStrike, PC Driv3r, PS2 Dungeon Keeper, PC Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons, pen-and-paper Duke Nukem, PC Elder Scrolls 3: Morrowind, PC Elite, Commadore 64 Elite 2, PC Escape From Monkey Island, PC Eye of the Beholder, PC Eye of the Beholder 2, PC Eye of the Beholder 3, PC Fatal Frame, Xbox Fifty-two pickup, card Foosball, table Football, sport Frogger, Atari 800 Frogger, PC Full Spectrum Warrior, Xbox Galaxian, Atari 2600 Gauntlet, arcade Gauntlet, PC Gettysburg, PC Golden Axe, arcade Golden Axe, PC Golf, sport Grand Prix, Atari 800 Grand Theft Auto 3, PC Grand Theft Auto: Vice City, PC Grim Fandango, PC GURPS, pen-and-paper Half-Life, PC Half-Life: Blue Shift, PC Half-Life: Counter-Strike, PC Half-Life: Opposing Forces, PC Halo, Xbox Haunted House, Atari 2600 Hearts, card Heros Quest, PC Heros Quest 2, PC Hexen, PC Hop-Scotch, sport The Hitchhikers Guide to the Galaxy, Apple II Homeworld, PC Homeworld 2, PC Homeworld: Cataclysm, PC I&amp;rsquo;mperialism, PC Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom, Atari 2600 Jedi Knight: Jedi Outcast Joust, Apple II Joust, Atari 800 Joust, PC Jumpman, Apple II The Legend of Zelda, Nintendo Karate, Commadore 64 Karate, PC Kings Quest, PC Kings Quest 2, PC Kings Quest 3, PC Kings Quest 4, PC Kings Quest 5, PC LeapPad, electronic book Leisure Suit Larry, PC Leisure Suit Larry 2, PC Leisure Suit Larry 3, PC Leisure Suit Larry 4, PC Leisure Suit Larry 5, PC Loadrunner, Apple II Life, board Loom, PC Lords of the Realm, PC Mage: The Ascension, pen-and-paper Magic: The Gathering, card MechCommander, PC Mechwarrior, PC Mechwarrior 2, PC Mechwarrior 4, PC Microsoft Flight Simulator 2002, PC Mine Sweeper, PC Miner 2049er, Apple PC Missile Command, PC Monopoly, board Montezums Revenge, Atari 2600 Mortal Kombat, arcade Mortal Kombat 2, arcade Motocross Mania, PC Ms.</description></item><item><title>Campaign Contacts</title><link>https://ggr.com/campaign-contacts.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/campaign-contacts.html</guid><description>Just to give you an idea of what kind of networking I did to get in with EA, here are the people who I was in touch with about the campaign to get a job at EA:
Andrew Boer, Games 411, Publisher Andy Cheren, Digital Artists Management, Senior Partner Anourath Senebouttarath Aramazd Dermardirosian Auren Hoffman, Stonebrick Group,Chairman Ben Durbin Bing Gordon, EA, Co-Founder Bill Shwartz Bo Lasater Brad Klassen, former EA, QA tester Brian Donoho, QuickLogic, IT Manager?</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://ggr.com/faq.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/faq.html</guid><description>What is the point of all this?
This site exists to encourage and educate future EA employees about the roles and people of EA.
When I started looking into the game industry I couldnt find much guidance about how to make the jump coming from 10 years in another industry. So, I decided I would share my experiences and try to blaze a path for the next person. Much of the blog was written while I was in the middle of figuring out how to find a job with EA.</description></item><item><title>Emailing Me</title><link>https://ggr.com/emailing-me.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/emailing-me.html</guid><description>Thanks for saying hello! If you have a question for me about getting a job in the game industry go ahead and email me. I&amp;rsquo;ll post your email message and my reply to it so everyone can check it out and participate&amp;ndash;if youre lucky youll get some replies from my colleagues at EA&amp;hellip;they check out these posts on occasion.
Over time I&amp;rsquo;ve answered a bunch of questions and I&amp;rsquo;ve written on a number of topics related to getting into games.</description></item><item><title>Looks Like EA Canada Is Hiring</title><link>https://ggr.com/looks-like-ea-canada-is-hiring.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2003 10:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/looks-like-ea-canada-is-hiring.html</guid><description>At least, it looks like they are trying to find a few good programmers. ASCII stupid question, get a stupid ANSI.
Updated on October 9th, 2013
Archive.org-ed the first link.</description></item><item><title>Update From Lisa Bell</title><link>https://ggr.com/update-from-lisa-bell.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2003 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/update-from-lisa-bell.html</guid><description>I started our call by updating Lisa on my conversation with Hunter Smith, and she let me know what she had found. Basically, she feels stuff has a good chance of coming together at EARS shortly and shes still waiting to hear back from the other studios. Weve decided we should touch base one more time this year and then follow up after the holidays.
Updated on October 9th, 2013</description></item><item><title>Job Fair End Of January</title><link>https://ggr.com/job-fair-end-of-january.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2003 11:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/job-fair-end-of-january.html</guid><description>Chris Sherman emailed me to let me know about a game industry job fair hes organizing in January. Looks like its over in SOMA&amp;hellip;may be worth checking out!
Updated on October 9th, 2013
Archive.org-ed the job fair link.</description></item><item><title>Call With David De Martini</title><link>https://ggr.com/call-with-david-de-martini.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2003 19:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/call-with-david-de-martini.html</guid><description>I had the chance to speak to David De Martini today and tell him my story. He offered to help me land an internship since its the easiest way to get me in the door and give me a chance to prove what I can do. I asked whether I had been out of college too long, but he seemed confident he could hook me up with a position. Sweet. It will give me the chance to learn from the inside AND it gives me exposure to the people I want to work with.</description></item><item><title>Growing Pains For The Industry</title><link>https://ggr.com/growing-pains-for-the-industry.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2003 10:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/growing-pains-for-the-industry.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been told by a few people that getting into the game industry these days is a bit trickier than it used to be&amp;ndash;now that its grown into something with some amount of status (where it used to be considered more of a hobby than an industry), a lot of people have taken an interest in working in the industry. So, you might expect it would be a buyers market for talent.</description></item><item><title>Update From Lisa Bell</title><link>https://ggr.com/update-from-lisa-bell.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2003 16:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/update-from-lisa-bell.html</guid><description>Lisa Bell called me this afternoon with a quick update: shes been in touch with her counterpart at EARS: Rachel McIntyre. Rachel was out of town when I met with EAP, otherwise I would probably have met her then, though I keep hearing her name. Anyway, Lisa has also been in touch with a couple of her Canadian counterparts too; but everyone (outside of Maxis at the moment) is hella busy hiring, so she thinks they will take a couple days to get back to her.</description></item><item><title>Spike Tvs Video Game Awards</title><link>https://ggr.com/spike-tvs-video-game-awards.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2003 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/spike-tvs-video-game-awards.html</guid><description>Shawn Kresal sent me this article about Spike TVs video game awards show. Itll be interesting to see how well games and TV mix&amp;hellip;I suspect it will take some trial-and-error to find a good mix. Few game makers, much like the non-actors in movies, have transformed themselves into TV&amp;ndash;compatible celebrities so far. But hey, perhaps our day is coming!
Updated on October 9th, 2013
Removed the dead link to the article in question.</description></item><item><title>2003 Video Game Gift Guide</title><link>https://ggr.com/2003-video-game-gift-guide.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2003 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/2003-video-game-gift-guide.html</guid><description>Saw this post over at Slashdot talking about Gaming Horizons suggestions for this Christmas season. Interesting to compare their list with the top games of the year according to Metacritic.
Updated on October 9th, 2013
Replaced the broken link to the holiday list with a link to a copy at the Internet Archive.</description></item><item><title>Rules Of Play Review</title><link>https://ggr.com/rules-of-play-review.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2003 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/rules-of-play-review.html</guid><description>Shawn Kresal sent me a review of Rules of Play, a new book that examines games and gameplay from an academic perspective. It sounds excellent&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m adding it to my reading list. I&amp;rsquo;ve also added a new blog category called &amp;ldquo;Background Reading&amp;rdquo; for the purpose of sharing with my fellow newbies my sources for a lot of the industry background info that you see showing up in these blog entries. I&amp;rsquo;ll start adding them as I read them and then see about adding the stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve already read, at least the ones I can remember&amp;hellip;there have been a lot.</description></item><item><title>Post-mortem With EAP</title><link>https://ggr.com/post-mortem-with-eap.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2003 20:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/post-mortem-with-eap.html</guid><description>A couple days ago I emailed Craig Alexander thanking him for the opportunity to interview with his team and asking for a time to talk and get his feedback on the interviews. While I wasnt a fit for somewhat structural reasons I figured there were probably other areas that could use some improvement. We connected this evening and Craig buried me with help and advice!
I started the conversation with a quick recap of what I was looking for: how I could have presented myself better and what I should do to be better prepared when I interview with other groups at EA.</description></item><item><title>Phone Call With Lisa Bell</title><link>https://ggr.com/phone-call-with-lisa-bell.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2003 15:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/phone-call-with-lisa-bell.html</guid><description>Lisa and I spoke briefly a couple months ago, before scheduling todays informational interview. Lisa called right on time. She started by mentioning that this site has been an item over at Maxis and the blog entry that mentioned our first encounter had gotten her some attention. :) I hope it was good! I took the opportunity to let her know that I dont post anything that I suspect or am told is confidential, and I give my conversation partners the final say on material I put on here.</description></item><item><title>A Quick Hello With David De Martini</title><link>https://ggr.com/a-quick-hello-with-david-de-martini.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2003 20:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/a-quick-hello-with-david-de-martini.html</guid><description>As my meeting with Jose was coming to a close, in walked David De Martini. I had emailed DeMar to try and setup a meeting but we hadn&amp;rsquo;t set anything up yet. Turns out Bing put me on his calendar to his surprise. :p Made me feel pretty cool that Bing got him here on my behalf, but I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t want to inconvenience DeMar! He offered to reschedule since now wasn&amp;rsquo;t a good time for him to step away and I was happy to accept.</description></item><item><title>Intro To Jose Martin</title><link>https://ggr.com/intro-to-jose-martin.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2003 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/intro-to-jose-martin.html</guid><description>Apparently Bing asked Jose Martin to meet me after Bing and I met, and there he appeared! Jose is &amp;ldquo;Vice President Human Resources, WW Group Studios&amp;rdquo; which means I couldnt meet someone with a better view of Studios hiring plans.
We started our conversation with the standard questions about my interest in games, my favorites, etc. and then I started in with some questions of my own. I asked what makes the difference between a good producer and a great producer and he said there were three areas where a great producer excels:</description></item><item><title>Lunch With Bing Gordon</title><link>https://ggr.com/lunch-with-bing-gordon.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2003 19:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/lunch-with-bing-gordon.html</guid><description>So the other day I&amp;rsquo;m in 250&amp;hellip; :) After chatting with Tara I headed over to the front desk to let Jenny Turick (Bings exec assistant) know I was here. That is, the front desk of death.
The Front Desk Puzzle &amp;rsquo; 10 points
I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, after about 4 visits, that when the front desk calls someone and tells me that they have confirmed that they know I&amp;rsquo;m in 250 it can actually mean one of a few different things: a) they left a message for someone other than the person I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to meet with, b) they left a message for the person I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to meet with, c) they talked to someone who doesnt know who I am, doesnt care, and is not coming down to see me, d) they talked to the right person and they are actually coming right down.</description></item><item><title>Flyby Chat With Philip Gee</title><link>https://ggr.com/flyby-chat-with-philip-gee.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2003 18:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/flyby-chat-with-philip-gee.html</guid><description>While Tara and I chatted away Philip Gee walked by and Tara quickly introduced us. Phil handles college recruiting for EA and Tara wanted to see if he might have some ideas. I&amp;rsquo;ve been out of college too long for his department, nevertheless he offered to fill me in on which teams he knows of that are hiring producers right now and what the calendar looks like. He pointed out that in December, after the big Christmas push in October, a lot of the teams are working on their pilots with a small team of artists and developers.</description></item><item><title>Sit Down With Tara S.</title><link>https://ggr.com/sit-down-with-tara-s..html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2003 17:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/sit-down-with-tara-s..html</guid><description>Weve been meeting to get together and swap stories and it finally happened today right before my meeting with Bing. I was wandering the area that the geese had marked as their own (at least, I think the dropping saturate sidewalk must be a popular hangout for them) when Tara called and we converged on 250 to talk. Tara made sure to introduce me to everyone she could along the path from the front of the building to the cushy chairs, because shes just cool that way.</description></item><item><title>The Swedish Connection</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-swedish-connection.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2003 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-swedish-connection.html</guid><description>A few weeks ago I heard from Fredrik Thylander (a game designer with Digital I&amp;rsquo;llusions) who had stumbled across this site and sent me an email just to say he likes the site and good luck. He also put a good word in for John Vifian and EAP&amp;ndash;good bunch of guys to work with. Today I heard from Sean Decker who, it turns out, is over in Sweden working with a team on the Battlefield series.</description></item><item><title>On I'mmersion And Tron 2.0</title><link>https://ggr.com/on-immersion-and-tron-2.0.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2003 01:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/on-immersion-and-tron-2.0.html</guid><description>I just finished Tron 2.0 and prior to that by a few days I had watched the Two Towers, extended version and its appendices. I find the making of the LOTR movies and Peter Jackson as a supreme inspiration&amp;ndash;and it reminds me of what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for in game production. I want to help bottle the awe and joy of those moments I&amp;rsquo;ve found in books and on screen and bring them to games.</description></item><item><title>No One Lives Forever Notes</title><link>https://ggr.com/no-one-lives-forever-notes.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2003 00:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/no-one-lives-forever-notes.html</guid><description>Well, its a top rated game so I thought Id check out what its all about. I opted not to read the reviews first and just let it impress me on its own. Of course, the graphics are a little dated, but I liked Alice a lot and its getting a little long in the tooth. My favorite games have survived a graphics cycle or two and are still fun in any case.</description></item><item><title>First EA App Complete</title><link>https://ggr.com/first-ea-app-complete.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2003 23:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/first-ea-app-complete.html</guid><description>Heard from Rob Moreno today letting me know that EAP isn&amp;rsquo;t ready to bring me on just yet. Darn! I was hoping that they would see past my lack of game industry experience but it looks like they noticed. ;) So that wraps my first formal application to a position with EA! Not too shabby&amp;ndash;I made 5 new production contacts, several of whom were kind enough to offer me help after the interview was over.</description></item><item><title>On Bing Gordons Calendar</title><link>https://ggr.com/on-bing-gordons-calendar.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2003 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/on-bing-gordons-calendar.html</guid><description>I feel very lucky to have been introduced to Bing Gordon by Neil Young. Bing has offered to meet with me in a week and a half where well no doubt have the chance to speak about a number of interesting topics. Id love to hear the tales he has from the early days of EAhes one of the 7 original founders from back in 1982. That makes him one of the rock stars of the industry&amp;hellip;I can hardly believe I get to sit down with him!</description></item><item><title>Some Thank You Cards</title><link>https://ggr.com/some-thank-you-cards.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2003 01:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/some-thank-you-cards.html</guid><description>I thought it would be nice to thank everyone I met with during the course of my interviews. I learned a lot and a number of people even offered their business cards and told me to call or email if I had more questions. Thank yous are definitely in order! I was thinking about sending emails, but I decided on personalize hand-written thank you cards. I think cards convey greater appreciation and courtesy because they take more effort.</description></item><item><title>In-person Interviews With EAP, Round</title><link>https://ggr.com/in-person-interviews-with-eap-round.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2003 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/in-person-interviews-with-eap-round.html</guid><description>Its been quite a day! 5 hours of interviews stacked back-to-back with a bunch of the EAP team&amp;hellip;and this is just the first round of in-person interviews. These were proceeded by two phone interviews a couple weeks ago. It was pretty cool meeting everyone and having the chance to ask a lot of questions about EA and the production roles here.
Craig Alexander told me the reason for the high number of interviews was that EA is very consensus oriented&amp;ndash;I will be working with a lot of people very closely under a lot of pressure and it&amp;rsquo;s important that everyone get along really well.</description></item><item><title>Chat With Ofer Estline</title><link>https://ggr.com/chat-with-ofer-estline.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2003 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/chat-with-ofer-estline.html</guid><description>Ofer and I met at EALA after work (well, not really, Ofer planned to stay until midnight) to talk about EA and Development Directors (DDs). First a quick tour of EALA which is presently packed with three studios. Its nice and cozy until January when the new offices come online.
I asked Ofer to tell me more about DD vs Producers at EA. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard the story from a couple Producers, but Ofer is the first DD I&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to sit down with.</description></item><item><title>The EA Way</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-ea-way.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2003 09:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-ea-way.html</guid><description>While I was visiting Jordan Maynard last week, I noticed an old EA advertisement framed on his desk. It was a sort of manifesto for EA that defined what EA was about and told why it mattered. Even though some people may think of EA as more business oriented than a lot of smaller game companies, I think the founders articulated a vision that still captures the underlying spirit of the company and the industry: yes, money keeps the ball rolling, but at the end of the day we are not just creating a way to have fun&amp;ndash;we are participating in a cultural and artistic conversation about ourselves and our world.</description></item><item><title>Online Networking</title><link>https://ggr.com/online-networking.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2003 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/online-networking.html</guid><description>I was recently asked how online networking tools like Spoke have contributed to my efforts to meet people within the game industry. I signed up for Spoke, Linked-In, Friendster, and couple others a few months ago. But none of them were much help for meeting people in the game industry.
Whats Missing?
First, I havent met many people in the game industry that choose to spend a lot of time on networking&amp;ndash;it sorta happens during the course of working in the industry but the industry is otherwise a bit insulated.</description></item><item><title>6 Hours Of Interviews</title><link>https://ggr.com/6-hours-of-interviews.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2003 13:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/6-hours-of-interviews.html</guid><description>Got the email packet for my EAP interviews this week and I note that its going to be a marathon of 30 to 45 minute interviews. I&amp;rsquo;ll get the chance to meet a lot of the people I would be working with and I&amp;rsquo;ll have an opportunity to meet all the different titles I want to learn more about&amp;ndash;Associate Development Director (DD), Associate Producer (AP), Producer, Senior Producer, VP. Thats some serious interviewing though!</description></item><item><title>APs and Morrowind</title><link>https://ggr.com/aps-and-morrowind.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2003 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/aps-and-morrowind.html</guid><description>Met up with my friend Aaron Butler for lunch. Hes an Associate Producer with MTV and hes earned credits for editing and directing as well. Hes had some offers from VH1 too&amp;ndash;basically hes totally kicking butt down here. We used to be roommates and before that we were involved in student government together at Cal. Aarons been making films for the absolute love of it since he was in junior high&amp;ndash;seeing him doing so well is really cool.</description></item><item><title>LA Gamer Friends and My Reunion</title><link>https://ggr.com/la-gamer-friends-and-my-reunion.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2003 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/la-gamer-friends-and-my-reunion.html</guid><description>Last night I attended my high school reunion. I met up with my old friend Dean Musson beforehand and met his 3 month old daughter Mathilda, who is as cute as can be. All smile and naps. :) Hes a stay-at-home dad for a few months and he cant do too much&amp;hellip;everything is in 2 hour feed-sleep cycles. He and Amy are big gamers and hes tried to fit in some Shadowbane, but its hard to do much but clean the house and watch Jerry Springer.</description></item><item><title>This Ungodly Hour</title><link>https://ggr.com/this-ungodly-hour.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2003 07:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/this-ungodly-hour.html</guid><description>So I got up at 6a this morning to take care of some stuff before flying down to LA. For one, I timed a bunch of eBay auctions poorly and I&amp;rsquo;m packing them now. It probably doesnt help that I stayed up late opening up Pass 2 in SSX3. I also sent some emails out to contacts at EALA. I dont know if the new studio has opened yet, I&amp;rsquo;m guessing it hasnt.</description></item><item><title>In-person For EAP Scheduled</title><link>https://ggr.com/in-person-for-eap-scheduled.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2003 07:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/in-person-for-eap-scheduled.html</guid><description>I heard from Stephanie of EAP last night&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m scheduled to spend some face-to-face time with the EAP folks next week. I got a chance to meet John and Craig briefly, but this is the real deal. I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to sitting down with them and some of the EAP team and getting a better feel for how EAP works! And asking more questions from my unending font of questions about game production and the industry.</description></item><item><title>A Fond Adieu</title><link>https://ggr.com/a-fond-adieu.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2003 19:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/a-fond-adieu.html</guid><description>Before I took off I stopped by to say hi to John Vifian and Craig Alexander to put a face with the name. I noticed that John had a wireless Logitech joystick&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about getting one. But he says it sucks. Except when you plug it into someone elses machine, program the fire button to emulate the keypress of &amp;rsquo;e&amp;rsquo; and then wait for your, uh, &amp;lsquo;friend&amp;rsquo; to fly a plane while playing Battlefield: 1942.</description></item><item><title>Bond and Jordan Maynard</title><link>https://ggr.com/bond-and-jordan-maynard.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2003 19:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/bond-and-jordan-maynard.html</guid><description>After lunch Erin and I walked over to say hi to Jordan Maynard. Erin took off for her appearance at Stanford and Jordan sat me down and showed me what he was working on. He helps with the animation on Bond&amp;ndash;he develops some of the custom tools they use and the capabilities are seriously ahead of the pack.
As far as I can tell, hes working on the holy grail of character animation: hes building and tweaking a tool that allows a programmer to take a character and just tell him what to do from this inventory of moves&amp;ndash;and the character moves properly, transitions and all.</description></item><item><title>Lunch With Erin Turner</title><link>https://ggr.com/lunch-with-erin-turner.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2003 17:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/lunch-with-erin-turner.html</guid><description>After I said goodbye to Neil I headed to the lobby of 250. I was a little early so I played some SSX 3 while I waited for Erin. Once she appeared I pried myself off the console and we headed to lunch at the EA cafeteria. My first time there&amp;hellip;man if the cafeterias had been like this at Berkeley. The food was entirely, you know, identifiable.
I told her about my meeting with Neil as I wondered what it all meant.</description></item><item><title>Sit Down With Neil Young</title><link>https://ggr.com/sit-down-with-neil-young.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2003 16:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/sit-down-with-neil-young.html</guid><description>When Neil offered to meet with me last week it was sort of like I had written a blog about how I like epic movies and then I got an email from Peter Jackson offering to meet with me. Basically, it was really cool :) So I was looking forward to meeting Neil and seeing what it was we would talk about.
Who Are You, Who Are Any Of Us?</description></item><item><title>A Day at EARS</title><link>https://ggr.com/a-day-at-ears.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2003 15:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/a-day-at-ears.html</guid><description>On the schedule for today was a meeting with Neil Young, lunch with Erin Turner, and quick hellos with Jordan Maynard and John Vifian. I was hoping to get in touch with Rob Moreno and [Tara S.][1] as well, but I&amp;rsquo;ll have to catch them next time. I just got back and I&amp;rsquo;ve been smiling like a goofball most of the day. It was a lot of fun talking with everyone and I really dig the vibe I get when I&amp;rsquo;m at EA.</description></item><item><title>An Email From Neil Young</title><link>https://ggr.com/an-email-from-neil-young.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2003 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/an-email-from-neil-young.html</guid><description>Thursday I got an email, out of the blue, from Neil Young. Hes a very experienced Executive Producer at EA, judging from his rap sheet. He said he saw this web site and he offered to meet with me. I called his assistant and we set a time to meet this coming Wednesday. Totally made my day. :) I&amp;rsquo;m going to get in touch with Erin Turner, Jordan Maynard, and John Vifian and see if theyll be around so I can stop by and say hi while I&amp;rsquo;m at EARS.</description></item><item><title>On the Phone With Craig Alexander</title><link>https://ggr.com/on-the-phone-with-craig-alexander.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2003 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/on-the-phone-with-craig-alexander.html</guid><description>Just got back from the gym when I noticed Craig Alexander had left a message. John had told me he was the next person I would talk to at EAP, but I didnt know when I would hear from him. I guess today. :) I just missed him by about 15 minutes so I called back and we started things off with me offering a little background on myself.
Tell Me a Little About Yourself</description></item><item><title>Nonsequiter Project</title><link>https://ggr.com/nonsequiter-project.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2003 01:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/nonsequiter-project.html</guid><description>I met up with my friend Ben Durbin at Buzz9 about in the middle of the evenings festivities after the IGDA meeting on Wednesday. I only managed a single Guinness on the IGDA tab before we were talking shop. As you may recall, Nonsequiter is a small group of game newbies that has been getting together with the intention of sharing our experiences in the game biz, and more importantly, to make some games.</description></item><item><title>BAAD and Games At Work</title><link>https://ggr.com/baad-and-games-at-work.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2003 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/baad-and-games-at-work.html</guid><description>Just came across an article about how games may improve productivity at work. It reminded me of my consulting team at QuickStart. I dubbed my team BAAD (Bay Area Applications Development) and games were allowed in the office. Heck, half the time I was on AWP duty.
My team handled the applications development for QuickStarts consulting practice in Northern California and I was blessed with a team of outstanding consultants. Not only could they program&amp;ndash;they were communicators who worked well with our customers.</description></item><item><title>Emails Awaaay</title><link>https://ggr.com/emails-awaaay.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2003 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/emails-awaaay.html</guid><description>At Wednesdays IGDA meeting I met a few cool people that I&amp;rsquo;m hoping I&amp;rsquo;ll get a chance to stay in touch with. I usually like to follow up with an email within 24 hours, but I&amp;rsquo;m pushing about 26 here. ;) Dave Rohrl was an outstanding speaker and he seemed to me the bottomless pit of game industry wisdom and friendly wit. Liz Wakefield made the whole thing happen and seems like shed be cool to just hang with.</description></item><item><title>A Couple Shout-outs</title><link>https://ggr.com/a-couple-shout-outs.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2003 00:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/a-couple-shout-outs.html</guid><description>Thank you Russell Borogove for the email with encouraging words and some very helpful insights into what its like at EA. Congratulations to my good friend Mark Schlosberg who, after working his butt off for the past months as head of the campaign, won on Prop H in SF. Good to hear from you Tara S.! I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to grabbing a beer and swapping notes on the industry as soon as we find a chance.</description></item><item><title>IGDA SF Meeting</title><link>https://ggr.com/igda-sf-meeting.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2003 23:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/igda-sf-meeting.html</guid><description>I attended my first IGDA SF meeting last night at the Art Institute (I have a friend that works there too). The meeting centered on a discussion of the newly released whitepaper by the Online Games Committee. John Welch of Shockwave.com, Dave Rohrl of EA Online, Margaret Wallace of Skunk Studios, and Mark DeLoura of Sony formed the evenings panel with Jennifer Olsen (editor-in-chief of Game Developer Magazine) moderating.
I was very impressed by Dave, who I felt did an excellent job of presenting his perspective on online gaming and he was just a fun speaker.</description></item><item><title>Conversation With Tiffany</title><link>https://ggr.com/conversation-with-tiffany.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2003 11:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/conversation-with-tiffany.html</guid><description>Just spoke with Tiffany Spencer of Ubisoft. She manages the PR for the Clancy series for Ubisoft&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to get a hold of her for a little while. She was out of town on business and vacation, so that explains it. Pretty cool stuff though; she just had a meeting with MTV.
Tiffany noted that the Ubisoft office in SF is in fact a marketing office; though it is also home to a number of Ubisoft producers who manage relationships with their local studio partners (sorta like the role at EAP I&amp;rsquo;m interviewing for).</description></item><item><title>First Interview</title><link>https://ggr.com/first-interview.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2003 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/first-interview.html</guid><description>I had my first interview with EA today. John Vifian gave me a call at the appointed time and we talked about the job of Development Director (DD) at EA Partners (EAP). It was fun talking to him&amp;ndash;he has some great experience in the industry.
Development Director
The DDs report to Exec Producers who report to Tom Frisina. As I understand it, DDs at EAP represent the publishers (EA&amp;rsquo;s) interests on a project by helping guide the studio EA has a partnership with; ideally to help them take a successful game and turn it into a successful franchise.</description></item><item><title>Maxis Asst Prod, Update</title><link>https://ggr.com/maxis-asst-prod-update.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2003 13:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/maxis-asst-prod-update.html</guid><description>Just got off the phone with Lisa Bell. The scoop is that they already have someone internal for the position&amp;ndash;the post to EA jobs was really more of a formality. But, even though they dont have other production positions open, Lisa said she liked my resume and would like to speak to me in December. Were scheduled for a phone call 1st week of December. Pretty cool. Glad I made that phone call.</description></item><item><title>And On the EAP Front</title><link>https://ggr.com/and-on-the-eap-front.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2003 12:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/and-on-the-eap-front.html</guid><description>Went back and forth via email yesterday with John Vifian of EA Partners. RJ said he thinks they used to be called EA Distribution, at least when he was there. RJ worked with John briefly and had a good impression. Johns a Director of Development. I believe he works for Tom Frisina&amp;hellip;I think Rob mentioned that Tom heads up the team. John is interested in interviewing me by phone Wednesday. I&amp;rsquo;m very excited!</description></item><item><title>Maxis Asst Prod, Update</title><link>https://ggr.com/maxis-asst-prod-update.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2003 12:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/maxis-asst-prod-update.html</guid><description>So I emailed Kana Ryan and she forwarded me with a nice intro to Lisa Bell. I was getting all excited that I had a good intro into the hiring manager until I emailed Toby and he told me Lisa is in HR (and therefore a gatekeeper). I did think it a bit odd that the only credit I could find for her was a &amp;ldquo;thank you&amp;rdquo; on the Sims Online.</description></item><item><title>Dinner With the QS Gang</title><link>https://ggr.com/dinner-with-the-qs-gang.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2003 22:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/dinner-with-the-qs-gang.html</guid><description>Just got back from dinner with some friends from my days at QuickStart, one of which is was Matthew Chamberlain of Microsoft. He reports that hes still on the hunt at MS on my behalf (which is, of course, awfully nice of him). We got together a couple weeks ago at the MS SF office to search for people to talk to. We decided it would be a good idea to start with a couple of guys at the top (it goes something like: guys at the top-&amp;gt;studio heads-&amp;gt;exec producers-&amp;gt;producers-&amp;gt;associate producers) and go from there.</description></item><item><title>Phone Tag and Persistence</title><link>https://ggr.com/phone-tag-and-persistence.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2003 10:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/phone-tag-and-persistence.html</guid><description>My friend Auren emailed me an introduction to Tiffany Spencer who is a PR Manager (as best I can tellshe works out of SF and Ubisofts SF office is a marketing office) for Ubisoft. She emailed me once last week but I havent been able to reach her since. Perhaps shes out of town or very busy. I am reminded of how many times I have had to contact a person 10 times or more before I finally got a hold of them.</description></item><item><title>First Movable Type Spam</title><link>https://ggr.com/first-movable-type-spam.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2003 19:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/first-movable-type-spam.html</guid><description>It was bound to happen. Got my first comment Spam on this site today. I was all excited about getting a comment until I read it. ;) Heh heh. I hope I dont have to put a filter on too soon.</description></item><item><title>EA 10-K</title><link>https://ggr.com/ea-10-k.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2003 23:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/ea-10-k.html</guid><description>Its amazing what you can learn from reading the SEC filings for public companies. I thought Id check out EA&amp;rsquo;s filing in June and see what I could learn about the company. Its always a great way to see where the money really is and where the company is headed, generally speaking.
So far I&amp;rsquo;ve gleaned a few interesting tidbits:
The new EALA is going to be pretty important. EA is consolidating the old LA, Irvine, and Vegas studios into it, at substantial expense.</description></item><item><title>The Ancient Art of Resume Writing</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-ancient-art-of-resume-writing.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2003 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-ancient-art-of-resume-writing.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit that I find writing my own resume a challenge. On the one hand, I&amp;rsquo;m a fairly confident guy, but on the other hand, I dont really like tooting my own horn. Cant be too bold or too humble and I&amp;rsquo;ve gotta speak the right language. There are certain things I need to communicate to get past the gatekeepers and make it all the way to the hiring manager and then land an interview.</description></item><item><title>Maxis Assistant Producer II</title><link>https://ggr.com/maxis-assistant-producer-ii.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2003 10:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/maxis-assistant-producer-ii.html</guid><description>Just got the email that Maxis posted for an assistant producer on the SimCity series. Wow, that would be excellent&amp;hellip;Id love to have a chance to work at Maxis (which is, btw, an EA company). I sent an email over to Kana Ryan whom I noticed was the exec producer on the SimCity series as of SimCity 4. Yah, shes probably not the hiring manager, but hopefully shell be nice enough to forward it to them&amp;hellip;I also sent an email to Toby asking if he might know who over there is the hiring manager so I can address my interest to the right person.</description></item><item><title>Crimson Skies Notes</title><link>https://ggr.com/crimson-skies-notes.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2003 20:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/crimson-skies-notes.html</guid><description>MS just released their sequel to Crimson Skies on the Xbox. Heh heh, they know its a good game and they want it to help drive purchases of the Xbox and subscriptions to Xbox Live. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to take some notes down about the original for some time because it was a game I enjoyed and I thought it worth reflecting on why I enjoyed it as much as I did.</description></item><item><title>If You Tell Them</title><link>https://ggr.com/if-you-tell-them.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2003 10:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/if-you-tell-them.html</guid><description>My friend Brian Donoho (hes the guy behind the web-based system that keeps QuickLogic in business) was at a party this weekend when he bumped into a guy that works at EA in operations. He started plugging him for info on my behalf, but I think everyone was already way too into the beer part of the evening to do much good. :) Hey, you never know.
Updated on October 5th, 2013</description></item><item><title>Small World Effect</title><link>https://ggr.com/small-world-effect.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2003 22:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/small-world-effect.html</guid><description>I emailed RJ Berg after I finished Alice to tell him how much I liked the game. I also asked why Moby wasnt showing him on Alice in their DB and it turns out the person who put the data in originally missed him. So, I contacted Moby and got them to add his credit as the executive producer on the project. But he did a lot more than exec produce the game&amp;ndash;he wrote the script and the dialogue while directing the voice and music.</description></item><item><title>Reinforcements</title><link>https://ggr.com/reinforcements.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2003 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/reinforcements.html</guid><description>A number of weeks ago I had lunch with Erin Turner at the Sofitel hotel near the EA campus. Come to think of it, it was labor day or something. And of course, being a producer and all, Erin was in the office that day. :) Shes leading the charge on the next Bond game after all, and she was wrapping pre-beta. I was plunking away on the piano when she walked up and we went to grab lunch nearby.</description></item><item><title>Getting Closer</title><link>https://ggr.com/getting-closer.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2003 07:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/getting-closer.html</guid><description>A couple days ago Rob emailed me letting me know that he had pitched me to EA Partners and they were interested in speaking with me. :) As I understand it, EAP is looking for producer-types at an array of levels to help manage their relationships with outside studios, I&amp;rsquo;m guessing on one or a handful of projects at a time. Today I received an email from EA&amp;rsquo;s job engine with more details.</description></item><item><title>Games 411</title><link>https://ggr.com/games-411.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2003 12:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/games-411.html</guid><description>My friend Auren Hoffman just sent me a copy of Games 411 out of the blue. Nice! I was planning on getting this. Turns out the publisher is Andrew Boer. He used to be the VP of Sales for BridgePath (a company I cofounded in 1997, acquired in 2002) before he left to get his MBA over at Harvard. I wonder how he came to be involved with this project</description></item><item><title>Alice Notes</title><link>https://ggr.com/alice-notes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2003 11:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/alice-notes.html</guid><description>American McGee must be friends with Tim Burton. I decided to drop $8 for a copy of Alice. Heck, I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken to the producer and a bunch of friends have recommended the game. Took me about 20 hours to play through. The graphics were funthey set the mood of wandering through this land of dark imagination.
Excellent Interface
The music was good. The menus were excellent, starting with the startup sequence with the EA logo turning into the Cat, accompanied by light laughter turning into twisted laughter.</description></item><item><title>First IGDA Chapter Meeting Soon</title><link>https://ggr.com/first-igda-chapter-meeting-soon.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2003 19:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/first-igda-chapter-meeting-soon.html</guid><description>Got an email a little while ago. Looks like my first chance to check out the local IGDA chapter in SF will be coming in another couple weeks: Nov 5th at 6:30p. I wonder who I&amp;rsquo;ll meet!</description></item><item><title>Mage In SF, LARPs</title><link>https://ggr.com/mage-in-sf-larps.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2003 10:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/mage-in-sf-larps.html</guid><description>Writing about RPGs has gotten me all misty eyed for my pen-and-paper days past. I though Id try and find a game of Mage in the Bay Area. Posted on Craigslist and the forums for Mage, but I havent turned up much. After looking at the limited level of Internet chatter related to the game these day, I&amp;rsquo;m starting to think there arent that many people playing Mage. So sad. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll just have to storytell a game myself, or perhaps consider other game worlds like Vampire or D&amp;amp;D.</description></item><item><title>Homeworld 2 Notes</title><link>https://ggr.com/homeworld-2-notes.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2003 05:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/homeworld-2-notes.html</guid><description>Picked up a copy of HW2. You could say I opened the box with some anticipationthe first one remains one of my favorite games. It was immersive&amp;ndash;the story was engaging, the sound built and maintained the mood, and the interface still is the easiest 3D RTS I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. As for the sequel it has spawned, HW2 gives a great first impression&amp;ndash;the production quality is certainly there. The graphics, interface, and sound have all taken evolutionary steps that are great to see.</description></item><item><title>GDC Site Is Up</title><link>https://ggr.com/gdc-site-is-up.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2003 12:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/gdc-site-is-up.html</guid><description>The GDC site has done its soft launch (ie, pre-media blitz). Its like a web beta so everyone can fix there profiles and early-birds can get a peak and register. I&amp;rsquo;m on the QoL panel&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;ve even got a short profile on there. A couple days ago they asked for a picture, I had to whip out the digital camera. :p
Updated on October 4th, 2013
Replaced the broken link to the official GDC 2004 site with a link to an article on GDC 2004 by IGN.</description></item><item><title>EA QA and 'the Life'</title><link>https://ggr.com/ea-qa-and-the-life.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2003 14:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/ea-qa-and-the-life.html</guid><description>People like Matt Lewis are why I like the Bay Area. Totally cool guy&amp;hellip;we met for drinks last night at this chill bar with no sign (keeps the unclued out, I guess) and we chatted a bit about games. I was introduced to Matt through my friend Ben, who is friends with Matts roommate (3 degrees). Matt worked as a mid-level QA dude on the publishers side of The Sims a few years back and he told me that EA Redwood Shores is a great place to work.</description></item><item><title>PDI-Dreamworks</title><link>https://ggr.com/pdi-dreamworks.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2003 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/pdi-dreamworks.html</guid><description>Just got off the phone with Mark Kirk of PDI-Dreamworks. Hes the former neighbor of my dads friend Phil (thats 3 degrees). Hes working on some really interesting stuff&amp;ndash;he started in IT (got introduced to the company by a friend who was getting his masters degree in graphics) and now builds the project and asset management/project pipeline tool for PDI. Basically, he makes it easier for everyone to do their piece on a film and seamlessly pass things to the next person for the work they need to do, all the while maintaining a great deal of transparency and insight into where things are on the project.</description></item><item><title>First Link</title><link>https://ggr.com/first-link.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2003 11:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/first-link.html</guid><description>I thought Id Google this sitesee if it was in the search engine already. I was surprised to find a link from another blogger! Pretty cool. Wonder how he heard about the site? So far I&amp;rsquo;ve told so few people about itmy main avenue of exposure so far is through people who I email from the domain. They sometimes notice the address. I also &amp;lsquo;ping&amp;rsquo; a couple blog portals to let them know I&amp;rsquo;ve posted something.</description></item><item><title>Cooperative Multiplayer</title><link>https://ggr.com/cooperative-multiplayer.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 06:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/cooperative-multiplayer.html</guid><description>One of the best things about System Shock 2 was the cooperative multiplayer game.
These days most games I come across are either single-player, plot-driven (games like The Sims being the exception) or multiplayer interaction-driven. And when I say single-player games are plot-driven, I mean it to include a broad range of plot complexities. Some of these plot-driven games have rather pitiful plots, i.e. Earth is being invaded by aliens and you, the last super badass are all that stands in the way of total destruction.</description></item><item><title>The Future of IWantToWorkAtEA.com</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-future-of-iwanttoworkatea.com.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 04:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-future-of-iwanttoworkatea.com.html</guid><description>I was thinking the other day about what should happen to this domain once I land a gig at EA. What Id like to do is find someone whose trying to get a gig at EA like I was and hand the steering wheel off to them so they can add their experiences. I&amp;rsquo;ll contribute advice and insight into my experience from the inside as well as help this person along.</description></item><item><title>The Maxis Tour</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-maxis-tour.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2003 04:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-maxis-tour.html</guid><description>Last night I got the full tour of Maxis from Toby Roberts, a central leader in their IT operation. Met Toby through my friend Kat Sewell and we all went to grab dinner after. Man, what a cool place Maxis is! I cant even begin to describe the energetic atmosphere in those colorful halls. And I cant even begin to tell you all the cool shit they are working on because of the NDA I had to sign before entering.</description></item><item><title>One Of These Lives Has a Future</title><link>https://ggr.com/one-of-these-lives-has-a-future.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2003 08:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/one-of-these-lives-has-a-future.html</guid><description>I just applied to a couple positions with MSs Xbox team in Redmond. I know, I know they arent EA, but I figure I need to keep my options open. They are growing fast and they are more familiar with how to leverage my kind of biz software production experience in the game space, increasing my appeal, which is good. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a few friends at MS that could help me navigate the place and I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with them before.</description></item><item><title>EALA Connection</title><link>https://ggr.com/eala-connection.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2003 16:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/eala-connection.html</guid><description>Found out I&amp;rsquo;m going to be a first cousin once removed by my cousin Stew. He and his wife are both in digital animation. She teaches and hes got a gig with Disney. He introduced me to Dave Kury (a college friend of his from UCLA animation) about a month back, who working for EALA as the lead animator on the next Medal of Honor. He introduced me to Rick Kane, an EA producer who gave me some good advice and the latest on EA new EALA studio that is close to completion.</description></item><item><title>Find Your Bliss</title><link>https://ggr.com/find-your-bliss.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2003 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/find-your-bliss.html</guid><description>Didnt think Id post one every day did you? :) My friend Brian Donoho drove his old trainer bike all the way from Sunnyvale to loan it to me so I can practice. He says it has as much pickup as a lawnmower, but it should get me around the parking lot just fine. Brian joined Nonsequiter studios a little while ago and we got to talking about the game industry over Zacharys and some more on the drive back.</description></item><item><title>Game Girl Advance And 411</title><link>https://ggr.com/game-girl-advance-and-411.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2003 12:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/game-girl-advance-and-411.html</guid><description>I subscribe to Game Girl Advance and they mentioned this goth band in an article about how the goth scene is full of gamers. The band was in SF Tuesday so I went to check them out and I thought they were pretty good! Theyve got their own Sims skins5 too. :) That evening, after the evening of ear blasting and all things black, I stumbled across a little gem known as 411 publishing.</description></item><item><title>System Shock 3</title><link>https://ggr.com/system-shock-3.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2003 12:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/system-shock-3.html</guid><description>Like everyone else in the game industry, I too have a pet game idea or two. Having read most of the production articles at Gamasutra and much of Sloperama I realize that like most software and unlike Athena, games do not spring forth from your head fully formed. So a few weeks ago I started looking into just what it would take to build a game myself.
Start With an Idea, Add Salt</description></item><item><title>Beer At Jupiters</title><link>https://ggr.com/beer-at-jupiters.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2003 23:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/beer-at-jupiters.html</guid><description>Tonight I decided to grab a beer at Jupiters with Michael Constant. He left Activision a little while ago to work on a math degree at Berkeley (my alma mater). I met Michael when my friend Melinda brought him to a movie night a couple weeks ago. You worked in gaming you say? We really must talk some more. :) Turns out Michaels a real badass. Hes been mentoring new developers and taking on the bitch ass bugs that no one else has the guts to stare down.</description></item><item><title>EA's Biz Side</title><link>https://ggr.com/eas-biz-side.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2003 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/eas-biz-side.html</guid><description>Thought I would start the week by giving Joel Lizner of EA a call. I was introduced to him through my friend Jon Bass. I never would have guessed he knew people in the industry, but hes introduced me to Joel and to RJ Berg, a producer over at LucasArts. It just goes to show that when you are looking to meet people in the industry, tell everyone you can. You never know who all your friends of friends know.</description></item><item><title>IGDA And The Good Life</title><link>https://ggr.com/igda-and-the-good-life.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2003 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/igda-and-the-good-life.html</guid><description>I joined the IGDAs committee on quality of life a few weeks ago, offering to bring the newbie perspective to the table. Weve been asked to produce a white paper overviewing the state of the industry from a QoL point of view, to be unveiled at GDC 2004. The whole thing has been pretty illuminating.
I&amp;rsquo;m getting a health dose of reality from people who have come together to air the industrys dirty laundryall manner of things from unionization to reasons people leave the industry have come up.</description></item><item><title>The Campaign Begins</title><link>https://ggr.com/the-campaign-begins.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2003 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/the-campaign-begins.html</guid><description>Just got back from a fundraiser my friend put on for Prop H in San Francisco. Ammiano was funny and the vegetable dip was top rate. My friend Mel is threatening to find a way to get Georgy to my next movie night because I said that she is cute. But I&amp;rsquo;ve got my own campaign to think about. My campaign to land a gig with EA in Redwood City.</description></item><item><title>Copyright This</title><link>https://ggr.com/copyright-this.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 1997 13:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/copyright-this.html</guid><description>I decided to copyright my DNA (TM). I mentioned this to my parents, and they produced a copy of the End User License Agreement (EULA) that I signed for my DNA when I was just a few seconds old, and complained of numerous violations (they still claim to be the original authors, with all visible evidence to the contrary). But, reading legal newsgroups has kept me abreast of the latest, and I knew that a contract with a minor is non-binding.</description></item></channel></rss>