<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Misc on game, game. repeat.</title><link>https://ggr.com/tags/misc.html</link><description>Recent content in Misc on game, game. repeat.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:22:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ggr.com/tags/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NixOS Is Great</title><link>https://ggr.com/nixos-is-great.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:22:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/nixos-is-great.html</guid><description>Finally got around to trying out NixOS. This is the way. :)
I&amp;rsquo;ve used Chef, Ansible, shell scripts, manually cowboy sysadmin knob twiddling, CloudFormation, Terraform and other means of wrangling the computers and software I manage and code &amp;gt; manual but NixOS takes it to the next level with a declarative &amp;gt; imperative approach to configuring a Linux box.
It&amp;rsquo;s not all roses. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to invest real time before I&amp;rsquo;ll have wrapped my head around the Nix language&amp;hellip;and without that I&amp;rsquo;m groping around in the dark at times.</description></item><item><title>Mbsync Is Way Faster Than Offlineimap</title><link>https://ggr.com/mbsync-is-way-faster-than-offlineimap.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/mbsync-is-way-faster-than-offlineimap.html</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in the market for a tool that syncs your email over IMAP, I recommend you check out mbsync. On my hefty machine, offlineimap takes many minutes to sync, all the while pegging a CPU at 100% and slowing my machine to a crawl. On the other hand, mbsync sips 5% CPU, finishes much faster, and has no noticeable impact on me while doing other tasks on the same machine.</description></item><item><title>Some Predictions</title><link>https://ggr.com/some-predictions.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/some-predictions.html</guid><description>By 2020 OpenBSD will be in the top 25 on Distrowatch, because of an increased interest in security. By 2025 US legislation will have shifted the cost of poor software security practices from the consumer to the website/software maker in the US. By 2030 all the mainstream (desktop and server) operating systems will be open source and sponsored/supported by at least one large (for profit) company.</description></item><item><title>Contact Sales</title><link>https://ggr.com/contact-sales.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/contact-sales.html</guid><description>These days it seems that a lot of SaaS tools are offering a free tier, one or more paid tiers, and an &amp;rsquo;enterprise&amp;rsquo; tier, which, unlike the other tiers, has amazing new capabilities but no price. Or rather, the price is &amp;lsquo;contact sales&amp;rsquo;.
That price is too high for me. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to contact sales. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to waste time listening to a pitch, hearing the retail price, hearing what a great deal they&amp;rsquo;re willing to offer me off the retail price because I&amp;rsquo;m special and there&amp;rsquo;s a blue moon tonight.</description></item><item><title>Background Processes On the Brain</title><link>https://ggr.com/background-processes-on-the-brain.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/background-processes-on-the-brain.html</guid><description>When I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of a hard thought problem (i.e. coding) and I interrupt my work on the thought problem to do something else, I find it difficult to concentrate on the something else. I think my brain is still working on the hard thought problem in the background, sort of like a CPU that&amp;rsquo;s still processing a different job&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m not fully available to focus on the dinner party or new project at hand.</description></item><item><title>Wishlist Upgraded</title><link>https://ggr.com/wishlist-upgraded.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 23:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/wishlist-upgraded.html</guid><description>I moved my wishlist from Amazon to CamelCamelCamel. I use my wishlist mostly as a check on my impulses&amp;ndash;when I want something I add it to the wishlist instead of buying it. It feels almost as satisfying and I haven&amp;rsquo;t spent any money. Every so often I go through my wishlist to see if I still want the stuff on there. About 3/4 of the stuff gets eliminated, the rest I eventually buy.</description></item><item><title>How To Predict The Future Using Excel</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-predict-the-future-using-excel.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 16:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-predict-the-future-using-excel.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to run out of hard drive space at some point. I&amp;rsquo;ve got 1.5TB drives in my Drobo right now, I wonder when the 3TB drives will come out so I can just upgrade them in place for double the capacity&amp;hellip;
First I looked up when each of the last several capacity jumps were announced. Google news did the trick: 500MB in 2005, 1TB in 2007, 1.5TB in 2008, 2TB in 2009.</description></item><item><title>How To Monitor Amazon For Price Drops</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-monitor-amazon-for-price-drops.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 13:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-monitor-amazon-for-price-drops.html</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to run out of hard drive space at some point. I&amp;rsquo;ve got 1.5TB drives in my Drobo right now, I wonder when the 3TB drives will come out so I can just upgrade them in place for double the capacity&amp;hellip;
First I looked up when each of the last several capacity jumps were announced. Google news did the trick: 500MB in 2005, 1TB in 2007, 1.5TB in 2008, 2TB in 2009.</description></item><item><title>How To Keep Your Cables Untangled While You Use Them</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-keep-your-cables-untangled-while-you-use-them.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 17:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-keep-your-cables-untangled-while-you-use-them.html</guid><description>The mess of cables behind your computer sure doesn&amp;rsquo;t look safe. And this probably won&amp;rsquo;t make it any safer, but it sure makes it easier to see what&amp;rsquo;s going on. It&amp;rsquo;s all about taking up the slack.</description></item><item><title>How To Keep Your Cables Untangled While You Store Them</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-keep-your-cables-untangled-while-you-store-them.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 17:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-keep-your-cables-untangled-while-you-store-them.html</guid><description>Ziploc freezer bags help keep your cables untangled and easy to sort through. There&amp;rsquo;s even space for you to write the date when your cable goes bad, in case you are good at predicting that sort of thing.</description></item><item><title>How To Protect Your Pockets From Your Keys</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-protect-your-pockets-from-your-keys.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-protect-your-pockets-from-your-keys.html</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re tired of your keychain poking holes in your pockets you may want to consider investing in some protection.</description></item><item><title>How To Use Your iPhone To Record Notes</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-use-your-iphone-to-record-notes.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-use-your-iphone-to-record-notes.html</guid><description>In the &amp;rsquo;80s all the cool executive-type people carried around small tape recorders for capturing ideas any time they had them. Today we can record notes in &amp;rsquo;00s style and have them sent straight to our email. Turns out its pretty handy to be able to quickly taking notes anytime, anywhere. You know&amp;hellip;until you can afford a personal assistant like the really cool &amp;rsquo;80s execs.
Directions leading to note recording bliss:</description></item><item><title>How To Subscribe To a Website</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-subscribe-to-a-website.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 21:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-subscribe-to-a-website.html</guid><description>WHAT IF you could subscribe to your favorite websites and automatically be sent any new articles they post instead of checking back a couple times a day or week to see if there is anything new? Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be great? The future is now! Head over to Google Reader, sign up for an account, then click the &amp;lsquo;add subscription&amp;rsquo; button. Type in the URL of the website you want to subscribe to and if it supports subscriptions (aka RSS) you&amp;rsquo;ll be reading their articles in seconds.</description></item><item><title>How To Ship a Used Book</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-ship-a-used-book.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-ship-a-used-book.html</guid><description>So you sold your used book on Amazon, you&amp;rsquo;re basking in the glow of your success, and then it dawns on you that the buyer is expecting you to send them the book.
No worries, here&amp;rsquo;s how you do it: 1) print the packing slip from Amazon; 2) put the book in a padded envelope with the packing slip; 3) address the package to the buyer; 4) weigh the package; 5) look up the postage; 6) put the right postage on there; 7) write &amp;lsquo;media mail&amp;rsquo; beneath the stamps on the package;8) stop by your local post office and drop it off in person.</description></item><item><title>How To Sell a Used Book</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-sell-a-used-book.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-sell-a-used-book.html</guid><description>They do look good on your bookshelf, but are you really ever going to read them again? You can free up space in your home, save the environment, and spread knowledge throughout the world by getting that book off your shelf into the hands of an eager reader.
One of the easiest ways is through Amazon:&amp;ndash;do a search for your book, click on the &amp;lsquo;sell yours here&amp;rsquo; button, and you&amp;rsquo;re on your way.</description></item><item><title>How To Get More Outlet Space</title><link>https://ggr.com/how-to-get-more-outlet-space.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 16:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ggr.com/how-to-get-more-outlet-space.html</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s easy to run out of power outlets with all the must-have gadgets in our lives. Some self-important power adapters sprawl over 2 or more outlets, luxuriating without a thought for the other devices. Huge, Dubai inspired, power strips are one way to find more space, but these&amp;ndash;plug extenders leverage your existing power strip to offer each of your diva adapters their own luxury suite. &amp;ndash;Just don&amp;rsquo;t tell them that you only paid $9 for a pack of 3 (before tax+shipping), let them think you splurged.</description></item></channel></rss>